Tokuma Shoten, Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network, Buena Vista Home Entertainment, Hakuhodo, Mitsubishi and Toho Present If you find yourself troubled by something mysterious...
or a problem that's hard to solve...
there's a place you can go...
a place where...
Oh no!
Haru, are you awake?
Just got up!
Good.
Morning.
Really...
Why bother to set your alarm clock?
Bye.
Aren't you having breakfast?
It's so delicious.
Oh, so delicious.
Not fair.
Bye.
My shoe!
Excuse me.
Oh no!
The Kingdom is now gone.
Yet the mountains and rivers remain.
The castle draped in the dense greens of spring.
Yoshioka.
You don't have time to sneak in.
Just get to your seat.
Yes, sir.
Caught again.
The Cat Returns I hate this.
Late again and embarrassed in front of the whole class.
Machida-kun was laughing at me too.
He was laughing.
Why?
What's wrong with me?
Well, this must be a sign.
Something even worse is about to begin.
Thanks for the sympathy.
That's an unusual cat.
What's so great about Machida?
He's just so cool!
Have you told him that?
He seems to have a girlfriend.
She's a freshman and very good-looking.
So you already know.
In case you get dumped I'm ready to console you.
Thanks a lot.
I think Tsuge-chan is cool.
Good, if he dumps you...
Had something in his mouth.
Stolen goods?
Who knows...
What's he doing?
Hey, cat!
Watch out!
Anyway.
It's just a cat.
Hey, that's dangerous.
Oh no, what's he doing?
Wait, Haru!
Good going Haru!
Hey!
Stop that truck!
Cat...
Are you OK?
Thank you for saving me from a dangerous situation.
I hope you haven't injured yourself.
Please excuse me, but I really must be going now.
Allow me to express my gratitude later.
Don't mention it.
Haru!
Ah, you broke it.
Never mind, a cat's life is more important.
Did you see that?
Huh?
The cat bowed to me.
Haru...
Did you hit your head?
I'm home.
Don't step on that!
Sorry.
I can't decide which pattern to use.
Honey, can you make dinner?
Mom.
Can cats talk?
Well...
Let's see.
What?!
Come to think of it, you said so before.
Really?
When you were very small, you used to say "I can talk with cats."
Did I?
Yes, don't you remember?
What's wrong?
I see, you're hungry.
Do you like fish?
OK, take these.
You're so dirty...
Good?
OK, OK.
More?
Good girl.
Eat them all.
No need to thank me.
Haru.
Oh, Mom!
What were you doing?
Talking with a cat.
Remember I asked you what did you talk about with the cat?
Then you said, "She told me it's tough to make a living in this world."
and I thought it was so funny.
I guess that did happen.
Anyway, I'll get up early tomorrow in time for breakfast.
Uhm...
Over here please.
A little closer.
Allow me to introduce.
The King of the Kingdom of Cats.
A King among Kings.
The Cat King.
That's me.
The cat you saved today was the son of the King, Prince Lune.
Given the importance of the matter, the King himself has come to show his gratitude.
Uh...
Mhh...
Thank you.
This is the program.
From tomorrow, countless joys will befall you.
Thank you.
See you.
A dream?
You're saying...
It really wasn't you who did this?
I have no idea.
Then who did it?
Haru!
Haru, hurry up!
What is this?!
Cattails!
Oh, I work too hard.
I'll be in bed today.
No!
Why?
Haru, it's this one, see?
Morning!
Sorry.
Got to run.
What's she up to?
You think she has catnip?
Catnip?
Why?
Don't know.
Hey, Yoshioka!
Leave your cats at home.
They're not mine.
What is this?
It wasn't a dream.
It was those cats that did this.
Was it a mistake to save a cat?
Haru.
Wha...
What is it?
Did you get rid of the catnip smell?
Yeah.
It seems OK and the cats aren't after me anymore.
That's good.
Yeah.
Say, can I ask you a favor?
Can you take my turn for clean-up?
Tsuge-chan has a game today and I can't make it if I don't leave right now.
Please!
Oh...
Sure...
Clean-up, right?
Thank you, Haru!
Tsuge-chan!
Go for it!
Hurray Tsuge-chan!
You're so cool!
Be careful of the step.
Thanks.
Ouch, that hurt.
Oh no!
What a mess.
Uh oh.
What on earth am I doing here?
There you are.
Haru-sama, Haru-sama.
You cats!
One thing after another all morning.
We're glad you're pleased.
NOT!
Why is that?!
This project has been taken on by the whole kingdom to express our maximum gratitude!
What are you saying?
I don't eat mice.
I don't like cattails or catnip.
Oh, is that so...
Excuse our ignorance.
This is unexpected.
How shall I report to the King?
Sorry, did I hurt you?
Maybe I said too much.
To tell the truth, a lot happened to me recently.
Such as?
Such as many things.
I see, is that so?
Even a beautiful lady like Haru-sama has troubles.
Again...
That's enough.
No, it isn't enough.
We can't stop now.
We'll do our best to make you satisfied.
You have more?
Yes.
Please come visit us in the Kingdom of Cats.
The Kingdom of Cats?
It's a nice place.
Lots of natural scenery and good food.
The whole Kingdom will welcome Haru-sama.
And what's more...
The King is expecting Prince Lune, who you saved yesterday, to welcome Haru-sama as his bride.
No way!
That's impossible.
The Prince is a cat.
What's the problem?
He is a cat, but he's cool!
Cool?
Well...
A kingdom of cats might be good.
Just laying around all day.
Exactly!
It might be heaven.
Eat tons of great food, then have a nap.
Forget all your troubles...
But a cat's bride...
That's going too far.
Even if he is a prince, that's...
Huh?
Well then, we'll come for you tonight.
What do you mean?
Hey!
Wait!
Ouch.
That really hurts.
Wait, give me time to think.
That is to say... in a word...
What can I do?
I'm sure those cats will do it.
They'll take me to the Kingdom of Cats.
They'll make me the cat's bride.
No, no.
No!
Never!
Haru-chan.
Who is it?
Haru-chan, the Cat Business Office.
Find the Cat Business Office.
Not this.
Who is this?
What is the Cat Business Office?
I'm sure they'll help you.
A large white cat at the Crossroad will show you the way.
A large white cat...
Haru-chan, go to the Crossroad and find the Cat Business Office.
Never heard of the Cat Business Office.
A large white cat...
But the voice was beautiful.
Might be a nice white cat.
Oh, I'm tired.
I'm taking a break.
What?
What is it?
What's this big fat cat?
What are you doing here?
A large white cat!
Is this it?
Hey, you.
Do you know the Cat Business Office?
I need your help.
I mistook you for a different person...
Ehh, a different cat.
I'm sorry I sat on you.
Follow me.
You are the one.
Hey, wait for me!
Hey, isn't there an easier way?
Is this revenge?
Because I said you're fat?
What a strange place.
Where's the Cat Business Office?
Are you listening?
I have a big problem.
These cats are taking me to their kingdom!
Is... this...
Hey, Baron!
You got a visitor!
Cut the theatrics and just come out!
Welcome to the Cat Business Office!
Cool...
This place is in a dimension a little different from yours, a world for beings who have souls.
When people create something with all their heart and hopes, the creation is given a soul, like me and him.
Oh my gosh!
He is Toto.
A gargoyle with a soul.
Baron, it's quite rare for you to have a visitor.
Yes, and a quite charming one, don't you think?
Baron?
I'm Baron Humbert von Gikkingen.
The person who created me named me so.
So that's why you're called Baron.
I heard your story.
Trouble with some cats from the Cat Kingdom?
That's right.
I saved a cat from being run over.
Now they're saying, in return, they want to take me to their kingdom.
In return?
Heh, it figures.
Too kind for your own good.
You shouldn't have bothered.
Your mind is nasty as ever.
You can't appreciate the kindness which saved a cat.
And she is in trouble for it, right?
Never mix in somebody else's business.
Where did you meet this girl?
At the Crossroad place.
She already knew about this place.
Hmm.
Uh, I heard a voice, though I don't know who it was.
A voice?
You listened to some strange voice?!
How naive can you get...
Yeow!
What are you doing?
Why don't you hold your tongue!
You stay out of this!
Don't fight because of me...
You said your name was?
Oh, it's Haru.
My name is Haru.
Okay, Haru.
Please do come in.
Don't worry about them.
You lousy black bird!
Don't you even know I'm a crow?
Come out from the dark, you fowl!
Nobody can miss a giant marshmallow like you!
You big hog of a cat!
Go get fried, chicken wings!
Shut up, moo shoo pork!
Pollo loco.
I'm coming in.
Whoa...
This place is gorgeous.
Now, do come in and have a seat.
Thank you.
Any lemon or milk with your tea?
Milk, please.
You have a beautiful office.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Cute.
It's my special blend.
Can't guarantee the flavor though, it's different each time.
This is good!
This is really good.
Then, you're lucky.
How can you drink green leaves?
Too refined for your tongue, I bet.
Go catch a worm, bird.
Muta...
Tell me about the Kingdom of Cats again.
That whole place is fake, a place for those who don't have a mind of their own.
Mind of their own...
One of the Cat King's men said they want me to marry their Prince...
Why not?
A cat's bride?
What?!
Might not be so bad.
This is going nowhere.
Could be an interesting experience.
I see.
I did want to visit the Kingdom of Cats once.
This might be a good opportunity.
How brave of you, Baron.
But I think I'll give it a miss.
You are coming with me.
No, thanks.
It's not my territory.
You're not taking her, are you?
That won't be wise.
But I can't leave her here all alone.
Babysitting isn't my thing either.
Are you busy?
Not really.
Um, I think I'll go home.
I'm just making trouble for all of you.
I started all this mess.
I have to solve this myself.
I see.
I'm sorry I couldn't be of any help.
Okay.
Okay, I'll do it.
I'll just hang around for a while.
You're a good cat, Muta!
It's set then.
Haru, you can come back now.
But...
Muta complains a lot, but doesn't actually mean it.
I see.
He is actually nice then.
That's right.
I'm not listening.
Thank you for your help.
Buta-san.
Bu?
Did you say Bu?!
Note: "Bu" is a reference to his overweight You said it on purpose, didn't you?!
I'm sorry, it wasn't on purpose!
This girl is not bad.
No way I am going to help!
Didn't we have some delicious chiffon cake in the cupboard?
Where?
On the upper right shelf.
Why didn't you say so.
Let's have a piece before we start.
I'll go get my special mulberries then!
It seems like this is going to be fun.
Let me help too.
Haru, you need to think about how you can learn to be yourself.
Then, you should have nothing to fear.
Okay.
Baron!
Give me a hand.
I'm putting some whipped cream on top.
We're really going full-scale.
Of course we are.
Maybe I'll find something here.
Yes.
Is that Toto-san at the door?
Haru-sama, we have come for you.
No!
What is this?
Not good.
You promised to help me!
Baron, horde of cats headed this way.
You're blind as a bat!
After them!
Haru-sama, we looked all over for you!
I'm going home.
Careful!
Let me off!
Take me back!
I am going back, this instant!
You must be having pre-marriage blues.
I am not!
Things got a bit out of hand.
Hey, you, wait, ouch, let go!
Muta-san, and Baron!
Let go, I'm telling you!
Toto, now!
Don't let go!
Why did we get out of the way!
No choice.
I'm really mad now!
Yay!
This is over the weight limit!
Toto!
I see it.
Where are you going?!
Out-maneuvered.
Go up.
OK.
Now what?
The wind.
Follow the lights.
OK!
Ouch...
I landed on my back...
Why?
Where am I?
Muta-san?
Did you get bigger?
No, you got smaller.
Why?
Because we're here.
This is the Kingdom of Cats?
This is it.
Wow, cats really live here.
Well, this is their kingdom, you know.
Hey, come on.
Ahh, it's so nice and relaxing here.
We should find a way out and go back.
Just a little longer.
Let's get going.
But... it feels so nice.
No!
You must go back at once.
Hurry.
Run away!
Hey, what a pretty cat.
Even the cats are prettier here.
Please, you have no time to lose!
Haru-chan, you are not meant to be here.
Why do you know my name?
Haru-sama!
It's that cat again.
I am so relieved to find you.
Seems we dropped you when coming in.
Your servant exceeded our weight limit.
Servant?!
No, no.
This is Muta-san.
Shall we?
A banquet is being prepared in your honor.
You are welcome to join us, Buta-sama.
Bu...
Bu?!
But I...
His Majesty is waiting at the palace.
Palace?
The palace is right over there.
Oh, really.
Yes, indeed.
Hey.
You're not thinking of...
Maybe it's rude not to greet the King first.
Are you out of your mind?
Please, this way.
Wait.
Can she come with us?
What is your name?
My name is Yuki.
I serve at the royal table.
So you work at the palace.
Haru-sama, you'll see her later.
Okay, I'll see you again.
Haru-chan.
What's that?
Creepy!
There's my future daughter-in-law.
Well, I must go see her in person!
He's strangely familiar.
Please change before meeting the King.
I need to change clothes?
Please wait in the next room.
Why can't I go in with her?
Don't be gross.
Gross?
We prepared refreshments for you.
Okay, I'll wait.
Not bad.
The dress is very becoming on you.
Prince Lune is the idol of all female cats in this Kingdom.
You'll be very happy with him.
Really?
I mean, no.
That's not why I'm here.
You look lovely.
You are the purrfect bride for Lune.
Natoru, who is that cat?
A servant named Buta-sama, I believe.
Buta?
Never heard of him.
No match for my stomach.
Um, I am sorry, but I can't really accept marriage to...
I thought you already said yes?
That was what I was told.
Where is the Prince?
He is away at an official function.
Anyway, I don't really know him.
And the Prince, he is a cat, right?
I'm not a cat, so I can't marry him.
That, you don't need to worry about.
You already are a cat.
Wow, real cat ears.
I'm a CAT!
Muta-san!
What happened to him?
He insisted on having a bowl full and dunked himself in catnip jelly.
He didn't have to die like this!
Muta-san, how could you do this to me?
The banquet is ready to begin.
No!
I don't want to leave him.
Then, he will come with us.
Is this Haru-sama?
She has a perfect pair of ears!
Such full attractive paws!
I was told you don't like mice, so I have prepared fresh fish for you.
Haru doesn't seem pleased.
What do we have for entertainment?
I will bring them in.
I want something more amusing.
Next!
Can't you do anything better?!
I shall amuse Haru-sama.
What should we do?
Why not?
Shall we dance?
I can't dance meow.
Oh no, I even sound like a cat!
Trust me.
They dance well together.
What is this...
I never felt like this before.
Being a cat might not be that bad.
No, Haru.
Don't lose yourself.
You must learn to be yourself.
I already told you that, didn't I?
You are...
Stop this music!
You suspicious cat.
Exactly who are you?
Apologies for my belated introduction.
There is nothing to fear.
I am Humbert von Gikkingen.
I have come for Haru.
Baron!
Can this be?
What?
No way.
Guards, get him!
I can't eat anymore.
It's alive!
I'm glad, you're alive, Muta-san.
Uh oh.
Stop, you scoundrel!
Take His Majesty to a safe place!
Don't let him get away.
Guests' emergency exit this way.
Out of my way!
Muta-san.
You're strong!
I didn't start it.
This way.
You're the cat from before...
Baron, I knew you would come.
How do you know me?
I've heard about you and your Office.
If I had listened to you, this wouldn't have happened.
If you leave before dawn, you can still become human.
Really?
A secret passage to the outside.
This is convenient.
What about Muta-san?
He'll be all right.
Hurry, Haru.
Yes.
This is the back of the castle.
The top of that tower leads to the exit.
It's so tall!
You must go through the ruins to the tower and then climb up.
We'll make it.
Good.
Please take care of Haru-chan.
Wait.
She is gone.
I haven't even thanked her yet.
Haru, this is just my guess.
But isn't she the one who led you to me?
Haru-chan.
The Cat Business Office.
Yes, that beautiful voice was hers.
But why?
Because of you, I almost died.
We must hurry now.
Right.
You guys, listen to me.
Did they go in?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Purrfect.
That labyrinth was built with our state-of-the-art technology.
We'll enjoy the view from here.
Tricky.
The sun is still high, though.
It's always daytime here.
What?
It is?
It's probably past midnight outside.
Then, we have to hurry!
This way?
That way?
Which way should we go?
They are lost.
It won't be easy to get out of there.
Right, Your Majesty?
Yes...
We have nothing to worry about.
Where are the soldiers?
Over there.
Let's go this way.
We must keep trying, one by one.
Keep your eyes on the tower.
You won't lose your way.
Smart.
Muta-san, you're cheating.
Why get lost just 'cause it's a maze.
There he is!
Why does it have to be me?
Let's hurry while he keeps them busy.
Right.
Why do I have to be the bait?!
Get back, Haru!
You're strong!
Your cane got bent?
I was going to buy a new one anyway.
Used is best.
Nice shot!
It hit one of ours!
What?
Your Majesty, how could you?
Don't tell anyone, okay?
Excuse me, sir.
Our men are all scattered.
They are all lost.
Where is Haru-chan?
They already got that far!
Hi!
Welcome back.
How's that way?
It's a dead end.
Everything as planned.
Is this another dead end?
It's getting more difficult.
Something's wrong!
There was no wall here a minute ago.
It must be your imagination.
No, we walked through here.
Are you saying that walls have feet?
This is no wall.
It's fake.
See?
Good work, Haru!
What is all this?
I told them not to get in line!
They are getting away!
Your Majesty, wait!
Go ahead.
I'll catch up with you.
Show off!
No, Baron...
Don't worry!
Your Majesty, please, it's dangerous.
I can't let this happen!
I have soldiers waiting in the tower, just in case.
Brilliant move!
Good, good.
I'm afraid the tower's getting old...
This is not good at all!
We have no choice, but use THAT.
What?
No, not that!
If you do that, Your Majesty, your image will go to shambles.
Give me the button!
There is no such thing here.
Here's the remote control.
Yay, we came out to an opening.
Just a bit more.
Now!
What?
Hold on!
That was a great spectacle!
Let's go!
We're back on the ground.
Let's see how things go.
We have no choice.
Come on, come on.
Gikkingen-kun, nice to see you again.
Haru-chan!
We'll go back to the castle right away.
Being a cat is not so bad.
Do I have to learn to like mice?
It's too early to give up.
What's all this?
Father!
Lune, you're back already?
His Highness the Prince!
As you were!
Prince?
I hurried back, thanks to Yuki-chan.
What is all this?
Haru-chan.
Oh, we meet again.
I'm glad we made it.
Err, I just wanted to thank her.
I thought you'd be happy to have Haru-chan as your bride.
You don't need to worry about me.
I want to marry Yuki-chan.
What?!
Looks like news to everyone.
This Prince is not bad.
Yuki-chan, look.
I went to your old home to find this.
Oh, could this be what I think it is?
Those cookies...
I used to love those.
That's right.
These are the fish cookies you gave me when I was an orphan kitten.
That kitten, that was you!
You're so beautiful now that I didn't recognize you.
Yuki-chan.
Will you accept these as a token of our life together from now on?
That means...
You two are getting married?
Oh, I am so happy for you, Yuki-chan!
Thank you, Haru-chan!
If I hadn't met you then, I could have starved on the streets.
You also saved me from danger.
I didn't know you were the person Yuki told me so much about.
You saved both of our lives.
How can we thank you?
I don't want anything.
You two made me so happy already.
Saving a cat was a good thing.
This is such a moving sight.
So you already had a fianc?