Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network,  Dentsu, Hakuhodo DYMP, Walt Disney Japan,  Mitsubishi, Toho and KDDI present The Tale of the Princess Kaguya Executive Producer: Seiichiro Ujiie Based on the Japanese Folktale "The Tale of the Bamboo Cutter" Original Concept: Isao Takahata Screenplay: Isao Takahata, Riko Sakaguchi Music: Joe Hisaishi Theme Song: Kazumi Nikaido Character Design and Directing Animator: Osamu Tanabe Art Director: Kazuo Oga Planning: Toshio Suzuki Producer: Yoshiaki Nishimura Director: Isao Takahata Once upon a time long long ago now, there lived an old bamboo cutter.
He would make his way into the mountain forest and cut wild bamboo, from which he made all sorts of useful things...
His name was Sanuki no Miyatsuko.
One day he noticed a light shining from inside a bamboo stalk...
Curious the bamboo cutter approached it.
As he approached it, the light flowed into the ground...
creating something he had never seen before.
What is this?
Bamboo shoot sprouting so early?
Even before the plums?
What is this?
Have mercy on me!
Hello...
May I ask please, who might you be, my lady?
Oh my!
She is such a beautiful little princess!
It's a miracle!
This must be a blessing from Heaven, I'm sure of it!
You're back early.
Something wrong?
Ah!
What a beautiful little doll!
No quiet, you'll wake her.
She's sleeping.
Ah!
Shh.
She just appeared to me in the grove.
Appeared?
Definetly a blessing from Heaven!
Hey!
Heaven gave it to me!
Oh?
Well I'm the one who'll raise her.
Raise her?
She's already a perfect little princess.
No no no!
Don't be silly, there is more to raising a child than you think.
Right?
Here let me take her...
Oh!
Don't just sit there!
Go find a lenght of cloth or something warm I can wrap her in!
Don't be upset, sweetheart.
We're gonna take very good care of you.
I promise.
Will this work?
There, there!
You're gonna be just fine.
That's a good girl!
What's happening?
What's going on?
Can't you see?
She wants me to be the person who raises her!
Bring me one of the good baskets, please.
Alright!
This is really strange, you know.
I mean think about it...
What if she's a woodland spirit or something?
What does she look like to you?
A little baby, of course.
That's right!
But she was a beautiful princess just a moment ago!
Well I have to believe thats Heaven showing us what a beautiful princess she's going to become someday when she's all grown up.
You're right!
Of course.
So that means we have to raise the baby properly right from the start.
Yes, that must be it.
I see I'm glad you understand.
I'll be right there helping!
Wait!
We have to find a breast for her.
That's why I'm taking her to a wet nurse.
Yes, I heard there was a new baby in the woodworker settlement.
Is that what this is for?
Yes, we had to bring a gift.
What's wrong?
Hey!
Hey what are you doing?
Oh you poor thing!
I guess you were really hungry.
How did you do that?
You see?
She's very content, she's drinking it right down.
Yeah!
I can't begin to explain it, but I have milk!
She's laughing!
Ah!
I might be imagining it but she feels heavier.
No!
That can't be!
What's the matter?
She just got even heavier!
What?
Let me see.
She seems to be growing right before our very eyes.
Look!
The plum blossoms!
I think she's got a little heavier!
You see?
She's certainly healthy!
And from that day forward the Bamboo Cutter and his wife...
carefully raised this miraculous child, as if she were their very own.
Careful!
You do not want to touch those.
Look!
There's a baby in there!
Can you make it?
Stop pushing!
See?
There she is!
Hey!
She's looking over here!
Yeah!
She is!
No she's not!
What's the matter?
Oh!
Hey!
Princess!  Princess!
She's standing!
She's begun to walk!
Oh!
Hey now!
Alright...
Hah!
That kid's weird!
She can walk now!
Yeah!
She was just crawling.
I think she just got bigger too!
She grows fast!
Like bamboo!
That'll be her name!
Little Bamboo!
That's perfect!
What do you mean Little Bamboo?
She's Princess!
Princess!
Little Bamboo!
Come here!
Princess... come here!
Atta girl!
Come here Little Bamboo!
Be quiet!
Little Bamboo!
Princess!
Come here!
Princess... come here!
Little Bamboo!
Princess, Princess... come here Little Bamboo!
...come here, Princess!
C'mon Princess!
Princess!
Come here!
Yeah!
You wanna come with me?
C'mon!
We'll have these bamboo shoots for dinner.
Dinner!
Bamboo shoot!
Alright now!
Stand back Princess.
There's lots of them!
Yeah!
Come here!
Stupid!
You don't mess with wild boar piglets!
Huh?
You're really a strange kid!
It looks like you just got bigger!
That kid's weird, Sutemaru.
Woh!
Look at her!
She's grown again!
She's just like a bamboo shoot.
Yeah you're right!
Bamboo shoot!
For dinner!
Little Bamboo!
* Go round, go round * * Waterwheel, go round * * Go round, and call Mr.
Sun * * Birds, bugs, beasts, grass, flowers and trees * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * bring 'em all on * * Go round, go round * * Waterwheel go round * * Go round and call Mr.
Sun * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * bring 'em all on * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * bring 'em all on * Birds!
Bugs!
Beasts!
Grass!
Flowers!
And trees!
Tell me something?
How come you know this song?
I just know it!
* Go round, go round * * Waterwheel go round * * Distant time, come round * * Oh distant time * Come round, call back my heart Come round, call back my heart Birds, bugs, beasts, grass, flowers...
I will want to return to you, I will want to return to you...
Those aren't the words.
Hey!
She's crying!
Yeah she is!
What's wrong?
I don't know.
She's so weird!
Look!
That's where our houses are.
And that's your bamboo grove.
Yeah!
Bamboo shoots!
It's time to go!
C'mon!
Princess!
Where are you?
Where... where are you?
Where could she have gone?
What is that?
What's this?
I'll be back later!
I will!
I'm a little worried, those boys are rough.
She might get hurt playing with them.
They're fine, don't worry.
It's good for her.
Yeah, it's just that up in the bamboo grove...
Ah... no, it's nothin' No no, that's lacquer!
You'll get a rash!
Lacquer?
That smells good!
He's gonna make bowls out of those.
Really?
Goodbye!
Bye!
Bring us a present!
Bring us back a present!
This is the Bamboo Cutter's daughter.
Little Bamboo.
Little Bamboo!
It's okay, c'mon jump!
It's really hot!
I'm thirsty.
I bet those...
I bet those are so sweet.
They are?
Hey!
Come back!
Let's go!
Someone's coming!
Leave it!
I'll save this for the others.
Delicious!
Then when I saw these beautiful robes shooting up in the air, I finally realized...
what Heaven wishes to be done.
What Heaven wishes to be done?
Think of Princess a way of life, that is appropriate to this robe.
Raise her as a Princess of noble rank.
That is what Heaven expects of us!
What are you saying?
With this gold I was given.
I am going to build the Princess a fine mansion in the capital.
You're taking her to the capital?
I must.
Out here in these mountains she's  nothing but a country girl.
Up in the capital she'll become a noble  princess...
She'll have the opportunity to meet other nobility...
And I believe she'll be happier.
Well, in any case, that is the command of the Heavens.
I don't know about this...
Well I do.
Anyway, tomorrow I will travel to the capital.
From the next day on, the old Bamboo Cutter went to the capital city often...
with the front of his kimono filled with gold.
The summer season passed, and the time of the autumn harvest came round.
* Blow wind, blow, blow * * Blow, blow hard, oh wind * Little Bamboo!
Can you please take him?
Sure!
* Bring the fruit of the mountains * * Chestnuts, chestnuts... * * Mushrooms, mountain, mountain grapes * Pick up!
Pick up!
I'm gonna get this all over you!
Look!
A pheasant!
It's heading for you!
Little Bamboo!
Chase it to the left!
I got it!
It's coming your way Sutemaru!
You're not getting away!
Sutemaru!
Sutemaru are you okay?
I got it.
I got it!
Yeah he got it!
That's awazing!
Are you okay?
I'm coming down to help you.
It wont hold!
Sutemaru!
I'm really sorry!
Are you okay?
Stupid!
Those rocks are too loose to climb!
I'm sorry.
Go find a long piece of ivy and bring it here!
Yeah okay!
Oh!
Hey you're bleeding!
It's nothing a little bit of spit won't fix.
No!
Wait!
Little Bamboo...
Have you gotten bigger again?
Yeah?
You think so?
I do.
I have this feeling you're gonna keep on growing...
and go somewhere different, and leave us behind.
I don't know why you would say that?
Your Little Bamboo will always be here with you, forever and ever.
And I'll always be a part of your gang, forever and ever, too.
Sutemaru!
Is this one alright?
Looks good.
Tie it to a tree!
We did!
Good!
Here.
Thanks.
Hey, look at this!
There's mushrooms here!
Look, Sutemaru!
They look delicious!
There are so many of them growing here!
Tomorrow we can make stew for everyone!
Yeah!
I'll get the pheasant ready!
Pheasant stew!
Pheasant!
Sorry I'm late.
Sutemaru caught a pheasant.
And we found some mushrooms.
Oh, and mountain grapes!
Where are you going?
The capital.
The capital?
Me, too?
Right now?
Yes.
Just leave the basket on the ground.
What?
But we're making pheasant stew tomorrow.
I promised Sutemaru that we...
Just put it down.
Now, let's go.
Can we come back tomorrow in time for stew?
But for the Princess and for Sutemaru, that tomorrow never came.
The young lady is awake.
Good morning, my lady.
If you please...
Ah!
Well, well, Princess!
And can I ask you, if Your Highness' mood, would you be in the best of spirituals today?
Is that you Momma?
And Papa?
Why are you dressed like that?
I suppose we aren't doing this right!
I am!
My Princess!
Get yourself a change of range.
I mean, a range of chobes!
Sorry.
Get a change of robe!
All of these robes are yours, Your Highness.
Wow!
These smell good!
They're beautiful!
They're like falling rainbows!
She's having a great time, she seems to like them.
Well, of course!
As of today, this will be our new home.
This mansion is ours?
That's right.
Poppa, I can swim in there... can't I?
You most certainly will not swim in there.
A noble princess would never frolic, nor even consider part taking in such unlady like antics.
Your Highness...
I have thusly summoned Lady Sagami here from the palace to educate you...
in the ways of nobility.
Her job is to make you a noble princess!
Noble princess?
From the palace?
My Lord!
This child is clearly in desperate need of my instruction.
Naturally, I would have liked to have started earlier but I, Sagami, will mould her into a truely fine young lady.
And so the Princess, under Lady Sagami's tutelage...
began to learn the heirs and graces of a noble lady.
Watch this carefully.
Keep your back like so, as straight as an arrow.
Swish up perfectly, like this.
Swish?
That is approximately correct.
The truth is, a noble princess stands only on rare occasions.
But... how do I move if I want to pick up something?
Like this...
Come to a kneeling position and schuffle your knees, to move gracefully.
Shuffle, shuffle, shuffle.
Notice nothing else moves.
Your Highness!
We are far from done!
Wow!
It is a beautiful scroll, is it not?
A proper way of looking at it, is like this, so the story flows.
Look!
Now it's really flowing!
How about a small reward?
Oh!
It makes me so proud to see you practicing your letters...
I'm happy to see my teachings are reaching you.
Your Highness!
Yes!
Now once more, together.
Hey, that was fun!
Your Highness!
How's practice coming along?
Is everything going smoothly?
Ah, My Lord!
I trust you are well, Father.
Oh, my!
You've become so elegant I hardly recognize you.
How about the koto lessons, are they coming along as well?
We've only just begun... she only knows a few notes!
My, how beautiful!
It's very suspicious and I'm starting to wonder if someone else has trained her before...
In front of you, she performs perfectly but with me, she's all games!
Oh!
That's right!
Her Highness' a being who has come straight down from Heaven.
She was never supposed to stay in the mountains like some kind of common girl.
With her father watching proudly, the Princess devoted herself to Lady Sagami's training.
What is happening here?
Why are you still behaving like some kind of a servant!
You are, if nothing else, the mother to a noble princess.
But this is the only way I feel at ease living in this house.
And it's because you feel that way the princess never changes her...
Princess, what's wrong?
You're extremely quiet today.
Come over here and listen husband...
What?
Really?
Yes.
That's wonderful news!
We'll have to hold a great banquet!
A banquet?
A celebration of your coming of age.
Well, of course!
This is the happiest of occasions!
If we're having a party,  can we can invite my friends?
I'd love to see them all!
Your friends from the village!
That would be wonderful for you.
Don't be stupid!
You don't understand anything!
Do you realize how important this is?
We live in a much different world than those hillbillies back in our old village!
This banquet will make you  a truly noble princess!
So right after the new year we'll have a celebration!  With putting up with hair, and the naming ritual.
But Poppa...
Ah!
This is wonderful!
I mean, it's wonderful!
Wait!
I'll ask Inbe no Akita.
He'll serve as the name father.
Hello?
Is anybody there?
Lady Sagami?
What a bore.
* Birds, bugs, beasts * * Grass, flowers and trees * * Teach people how to feel * Momma, would you give a part of the garden to me?
Why?
It would be fun to plant some of the things I like.
Yes, yes of course if it makes you happy.
You can do whatever you want with it.
Thank you, Momma.
No!
Get away!
You will never be a noble princess looking as you do now.
Without eyebrows the sweat will run into my eyes!
Don't be ridiculous.
For a noble princess there is nothing that will maker her perspire!
Come...
Why would I want black teeth?
I wouldn't open my mouth then!
And I won't be able to laugh anymore!
You won't have to worry about that!  For a noble princess does not open her mouth to laugh.
That's stupid!
Even a noble princess must sweat and sometimes want to laugh out loud!
Surely they wanna cry, or get mad and wanna scream!
A noble princess should never show...
Then a noble princess is not human!
Princess!
The poor thing was all tied up!
Your Highness!
This way, Lord Akita and thank you for coming.
Princess!
This is extremely embarassing!
I'm afraid she's still but a child.
No... not at all.
She looks like an adorable little princess.
She hasn't been properly made up yet.  I am truly ashamed and I must apologize to you!
No!
Please don't give it another thought.
If I see her face as it really is...
the better I can divine of a truly appropriate name for the Princess.
Those are very welcome words.
I have every confidence that you will bestow upon the princess a very fine name.
Please Your Highness, come out and greet this gentlemen who will give you your name.
How do you do, my lord?
It's an honor to meet you.
Your Highness, if you wouldn't mind, perhaps you could perform something, on the koto for our esteemable guest.
Beautiful!
The Shining Princess of the Supple Bamboo...
The Shining Princess...
of the Supple Bamboo?
Yes.
She has a form as graceful as supple bamboo...
and a beauty that radiates out from her!
Superb!
So then I add a name for "Princess of the Shining Light" And thus I suggest to you the name "Princess Kaguya" Yes!
How beautiful!
I'm so proud, Lord Akita, that is the most wonderful name I've ever heard!
Thank you very much.
As is the custom, the naming ceremony was followed by putting up the hair and dawning the trailing skirt.
Soon after, large numbers were invited to the great banquet...
to celebrate the naming of Princess Kaguya.
Congratulations sir!
Princess Kaguya...  a truly fine name.
This is wonderful, right?
Just wonderful.
There are many good gentlemen who have come to the banquet!
Then the purpose of this banquet is to celebrate the taking of my name?
Of course it is, mam.
Yes, but... all I'm doing is sitting here.
It's like...  I'm not even at my own party.
Thank you very much!
The banquet to celebrate the naming of Princess Kaguya, went on for three days, and three nights.
Here to Princess Kaguya to celebrate the putting up of her hair!
A fine thing!
Yes?
Really my friend!
This is all a bit pretentious, don't you think?
What?
The Princess... the so called Princess C'mon you know what we mean?
Princess Kaguya or whoever...
Her flower of a face enshrined behind that blind.
Clearly there wouldn't be any harm in allowing us to see her if she's as beautiful as they say?
Yeah!
Why not?
I agree!
No no!
I'm afraid that would be out of the question.  What's happening here?
We've come to celebrate her naming, and we don't even get to say hello?
I'm sorry!
But that's just the way things are done!
What do you mean?
The way things are done!
No wait!
There's no noble princess here!
Yeah!
You're right!
Who are you saying Her Highess is?
Her Highest?
How much did it cost?
A naming ceremony for this Princess?
Who cares about that?
Atleast show her to us!
Maybe she looks like some kind of goblin!
Or worse!
Excuse me?
Where did the people who were living down below go?
I wouldn't know.
They packed themselves up...
Took off on a journey to find better wood.
Better wood?
They probably won't be back for ten years.
Ten years?
If you use up all the trees, the mountain is ruined.
But if you leave the mountain its power, and go on a journey...
it comes back to life.
Trees need a good ten years, then you can work them again!
It's like that for charcoal burning too.
I see... but the mountain looks dead already.
The leaves used to be so full and bright here...
Everything comes back eventually.
See for yourself.
The trees are already getting ready for spring.
Getting ready?
So spring will come back again?
Sure it will.
It's like a circle, just when you think one ends, another begins again.
You can always count on it.
So who might you be?
I've seen this before.
I've seen it.
From that day forward, it was as if Princess Kaguya...
was another person, devoting herself to her studies...
and passing her days in silence.
Hey look!
Look at this huge pile of gifts from the nobility!
The high born have now accepted you!
See?
They obviously consider you to be one of them!
You know what?
This bird deserves a much better space...
How about, for old time's sake, I weave you a fine bamboo cage to keep him in?
Now what do you think about that, huh?
Thank you, Father.
Ha-ha!
Wonderful!
It's wonderful!
I mean, wonderful!
Wonderful!
I'll just leave the bird right here.
Thanks be to Heaven!
As time went on, rumours of the Princess' beauty grew.
The streets outside the mansion became cramped with people...
hoping to catch a glimpse, of the mysterious Princess Kaguya.
Are you a servant of Princess Kaguya?
If your are, give her this for me!
Give this to her!
No!
You must give this to her!
First!
See that she gets this!
Please!
She needs this gift!
You must take this to her, right away!
There's another crowd of gentlemen suitors in the streets.
They've were very persistant.
They gave me all these letters and demanded that I pass on to you.
And so I am, and since it seems to be impossible for...
you to go outside the mansion, I thought I'd bring you some cherry blossoms.
Thank you!
I hear you have summoned me, Prince Ishitsukuri?
Yes, it's about that rich upstart's daughter whom you named...
Oh!
You're taking about Princess Kaguya?
Shh!
Keep your voice down!
Did you say Princess Kaguya?
Woh!
Princess Kaguya?
I've heard the rumours about her.
They say that she's very beautiful.
You fool!
You had to raise your voice didn't you?
But don't matter how beautiful they say she is...  she is still of humble birth.
So she is not a woman appropriate for any of us.
Even you have to admit Akita, that Princess Kaguya is a very presumptuous name...
to be given the likes of a commoners daughter.
No matter how much you paid for it.
Not so, Lord Minister.
This beautiful girl is not Miyatsuko's true daughter.
She was found in a bamboo stalk.
What?
A bamboo stalk?
Now that's interesting!
She could be some kind of forest spirit!
After seeing her with my own eyes... that is entirely possible, my Lord.
Really?
I must confess, that the moment I stood before Princess Kaguya...
this old man's body began to tremble...
as if a dry fountain had come flowing back to life!
Even remebering her now, words fail to express her glimmering beauty, and my heart...
surges as I remember every moment looking at her!
Out of the way!
I swear!
I will win this race!
I must get to her first!
That glimmering beauty will be mine, I tell you, nothing will stop me!
The one who will win her is me!
I swear!
She will be my wife!
Lady Sagami!  You have to see these!
What is it, my lord?
Just look at these!
Look at them all!
Five of the most high-born men in the land have come calling for one simple reason...
they wanna marry the Princess!
Oh, my!
Oh!
Wonderful!
All these princes are interested in her...
and even the Minister of the Right!
But how do we choose among them?
It's going to be a very difficult challenge!
And to make matters worse, they are all waiting impatiently in formal dress even as we speak!
I will take care of this.
Leave Her Highness to me.
You go entertain them, and whatever you do, keep them happy!
Alright, my lady!
Oh and thank you!
Thank you!
Wonderful!
I just knew that banquet was worth putting on!
These are five proposals from five of the most...
important nobles in the land.
Whichever one you choose, you cannot go wrong!
But I've never even met them!
Oh!
Please don't worry!
This is very simple!
You'll pick a proposal from one of these noble gentlemen, and then you'll meet him on your wedding day.
It hardly matters because with any of these fine princely men, you'll be happy forever... and ever!
I have no intension of marrying anyone yet.
Have you lost your mind!
Once you have become a noble princess, you must marry a suitable gentleman as quickly as possible!
That is the very defintion of happiness!
Why would you even think twice?
With any of these men, your happiness would be completely guaranteed.
I do not want any of it!
So please tell those men to leave.
Do you really want to hurt your father like this?
Do you understand that he is as happy for you, as he would be for himself?
Everything has been made ready for you.
If you would be so kind to come this way...
Now please, express your proposal to the Princess in order.
I am Prince Kuramochi.
Princess...
as you know my true feelings have been clearly stated in the letter that has been given to you...
Your Highness, Princess Kaguya, if I were so fortunate...
that you became my wife, it would be as if I plucked a branch of the tree of jewels...
that grows on the Mountain of Horai...
whose trunk is of gold and it's fruits are the whitest of pearls.
Princess Kaguya, you are an exquiste treasure that is as unattainable...
precious as that...
I'm Prince Ishitsukuri!
Princess Kaguya, if you consent to be my wife...
I will worship you morning and night.
My forehead pressed to the ground in utter devotion...
you are a treasure I would revear as much as the stone begging bowl of Lord Buddha himself.
You would worship her as if she were some cold stone bowl?
Princess Kaguya, to me you are as a robe of fire-rat fur.
From which when thrown in the fire, all the impurities is burned away...
but which itself is not consumed, only shining more brightly as the flames grow higher...
you are utterly rare.
Untouched and innocent.
As illusive as this treasure about, which they speak of finding in China.
You have the goal to compare Princess Kaguya to a rat-skin?
Princess, to me...
Councilor Otomo you are a fine glistening jewel, a jewel that shines intensly from above.
A gem with more radiance than the five colored jewel that shines on the dragon's neck!
Oh!
No, no, no!
For me, Princess Kaguya...
is something more precious and natural, like the warm cowry shell amulets, swallows use as a charm...
for safe birth.
That is a true treasure!
A true treasure...
You think a boring everyday seashell is a treasure?
You must be crazy!
Well... well, a dragon's neck stinks you know!
It's on the neck!
What a beautiful sound!
She is truly gifted!
Gentlemen!
I'm most grateful for the sentiments you expressed...
to someone you have never seen or met.
Yet there is something else I require...
These rare treasures that are difficult to obtain...
I ask... that you bring them to me.
Then, and only then, will I be able to clearly and fully  understand how you treasure me in your hearts...
Prince Kuramochi, present to me a jewel branch from Mount Horai.
Prince Ishitsukuri, the stone begging bowl of Lord Buddha.
How?
But...
Lord Minister of the Right Abe, bring a robe made of fire-rat fur.
Excuse me?
Grand Counselor Otomo, obtain the jewel from the great dragon's neck.
Middle Counselor Isonokami,  please bring me the swallow's cowry shell...
The amulet of easy child birth...
Wait!
Wait... but that!
No, no no no...
All these items would be impossible to find, even if they do exist!
Princess, these five gentlemen were only using them as comparisons!
Yes.
All these gentlemen compared me to very rare treasures.
Therefore, whomever can present me the real treasure...
I will happily become that noble gentleman's real treasure.
Gentlemen please, I humbely apologize!
My daughter knows nothing of the ways of the world.
But she must be a beautiful princess.
Her voice, her music...
Indeed, I must say that melody was quite out of this world.
The truth is, she is asking us to achieve an impossible task...
Impossible!
It can't be done!
She'll remain a jewel that no one can acquire.
This is terrible!
When the nobles left, so did all the other people who were waiting in front of the mansion!
They disapperaed just like the tide going out.
Exactly.
I thought I better let you know right away.
Your Highness!
C'mon!
Let's go!
Go?
Where?
Outside!
Outside?
Yes!
Let's go see the cherry blossoms!
You know what? we should ask father and mother to come along with us!
I'm sorry, but there is no longer anything I can do.
But, but...
The next time I'm sure the Princess will try to, ah...
There will certainly be no next time!
She has burnt her last bridge.
I will take my leave of you!
Oh no, please don't go...
Squire, the cart the Princess requested has arrived.
They are just waiting for you sir.
Tell them to go on ahead without me!
I'm not going!
Stop here!
Oh, my!
It's beautiful!
I'm very sorry, your Highness.
Please forgive us!
Let's go.
The cherry blossoms are right at their peak.
I must say, they're certainly splendid to experience.
Let's go home.
But...
Keep everyone back!
Stay back!
Clear the space here!
There seems to have been an accident up ahead.
Oh!
Someone's running this way.
Sutemaru!
It's Sutemaru!
What are you doing?!
C'mon!
Let's get out of here!
We're going!
Little Bamboo!
Sutemaru!
Let's go.
Three years passed...
Go on.
It's a lovely day, isn't it?
The plants in the garden seem to be thriving!
Yes, but you know...
It looks completely different from down here!
Well!
Yes!
See!
It looks like the mountain, doesn't it?
You're right.
There's the forest and a hill...
Oh my!
It is just like home!
That's right!
And see the cogan grass?
It looks just like the bamboo grove.
And the mugwort looks just like trees!
And Mr.
Moon could rise up from right behind those mountains, couldn't it?
Yes!
And look!
We can go across that bridge and climb over the hill...
Princess!
Where is the Princess?
You're in the kitchen again?
And what's wrong with that once in a while?
It's not once in a while, it's all the time!
Anyway...  I have news about Kuramochi!
What?
He brought back the jeweled branch from Mount Horai!
It's quite an accomplishment!
Impossible!
Yes, yes!
And I never thought such a thing would happen, believe me...
he is true to his word!
An impossible task, and he pulled it off!
I wouldn't be surprised if he would had me!
But he really did what he said he'd do!
Now!
After we recieve the gift, you must prepare yourself quickly to be married to the Prince.
My heavens!
I have to go!
I must prepare a bedchamber for the Prince and Your Highness!
If only Lady Sagami were here!
I don't believe it!
Prepare a bedchamber...?
Where is the Princess?
Quickly where is Princess Kaguya?
Please wait, Your Highness!
Please wait!
Ah!
Mr.
Miyatsuko!
Please forgive my appearance.
I was so anxious to get here,  I didn't have time to change my traveling clothes!
Your presence is always welcome here!
This is most truly wonderful!
Please... come in!
I'll show you the way.
Splendid.
Without further ado, I will present the promised object.
What can I say?
It's dazzling!
It leaves me speechless!
It's so... what the...
It is as you requested.
The jeweled branch of Mount Horai.
Princess Kaguya, can you see it?
Come closer!
Here!
I will bring it closer to you.
One moment, please.
First, allow me to ask you how you found it.
It must be quite a story...
Oh!
It is quite a story!
Three years ago I vowed to carry out your Highness' wish...
I then set my plan in motion...
from the harbor at Naniwa I set course for the Mountain of Horai.
We were tossed by fierce waves...
we nearly starved from lack of food...
and after a grueling, harrowing journey...
Behold!
What is that mountain, so forbidding yet so very beautiful?
What is this?
It flows with water of gold and precious gems!
Look!
A maiden scoops water with a silver bowl!
Dear Maiden...
please tell me what is the name of that mountain?
That is the Mountain of Horai.
And you are very brave to have travelled so far!
Ah!
I had finally arrived at the Mountain of Horai!
Without a second glance at the lovely maiden, I climbed the mountain.
Behold!
Those precious, exquiste trees!
Silver branches, a trunk of gold and fruit of pearls!
So beautiful!
It takes my breath away...
Are these not the jeweled branches of Horai...
the very thing that Princess Kaguya said she wished?
And thus, without haste, I snapped off this branch to bring to your feet.
One look is worth a hundred stories.
Please, won't you see for yourself Your Highness!
Stop!
You shall not pass!
Move!
Get out of my way!
What is that?
What's going on?
I'm sincerely sorry.
I'll go see.
Let go!  She must read this letter!
What's going on?
Just pay us our fee!
We are here to collect for the jeweled branch that we made!
What's that?!
The branch they made?
I am Ayabe no Uchimaro, a craftsman belonging to the Guild of Artisans.
At the order of Prince Kuramochi, we gathered together precious gems, mounted them...
and put them together, as if it came from a jeweled tree on Mount Horai.
Really?
However, the Prince has made no effort to pay us what we are owed!
That's an outrage!
sorry, one of his wives, was here, we decided to take action.
Ill mannered as such a move may be, in the end we had no choice!
Since the Prince has been avoiding us, it was our decision to try to collect our payment from her!
That's why we have come to collect at  your residence!
I understand.
I'll talk to him!
So what's going...?
Woh!
Where have you gone?!
Where... where's the branch?
Father, I'm afraid the Prince has taken his leave.
He has?
We should at least reward the Artisans!
They really did quite a nice job with that branch!
Next to call at the mansion was Lord Abe, Minister of the Right.
Feast your eyes on this!
It shimmers with an absolutely wonderous light!
It's extraordinary!
In all the world, there's never been an engagement gift as costly as the one I'm holding here!
However if it should please Princess Kaguya, the expence is really nothing!
I'm your trifle to win  the heart of this lovely damsel.
In that case then...
Oh, the Princess is close by!
Drop it in the fire.
Huh?
Excuse me?
If it's truly made of fire-rat fur...
it will not burn but merely glisten...  all the brighter.
Of course, Princess!
This fire-rat robe is no fake, it's genuine!
Genuine!
If placed in the fire, it should not burn.
But, I fear that... between the...
Princess and myself, there remains an issue...
A grain of unwarranted impurity.
A question of my varasity on the subject!
Is that true?
It's very possible.
All the more reason... to put it in the fire.
To burn all the impurity of my doubts.
Clean away!
Yes, Your Highness!
Look!
You see?
Ha-ha My entire fortune burning up in my hand!
I've lost everything!
It's a complete disaster!
What a mad sum of money I've stuck into this robe!
Look at it now!
Look, look!
It is all beacause you told me to burn it!
How much do you think the the Minister of the Right actually spent, to create that fake?
I'm sure that's all I am to those gentlemen.
What?
I'm a fake jeweled branch or a fire-rat fur robe that turns to ashes.
Well both of them were very expensive it would seem.
But have no fear, your suitors are trying.
I'm told that Grand Counselor Otomo has gone by ship...
He's traveling to Takoshi in a brave attempt to secure the stone from the dragon's neck.
What?
He is doing everything he can to bring you to him...
It's quite a story, they say he has sent his wife far away and is in the process of completely rebuilding his mansion...
A warrior's determination is a very powerful thing.
All right, Dragon!
Arise and meet your fate!
Watch out!
The Dragon!
Forgive me!
The dragon's everywhere!
Calm down!
The storm will pass.
While the warrior faced his dragons, Prince Ishitsukuri was paying a call on Princess Kaguya.
What's this?
You found Buddha's begging bowl?
This is extraordinary, Your Highness!
I don't know what to say!
Give it to Princess Kaguya.
So you brought something other than the bowl?
Please, just give it to her.
Well, alright...
Hey Princess, this is a gift from Prince Ishitsukuri.
Since I first heard her voice three years ago...
Princess Kaguya has not left my heart for even a moment...
I set out on my quest desperately  searching for Buddha's begging bowl...
Over meadow and mountain I walked, calling on temples throughout the land.
Been weary to the point of exhaustion, I sat myself down by a stone on the road.
Suddenly, my eye was taken by a beautiful wildflower  that was growing there at my feet.
Ah!
I was overwhelmed by my feelings.
My love for the Princess spread within me...
like the blooms on that exquiste flower.
And I had a moment of inspiration, It suddenly dawned on me, that what I  really wanted to bring the Princess...
and what she had truly wished for, was not some distant unobtainable treasure...
but this simple flower, which itself is a treasure of nature.
This flower has come to represent for me, the devotion with which I love the Princess Devotion...
Princess Kaguya!
In truth you are to me...
the only one whom I wish to dedicate my heart.
Could you please perhaps, accept this lovely flower as a token...
of the depth of my feelings?
Since I was a small boy, I have been fond of flowers and other plants.
I am also entranced by the nameless flowers that grow by roadsides or in meadows.
And in my heart...
I always wished that I could live, as do these flowers that bloom in the fields.
Princess, I want you to come with me, to that place.
Together we could leave this loud city and its formalities.
We could go to a rich green land where flowers bloom in perfusion.
Where birds sing and fish leap.
A place brimming with life.
Let us laugh and sleep and sing.
Let us follow our hearts.
Take pleasure in the tasks before us, with the blessings of the four seasons...
our needs will be supplied.
And we'll spin out a beautiful tale.
Please come with me to some place far away from here!
Where flowers bloom in perfusion, where fish leap and birds sing!
Come with me to that place!
Far away from here!
Please!
Excuse me!
What's going on here?
In a place far away from here, husband?
I would love to be taken there!
As I did when you said those very words, to me!
I'm sorry!
I beg for your forgivness!
Would she have been just like all the others?
Plucked from the field like a flower and then thrown away?
How many more princesses would be forced to shave their heads, and go into a nunery?
Get me down!
All that remained...
was Middle Counselor Isonokami, who was in search of the mysterious cowry shell amulet.
Counselor!
Is he alright?
The Counselor is dead?
Yes.
A great tragedy.
His back was broken... reaching for the nest.
Goodness, what's the matter?
This garden, it's... it's a fake!
Fake!
It's all fake!
And so am I!
So am I!
Everyone's miserable and it's all my fault.
It's not your fault.
It's not!
You mustn't blame yourself.
It is my fault.
All of it, is my fault!
Because I'm a fake!
I never wanted it to happen like this!
My love!
I didn't ask for this!
That may be true.
But it still doesn't make it your fault.
But in spite of her wishes, there was even more talk of the Princess...
and in time, His Majesty himself began to show interest.
She has led five of the highest nobles of the land,  around... by their nose!
Interesting!
Let's play her game.
Send word she is to appear before me!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Her father has most certainly raised her well... so when she becomes mine, give her father the rank of Court Official!
As your Majesty wishes.
Wonderful!
It's wonderful.
Princess!
Husband!
Calm down, please!
Princess!
Your Highness!
I have joyous news!
You've now come to the attention of His Majesty, who is summoning you to serve in his court!
What?
It's extraordinary!
You'll be one of His Majesty's wives.
Not only that, I will wear the hat of a court official!
Ah!
This is wonderful!
Listen to you!
You still don't comprehend how your daughter feels?
It is you, who doesn't understand!
All that we have done has been for the sake of this!
For a girl born in this land...
there is no greater happiness than joining His Majesty in holy wedlock!
None!
Now at last, after all this effort, Her Highness will finally be happy!
Father...
I'm sorry, but please refuse.
What?
I couldn't possibly be a court lady now.
What are you talking about?
You're refusing to serve at court?
Father, my answer is no!
But, you can't...
No one in this land is allowed to disobey an order from His Majesty!
In the slightest degree!
So quit thinking of just yourself, please!
Father...
If disobedience to His Majesty  is considered a crime punishable by death...
well then... the only choice is to kill me!
Princess!
Poppa, if your happiness depends on wearing the cap of a court official...
then I will go to His Majesty as you wish.
And after you have put on that cap as part of the court...
I will kill myself.
What?
She refused?
What is the meaning of this?
She has turned down an offer to live at the palace?
No woman has ever turned me down before!
Very interesting!
Now I truly want to meet her all the more!
Alright!
If she is determined to play that game,  I will grace her mansion with a surprise visit.
Yes, Your Majesty.
This way, your Majesty.
She plays the koto beautifully!
Her face is most angelic!
Now, let's waste no more time with games!
Why are you doing this?
Why, to make you happy of course!
My embrace pleases all women!
Let me go!
I will never be yours!
I'm afraid that's not an acceptable answer!
If I wish you to come, they you must obey!
Bring around the carriage quickly!
Where is she?
Where did she go?
I see that I acted in haste.
So please, show yourself, you have nothing to fear.
Please, Princess.
I will simply burn the sight of you into my eyes, and then withdraw.
How beautiful you are!
Remember your promise.
I will withdraw for today.
However I believe your ultimate happiness lies in you, becoming mine.
Such beauty I've never seen!
After His Majesty returned to his palace...
Princess Kaguya, would come out to the pavillion every night...
to gaze at the moon.
What's the matter, Princess?
Lately you never come in to see me.
You've left your spinning to sit, and you haven't tended to your plants for days.
You now spend most of your nights gazing at the moon.
I don't understand...
What is it?
What's happening with you?
Nothing has happened.
That's not true.
Now c'mon, tell me.
It's obvious from far away look in your eyes.
Don't worry, there's nothing wrong.
But... but...
Is it something you can't tell even me?
They're coming to take me back!
To the Moon!
The Moon?
Every night I've begged them to let me stay!
With you!
But it's no use!
They're coming for me on the 15th day!
Who's coming?
What's this about Princess?
I'm very confused.
Try to explain this in simple words so an old man like me will understand, Your Highness...
Oh!
You poor thing!
There is something very deep behind this, isn't there?
The truth is... the day you found me, I was was sent here from the Moon.
From the Moon?
The Moon put you in the bamboo?
Yes.
I understood it, on the day His Majesty was here.
And now on the 15th day, the people of the Moon will come for me...
and I must leave you both forever.
What?
I don't understand!
You planning to leave us?
Just... what is it we have done to deserve this?
I mean, from the start all we ever tried to do  was make sure you were always happy!
All this happiness that you wished for me has been very hard to bear.
Without realizing it...
I prayed for someone to save me.
And when His Majesty grabbed me, in panic my heart just screamed out...
I don't want to be here anymore!
You mean, you asked them to come here and take you back to the Moon?
That's just terrible!
What have you done?
I don't want to go back, Poppa.
I wanna stay here!
I won't let it happen!
We'll fight to keep you!
We'll figure something out, I just won't let them pass!
It's too late!
They are coming!
What have I been doing here in this land?
Throwing tantrums because I didn't want to  belong to anyone...
Ignoring what you want from me, and fooling myself with tiny fake meadows and mountains!
why I came here, and why it is, no matter what is happening...
in this strange land, that song has always been inside my heart.
* Birds, bugs, beasts * * Grass, flowers and trees * Yes, that's the song.
I was...
I was born to live here!
With the birds, bugs and beasts.
I don't want to leave!
And you won't!
I will never let you go!
From the day I found you in the bamboo and held you so gently in my arms...
I've just loved you as if you were my very own child!
And when I picked you up and cradled you, put you on your feet and changed clothes...
I was the happiest man on the face of the Earth, like I was in Heaven!
It's not too late to save you!
It's not!
You're here!
We still have you!
You're still here in my arms!
And these arms of mine, will drive them away!
I will not let them take you!
No matter how many of them come!
I'll fight them off!
Is everyone?!
Prepare to defend the princess!
Oh Poppa!
I'm sorry.
My Heavens!
What a lot of noise they're making!
How about a song to make us feel better?
* Go round, go round * * Waterwheel, go round * * Go round, and call Mr.
Sun * * Birds, bugs, beasts * * Grass, flowers and trees * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * Bring 'em all on * * Go round, go round * * Waterwheel go round * * Go round and call Mr.
Sun * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * Bring 'em all on * * Spring, summer, autumn, winter * * Bring 'em all on * * Go round, come round * * Distant time * * Come round, Oh distant time * * Come round, call back the heart * * Come round, call back the heart * * Birds, bugs, beasts * * Grass, flowers and trees * * Teach people how to feel * * If I hear that you pine for me * * I will want to return to you * * I will want to return to you *  I wasn't aware there was another verse.
I remember...
Long ago in the City of the Moon, a woman who had just returned from Earth, would sing this song.
When you put on the robe of the Moon, all memories of the Earth just disappear.
All grief and sadness are gone.
But when she sang that song, I saw tears fall from her eyes.
It was such a mystery to me.
I had to know what those feelings from Earth were?
That's why I broke the rules to come to this place.
I wanted to feel all the same things that she felt, and now...
I know exactly what she was feeling as she looked back at this land.
Tell me dear...
She wanted...
to come back here.
To feel all those wonderful, mysterious things again!
I know it!
If you are waiting for me, I will return to you...
come round and call back my heart.
I just... wanna go home!
Prepare a carriage quickly.
Don't bring the word to anyone.
Ginger flowers!
It's been a long time.
What's the matter?
Hungry again?
Mama!
Did anybody hear that?
Hear what?
I'll go look.
Sutemaru, it's you!
It's you!
Little Bamboo?
Is it okay if call you that?
We were just coming back here for the new trees.
And for some reason coming over the pass, I thought I heard your voice, singing.
I'm so happy to see you!
Yeah.
Tell me?
What are you doing here, dressed like that?
All this time I've wanted to come back to my real home.
Your real home?
Here?
Uh-hmm.
But weren't you happy in the capital?
Living in a mansion, eating fine food, wearing nice clothes...
All that time I was wishing I was here on the mountain, playing with everyone.
Well, everyone's gonna be here soon.
And with you, Sutemaru...
With you, Sutemaru, I know I would have been truly happy.
Happy, with me?
Now I realize that.
You're joking, right!
I don't think you'd feel that way.
You, living like us!
Sure I would!
I did live like you when we were kids!
In rags like these?
Half-starving, eating roots?
Sometimes stealing dinner because you hadn't eaten in days?
I saw that!
I also saw when they beat you up.
Oh that?
That was nothing.
It's nothing if you answer back!
Answer back by simply being alive!
I just know, I would have been happy.
Little Bamboo!
But it won't happen.
It's too late.
What do you mean?
Ah!
You are promised to His Majesty?  No!
I won't belong to anyone!
Let's run away!
It can't happen.
Why not?
We can leave right now!
Let's run.
Come with me, and we'll go!
I'll carry you on my back and run forever!
We'll go some place where nobody can ever find us!
I can't run away.
Not any more.
Of course you can, Little Bamboo!
I'll protect you!
I'll protect you from everyone!
But they're coming for me.
Who's coming for you?
I've been found.
So what?
Even if you have been found!
So what!
I don't care about that!
I wanna run away with you.
Please!
Sutemaru!
Yes!
I'll run, too!
As fast as I can!
Little Bamboo!
Sutemaru!
Oh Heaven, oh Earth!
Take me in!
Huh?
No!
Please let me stay, just a little longer!
To feel the joy and happiness of living on this Earth!
Please don't take me away!
It's alright Little Bamboo.
I'll hold you tight!
I won't ever let go!
Hold me tighter!
I don't wanna go!
Little Bamboo!
A dream?
It wasn't real?
Dada!
Hi...
And then at last, the 15th day of August came round.
Fire!
Princess!
Princess...
* Go round, go round * * Waterwheel go round * * Go round, and call Mr.
Sun * * Birds, bugs, beasts * * Grass, flowers and trees * * Flower, bear fruit * * bear fruit, and die * * Be born, grow up, and die * * Still the wind blows, and the rain falls * * The waterwheel goes round * My little girl!
My Princess!
Please!
No... no!
* Lifetimes come and go in turn * Princess!
Princess!
* Over and over a life revives * Princess!
Don't leave us!
Not yet!
Please, not yet.
Once I dawn this robe...
I will forget everything I know and love about this land.
So please just for a moment.
Princess!
Daughter!
Please!
Take us with you!
Forgive me, Momma and Poppa!
Please forgive me!
Now now, let us go.
This heavy heart will no longer trouble you in the City of the Moon...
And the memory of this impure Earth, will lift from your mind forever.
It's not impure!
There is grief and sorrow here...
There is also joy and happiness!
All who live on this earth, experience them in different shades.
Princess!
Voices: Chlo