Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network, Dentsu, Hakuhodo DYMP, Walt Disney Japan, Mitsubishi, Toho and KDDI present In this world, there's an invisible magic circle.
- So you did date him!
- What?
There's inside and outside.
Capture the movement.
- It's hard.
- Right?
- Let's see.
- Hey, no looking!
These people are inside.
And I'm outside.
But I don't really care.
How's it coming?
Um, I... kind of messed up.
Let me have a look.
Oh, no.
Are you okay?
Hey, hey---
I...
I hate myself.
Anna...
You're fine now.
Oh, I'm so glad.
Thank you, Doctor.
Anna, do you feel all right now?
I'm fine.
You looked like you were in agony.
Where was your inhaler?
I cost you money again.
Why do you say that?
Oh, Miyoko.
I brought Anna's bag.
Her notebook is inside.
Why, thank you.
We were just nearby.
If there's anything else...
Wait...
Has Anna been getting along with you?
She tells me nothing about school.
She's okay.
But she's very quiet.
Quiet?
More like...
Hey, don't.
We're just a bit loud.
Well, take care.
Ever the worrywart, your mother.
Mother. . .?
She's probably a hermit at school.
It's true that stress can trigger asthma attacks.
Meanwhile, my husband's off on a business trip.
Maybe he and I are partly to blame, too.
12 years old...
It's a difficult age.
Have you noticed anything about her?
She... always has an ordinary face.
Ordinary face?
I'm sorry.
Like she won't show her emotions...
She used to be more expressive.
But these days, I don't even know...
Maybe it's because we're not related by blood.
You may want to send her somewhere to get better.
7:03 Departure for KUSHIRO Say, Anna...
Do you remember Uncle and Aunt Oiwa?
The air is very clean where they live.
It'll help your condition to spend some time there.
I can't go with you, but they'll take care of you.
Be a good girl, eat well, and come back nice and happy.
She whines like a goat.
Oh, here she is.
Anna.
Remember us?
No, but Auntie told me all about you.
I'm Anna Sasaki.
I hope I'm not much trouble.
Thank you for having me.
Our pleasure.
Auntie?
She means Yoriko.
Get on in.
Sorry it's a bit of a clunker.
Sorry it's tight in here.
I don't mind at all.
This area's changed since I was last here.
All these new shops.
Where we're headed is a nice, relaxing place.
But since the highway was built, people stopped coming.
They still haven't fixed that pothole!
I hear you have asthma?
Uh,yes.
The wind here will fix you up in no time.
Nice place, huh?
Bet you'd like Auntie to see it, too.
What's that over there?
On the cliff.
Oh, that's a silo.
It's for storing feed for livestock.
Hasn't been used in decades, though.
Now the village kids use it for dares.
They say there are ghosts there.
Dear, please!
He loves stories like that.
Best to stay away from there.
Look, that's our house over there.
Here, mind taking this in?
What's this?
Why would you accept this?
It's too much for us to eat.
He's always accepting gifts without thinking...
Our kids are all grown up and moved out.
Make yourself at home.
Thank you.
Let's see, these go where...
Excuse me.
You must think it's an odd house.
No, it's a lovely home.
No need for flattery.
Your room's upstairs.
It was my daughter's room.
It'd be sad to clear everything, so I left it as it was.
I see.
She's a yoga teacher in Tokyo now.
I'm thinking of trying it myself.
Oh, and feel free to use the closet and shelves.
Oh, thank you.
“Write me how things are, whatever you please.
Yoriko” Postcards, how quaint!
You should write her.
Come here for a sec!
Corning!
He can be so pushy.
See you later.
Smells like a stranger's house.
Feels nice.
I've arrived safely.
It's quite nice here.
Mr. and Mrs.
Oiwa are both very kind.
To Yoriko Sasaki These are delicious.
Sorry, my hands are full.
Um, I'm going to the post office.
Sure, go on.
Won't you try this?
Later.
Okay, I'll save it for dessert.
By the way, there's a shortcut by the parking lot.
Oh, thank you.
SHORTCUT This is the shortcut?
Boys just drive me mad!
It's tough being class president.
Wait, I need to drop off a letter.
Hey, who's that?
Why is it...
That mansion feels familiar.
I wonder if anyone lives here.
Excuse me...
What a big house.
I guess there's no one here.
Oh, no...
Thank you.
He's a bear.
Or maybe a sea lion.
Sounds like an adventure!
Completely different in high tide, isn't it?
It's the power of the moon.
But imagine that, Toichi giving a girl a ride on his boat.
He's actually a good guy.
Just not much of a talker.
You should ask him for a ride again.
Ask him for a ride.
I Will.
But it's best you stay away from The Marsh House.
How come?
Ghosts.
Not again!
I'll get some wine.
Looked like no one lives there.
Not now, anyway.
Used to be a vacation home for some foreigners.
Then it changed hands a few times.
But it's been vacant for a while now.
I see...
Someone's there.
Have you finished them yet?
What Mrs.
Kadoya asked for.
Oh...
Almost done.
Hey, Anna.
Going out?
Yes.
Just finish them already...
I'm going to go sketch.
Sure, go on.
Thank you.
Yoriko was worried about her, but she looks fine to me.
As long as she's having fun and eating well.
That's for sure.
All the trash you pick up will be collected here.
Everyone listen!
Now begin!
Look, it's Toichi.
Toichi the mute!
Toichi who only talks once a decade!
Hey, I said we're not going there until later!
We're just checking it out!
See ya!
Perhaps we'll hear from you next time!
I'm going out.
Wait, Anna.
I have a little errand, so hold on.
Yes.
He should be delivering these himself.
“I'm allergic to that lady,” he says!
But Mrs.
Kadoya's been wanting to meet you.
Their daughter Nobuko is a year older than you.
Nobuko is at cram school today.
Oh, that's too bad.
This must be Anna.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, um...
Hello.
Ah, so you draw, I see?
Show me next time.
No, I'm not very good.
Oh, you should go to the Tanabata Festival with Nobuko tomorrow.
Great idea!
I should still have my daughter's yukata.
You can wear it to the festival.
But...
Yes.
I'll let Nobuko know.
Now come in.
Where'd I put it...
Uh, actually I...
Oh, you're going sketching.
Go ahead!
She'll look great!
Ready,and“.
- This one, too.
- Got it.
I won't look good in it.
None of her business.
He's not here.
- Bye.
- See you tomorrow.
The tide is out.
Again.
I hate festivals.
Hey, let's go.
Wait for me.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Here's some candy.
- Thanks.
I wish I was wearing a yukata, too.
At least you're comfortable.
Mom forces her tastes on me.
It's awful.
I think it looks cute.
What?
No way!
It's boring and tacky...
So Anna, where are you from?
From Sapporo.
Cool, I bet the city has great shopping.
Maybe lots of cute boys, too?
You be quiet.
Sure, sure.
Not much to choose from here in the boonies.
Why'd you come out here?
Well...
What's this?
Nobuko!
What is it?
He's always making the same mistakes.
I'll warn him next time.
There it is.
Will my wish come true?
Can I have a candle?
Here you go.
Write your wish on this.
My wish...
Ow!
Sorry about that.
Anna!
Hey, where were you?
I was looking for you.
Oh, your wish.
Let's see...
“I wish for a normal life everyday.” “Normal”?
Anna, what do you mean by normal?
Uh, well...
You see, urn...
Hey, your eye color!
What?
It's really pretty.
It's a bit blue, like a foreign...
Leave me alone!
You fat Pig!
Fat...
Uh...
I mean...
I see what you mean by normal.
But there's no use pretending to be normal.
After all, you look like just what you are.
Okay, now let's drop it.
You should join us next...
Anna!
Hey, watch it!
Like just what I am...
UQ/V, Stupid, moody, unpleasant...
That's why...
I hate myself.
That's why everyone...
We don't have long to live.
Typically, you're the ones who...
Still talking about that?
We already settled this matter.
We're not blaming you.
It's just that...
I've already told you.
It's not about money.
I feel bad for her, but...
It'll be best for her if you two...
I'd better get home.
Did someone row it here?
It's stuck!
Throw me the rope!
The rope?
Hurry!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh, urn...
Are you a real person?
Don't let anyone hear.
You look like the girl I saw in my dreams.
Dreams?
Thanks.
It's not a dream.
What's your name?
Anna.
I'm desperate to get to know you.
What about you?
Yes.
Have you seen me before?
Often.
I just got here.
How long have you been here?
I've been here for ages...
Look at this, the marsh at night.
How beautiful.
Say, let's go down for a closer look.
Madam.
I know.
By the way, where's that child?
Was she not in her room?
I need to get back.
Were they talking about you?
Yes.
Usually I'm in bed by this hour.
Come on, I'll row you back.
So it was your boat.
Yes, I left it for you on purpose.
But I thought you'd row a little better.
I know.
So did I.
You're my precious secret.
I haven't told anyone about you, and I won't.
If someone finds out, they'll only spoil it.
Please, promise me.
That we'll remain a secret.
Forever.
Yes.
It'll be our secret.
Forever.
It was awful.
She came home crying her eyes out!
Did Anna do something?
She called my daughter a fat pig!
Fat Pig?
And she pulled out a cutter, too.
The horror!
I doubt she'd...
No, you need to hear it from the girl herself.
Now bring her here.
Seems she's not home yet.
She's a delinquent, out and about this late!
You two are at fault, too!
Better keep an eye on her.
Take this.
It's dark.
No, thank you.
What if something happens to one of the kids?
So what if she's a bit late!
Don't get so riled up.
She is not a delinquent.
Ah, she's home.
Anna.
Aunt Oiwa...
Were you listening?
Don't you worry.
You two'll make up.
Now take a bath and have dinner.
Thank you.
Or is it dinner before the bath?
It hardly matters.
But “fat pig” is a bit harsh.
That's for sure.
It's not that funny.
Auntie, worrying like always.
Anna!
Watermelon!
Anna?
Two hours until high tide...
Hop in.
Time for a picnic.
I brought juice and cookies.
Picnic?
At this hour?
That's right.
Let's go across the marsh.
You're very good at rowing.
You need rowing lessons.
Come here.
It's easy.
Remember I said last night that you're my precious secret?
I remember.
And you're my secret.
I'm glad.
Hey!
Good, you're doing well.
But I don't even know your name yet.
I hadn't told you?
Marnie.
I thought you already knew.
That's dangerous.
Go ahead, just row.
There's so much I want to know about you.
But I want to find out slowly.
Slowly, by myself, as we go along.
Okay.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll ask each other three questions a night.
Great.
All right, I'll start.
Question one.
Why are you here in this village?
I have asthma.
The doctor said I should go somewhere with clean air for a while.
Even by skipping school.
Oh no, you're ill?
If there's no attack, I'm fine.
So I'm staying here with Auntie's relatives, the Oiwas.
Who's Auntie?
It's my turn to ask now.
Do you live in that mansion?
Ever since I was two.
With Nan and the maids.
It's juice.
Where are your parents?
They only come here sometimes.
They're busy with work.
I see.
Question two.
Who's Auntie?
My guardian.
But I was a worry to her, so she got rid of me for a while.
What do you mean?
I'll explain sometime.
It's my turn now.
Do you have siblings?
I'm an only child.
I see, you too...
How come?
Oh, it's nothing.
Just curious what it's like to have siblings.
I know, it'd be fun to imagine that.
All right, question three.
What's it like living at the Oiwas?
At the Oiwas?
Huh...
How strange...
I can't...
remember...
Marnie?
Marnie!
Anna!
There you are.
I wondered where you went.
Marnie?
I looked all over for you.
You just disappeared.
I didn't go anywhere.
I was just trying to answer your question.
Wait...
What was it?
It's okay, it doesn't matter.
I need to go soon.
Today is...
Oh, I know!
No no no, I really can't!
Parties aren't really my...
Don't worry.
I have a great idea.
It's true.
That's hard to believe.
Sorry, did you wait long?
I had trouble getting away.
Marnie.
What do you think?
It's pretty.
I borrowed Nan's shawl.
I'll be scolded again.
This won't work.
Don't worry, I spoke to Father.
Young lady.
I believe it is past your bedtime.
And who might this be?
She is wearing my shawl.
Upstairs!
Wait right there!
You must be up to no good again.
You go that way.
Marnie!
Why you little...
Open it!
Let's go.
If you keep this up, you'll grow up to be a lousy adult!
Everyone, we have a lovely flower girl here.
A guest of my daughter.
Ah, a flower girl.
- There's Marnie.
- She'll be pretty like her mother.
May I please have one of those flowers?
My mother.
Hello, dear little witch.
That woman there's the real witch.
I want only one, for good luck.
Will someone kindly pay for my flower?
If it is the witch's command...
Then I'll have one, too.
- Here.
- For superb luck.
Ah, it's begun.
I'm sorry!
Oh, she ran away.
Come take one for luck!
Young lady.
To your health.
Thank you.
Wine?
Awake now?
I...
Drunkard.
Who was that?
Which one?
The one dancing with you.
You mean Kazuhiko?
An old friend.
He's a good dancer.
So are you.
Now let's dance, you and I.
I can't dance.
Just follow my lead.
Look for me again.
And don't tell anyone.
Promise.
I know.
Hey, wait...
Is that...?
It's the girl with the Oiwas.
I see.
Hope you find the other shoe.
It must be somewhere.
I'll go look.
Used to always lose mine.
There's a bunch buried in the mud flats.
Don't compare her to you.
I should have my daughter's old shoes.
I'll get them out.
Thank you.
Marnie...
Wow.
Not only are they big, they're delicious, too.
You're good with the knife.
Auntie teaches me all the time.
You're so polite and well-behaved.
My daughter could learn from you.
Passing behind you.
I remember when you first came to Yoriko's place.
She was ecstatic.
She wanted to make up for the five years she didn't have with you.
So she taught you things, like knife skills.
But she worries too much.
Always calling me for help.
When I told her I was busy, she started pouting.
Oh, I shouldn't share this about your mother.
No, I understand.
You know, Yoriko sent us tons of photos of you.
I'll show you later.
Hey, look.
Found the wind chime I made on our honeymoon.
To survive the summer.
Your hair's getting long.
Shall I give you a haircut?
That would be a disaster.
Mar... nie...?
Look for me again.
How could I nearly forget about Marnie?
Marnie...
Marnie!
May I?
Sure.
I see you draw, too.
That girl looks like someone I knew.
She was a great girl.
Yes, she is.
But I haven't seen her in a week.
I wonder if she's upset that I forgot.
If she's a friend, talk to her and you'll be fine.
Say, will you take a look?
Sure.
Are the colors too messy?
No, it's wonderful.
I'm Hisako.
I'm in love with The Marsh House.
What about you?
I'm Anna.
I love it, too.
Better hurry and finish your drawing...
before the new folks move in.
The renovations are under way.
Thanks for your hard work.
Have some tea.
Oh, thank you.
Appreciate it.
Hey, let's take a break!
All right, coming.
Are you Marnie?
Come.
I hadn't seen the front before.
It's a lot cleaner now, but not done yet.
Hello.
Hey there.
Brought a friend, huh?
Choose your slippers.
A Quest?
Yeah, a secret one.
Secret?
Hey!
Sorry, make yourself at home.
Thank you.
Yes, it's a lovely place.
Yes, we're still in the middle of renovation.
This room...
Upstairs.
This hasn't been renovated yet.
Here, this is my room.
Really...
What do you think?
It's a cute room.
It used to be your room, right?
You're...
Marnie, right?
Me?
No, no!
But... then why have you been staring at my room?
Because“.
See, that's where I always see you.
I've seen you many times.
No, no.
I just love this mansion, that's all.
That can't be.
When I said Marnie earlier, you were surprised.
Rather, why do you know Marnie?
I found it behind the shelf.
A diary?
That's right.
Your diary.
Marnie!
I'll pour you some Queen Mary, your favorite.
I'll be back.
“Last night I went for a row in my nightie.” “The marsh and the moon were very pretty at night.” I shall do it again.
June 8th.
A party!
Father, Mother and many of their friends came.
It was such fun.
I went outside from the sunroom and danced with a flower girl.
But...
Nan locked me in my room because of last night.
So there won't be any midnight rows for a bit.
See, it's you, isn't it?
No.
Marnie is...
someone I made up.
An imaginary girl, only in my mind.
But this is Marnie's diary.
It's as if she really lived here.
So you're not Marnie?
No.
She's just imaginary?
That's right.
I thought you were Marnie, back for her diary...
I'm Anna.
I came from Sapporo to get better.
I'm Sayaka.
I'm from Tokyo.
But if she was imaginary, why is her name the same?
I don't know.
Marnie must be real.
I'm going to investigate.
Say, Marnie...
Who are you?
Is that me?
Marnie?
Marnie!
Wait, that one's not done yet...
Wow, you draw well.
Oh, thanks...
I've never had anyone draw me before.
How nice!
I missed you.
I kept calling you in my heart.
Me, too.
Let's go.
Come to my room.
Come to my room, Marnie.
I can't go far from the mansion.
Okay then, we'll go wherever you want.
You know a lot about mushrooms.
Father taught me when I was little.
I once brought home three bags full of mushrooms.
The look on Mother's face!
What's wrong?
So quiet all of a sudden.
You're very lucky.
I wish I was you.
Talk to me.
I'm...
a foster child.
My real parents died when I was little.
My grandmother, too.
I know they didn't die on purpose, but...
sometimes I feel like...
I can't forgive them...
for leaving me all alone.
I'm jealous of you.
You're lucky to be a foster child.
If you had no relatives, then the folks who took you in as a daughter must be truly kindhearted people.
Then I'll tell you a big secret.
It's about my foster parents.
They're good to me and they're kind.
I'm not their real child, yet they raised me, which I appreciate.
But you see, I saw it one day.
They're paid money for it.
Money?
I found a letter from the government.
It said they were increasing the subsidy for me.
I'm sure there's a reason...
I don't care!
They wouldn't get money if I were their real child.
They get paid because I'm not their real child.
Even worse... they hide it from me.
I see.
But that doesn't mean Auntie doesn't love you.
No!
Don't you see?
None of the other families receive money.
Just us!
She always looks worried that I might find out.
And I hate myself for thinking like this.
I... just can't... believe...
in anything anymore.
Anna, it's okay to cry.
Just know that I love you.
I love you more than any girl I've ever known.
Then you tell me your secret next.
It was long ago that I went mushrooming with Father.
Nowadays, I hardly see my parents.
Mother's usually travelling.
Because of Work, Father's home only twice a year.
Usually, Nan and the twin maids are the only ones home.
And me.
I slip out while they're gossiping.
And look how free I get to be!
It's lovely when my parents come home.
They host parties!
Like the other day.
With my amazing parents and many people there, it's delightful.
I get to wear new dresses and dance, too.
That's when I'm sure I'm the luckiest girl in the world.
I see.
Tell me, Anna.
Will you be my friend forever?
Yes.
I'm your friend forever.
Right?
Nan's always in a bad mood.
She yanks me by the arm, brushes my hair very hard...
No one thinks I'm being bullied.
But it really hurts.
Enough to cry.
The maids love to frighten me.
They threatened me all the time.
“Naughty kids get shut in the silo “where ghosts suck out their souls,” they said.
You mean, the silo on the hill?
Once, they actually took me there.
No!
They dragged me all the way to the silo.
I thought I'd die of fright.
Then suddenly, just as we got there, the sky went dark and the thunder came.
The maids were terrified, so we didn't go inside.
I can endure anything else.
Anything but the silo.
I never heard such a terrible thing!
I hope the maids and Nan get struck by lightning!
Hasn't anyone ever tried to frighten you?
Never.
Definitely not on purpose.
You're lucky.
I wish I was you.
Our castle...
Poor Marnie.
I love you the most, too.
More than anyone I've known.
Thank you.
Funny, it's like we traded places.
How true.
The tide's coming in.
Hey, let's go to the silo together.
The ghosts must be a lie.
Let's go make sure.
Tomorrow...
No, let's go right now.
I don't care who Marnie really is.
I just want to help her.
Are you okay, Marnie?
Yes, I'm sure I'll be all right if I'm with you...
Kazuhiko.
Anna!
Perfect timing!
I found it!
The rest of the diary.
Come to my place.
Marnie...
I'm sorry.
Another time.
What?
But it's a major discovery...
It's going to rain!
Who is it?
Is someone there?
Marnie!
So you did go ahead.
Don't scare me like that.
Marnie.
Are you okay?
Why did you...
Kazuhiko!
I'm frightened.
I heard somebody below.
I thought I'd die of fright.
Kazuhiko...
What're you saying?
I'm Anna.
Pull yourself together.
Anna...
Anna!
I don't want to be humiliated.
But I haven't the courage.
Oh, Anna...
You do have courage.
You came here.
Let's go home.
Wait!
It's just the wind.
Let's go.
We'll go home together.
Anna, come back here.
Anna!
We made it up.
I'm sure we can make it down.
I'll go first, so follow me.
No, don't leave me!
No!
Marnie!
Let's go over there.
I'm cold...
So cold...
Oh Anna, I'm scared...
I'm scared...
Don't worry, we'll be fine if we're together.
You did well, Marnie.
Are you okay?
Kazuhiko!
I thought you'd never come.
I...
Let's go home.
Marnie?
Marnie!
Marnie...
You left me behind!
Even you!
Kazuhiko...
Kazuhik0's all over this diary.
“Kazuhiko is trying to take me to the silo.” Silo...
Yes?
Mom cooked some corn.
Hurry or it'll be gone.
Wait!
Why go out on a night like this?
It's not safe.
My friend might be caught in the rain.
What if she gets pneumonia?
Is that...
Anna!
Are you okay?
So cruel...
Anna?
So cruel, Marnie...
She has a high fever!
I'll g0 get help.
Anna.
Anna?
Anna...
How's she doing?
Her fever's not coming down.
She did get a shot earlier.
I see.
So cruel...
Marnie, how could you?
I won't forgive you.
Leaving me behind without a word.
Anna!
My dear Anna!
Marnie!
How could you leave me behind?
Why did you betray me?
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to leave you all alone.
But...
But at that moment, you weren't there.
What do you mean?
Oh, Anna, I...
I can't stay here any longer.
I have to say goodbye to you.
So please, Anna, please say you forgive me!
Anna...
Of course, I forgive you!
I love you, Marnie!
And I won't forget you!
I'll never forget you!
Ever!
Anna.
Sayaka's here for you.
Thanks.
You could see her in your room.
No, it's nice outside.
The view here is beautiful.
I'd love to show you.
- Anna Sayaka.
Here, a get-well gift.
Thanks.
Also...
This is what made me think you might be at the silo.
What is it?
The rest of the diary you promised to read.
I'm having trouble remembering.
I impressed myself.
I found a clue in this painting that was behind the cupboard.
Maybe I'm psychic.
Turn it over.
Hisako!
Please, will you tell us about Marnie?
But...
it's a rather sad story.
I'm ready for it.
It was a long time ago.
I used to play at The Marsh House often.
Marnie and I were very little.
It's a bear!
Let me see.
This is Daddy.
Isn't he dashing?
Marnie loved to boast about her glamorous parents and their extravagant parties.
But the truth is, she was being neglected.
Goodbye, Marnie.
That poor child...
No, don't leave me, Mommy!
Don't go!
Seems even the maids were bullying her.
That's awful!
Later, Marnie moved to Sapporo and married Kazuhiko, her childhood friend.
With her family torn apart and feeling lost, he was there to support her.
I'm glad.
So Kazuhiko was a good man.
Two years later, Emily was born.
At last in the warm household she'd always wanted, Marnie was happy.
I didn't see Marnie for many years after that.
The next time was...
a few years after Kazuhiko had died of an illness.
By then, Marnie was in a sanatorium due to the shock of his death.
Sanatorium?
A place where you go to get better.
What happened to Emily?
Marnie's parents had died, leaving no one to look after her.
So for elementary school, she was sent to a boarding school.
By the time she returned at age 73, she had become a different person.
Emily!
She was willful and independent.
She knew Marnie was ill, but still resented her for sending her away.
You think that makes you more motherly?
I want you to live the way you wish, but...
you need to...
They never did make up after that.
As your mother...
I've never thought of you as a mother.
Emily ran away and soon g0! married.
She was expecting, you see.
But...
One day, Emily and her husband died in a car accident.
I heard Marnie took their child in.
She was determined to never let this child be lonely.
But...
she never got over losing Emily.
She became very ill, and died the next year.
That was about ten years ago.
I'm sorry, it's a sad story.
No, thank you very much.
Marnie adored that mansion.
She loved seeing the marsh from her window.
She said it felt like the birds spoke to her.
She had a lonely life, but she lived it fully.
Always with a smile, determined to be happy.
So you've met Marnie, too.
Wish we could've played more, Anna.
The plan was always just for the summer.
Will you come again next summer?
I'm sure I will.
I'll write you.
I'll write you, too.
I put the diary and painting back where I found them.
Good, it's for the best.
I haven't told my family.
Let's keep it our secret.
How funny...
Marnie brought us together.
That's true.
Marnie...
The girl trapped behind the blue window...
That was long ago.
Exactly, he does it to save her life.
I love that part.
Ah, now I want to read it all over again.
I'll loan you Volume 2.
Anna!
Auntie!
Anna...
Hey, be careful!
Sorry, sorry.
Auntie's here.
Ah, Yoriko, you're here.
Thank you for everything.
She's doing well, and even made a friend.
How can I ever repay you?
Oh, no.
We didn't do anything at all.
Anna is a good girl.
It was like having our own daughter back.
She's welcome anytime.
Thank you.
Let's talk inside.
I'm impressed you didn't call us this time.
I'm all packed.
Anna.
Yes?
There's something I need to tell you.
We receive monthly subsidies to cover your expenses.
We receive money.
I've long hesitated to tell you, but...
- It's okay.
- But believe me...
Whether or not we receive money, it doesn't change our love for you.
I already knew.
I'm happy you told me about it.
Anna!
I've been looking at the photos you sent.
Photos?
Oh, while you were away I was looking at old albums and found this picture.
Do you remember?
It's that mansion.
When you first came, you wouldn't let it go.
I was told at the orphanage it belonged to your grandmother.
My beloved home - Marnie Marnie!
So that's who she was.
Anna.
And so I was in the silo all night.
I was very frightened.
That's when your grandpa came.
He encouraged me, saying I did well.
I've overcome many frightening things.
And so will you, Anna.
After all, you're my one and only grandchild.
Grandma...
Excuse me.
Anna.
I'm sorry for what I said.
Don't skip trash pickup next year.
A friend?
Maybe.
Hisako!
Anna.
I'm going home to Sapporo now.
Is that right?
But your face tells me something good happened.
Yes, I'm really happy now.
Good.
Um, this is my mother.
Thank you for being kind to Anna.
Oh no, it was my pleasure.
Let's draw together again.
Yes.
I'll write you.
I have some amazing news.
Goodbye.
Thank you very much.
Amazing news?
Yeah, I'll tell you later.
Oh, why not now?
I promise I'll tell you.
Toichi!
Sayaka!
Goodbye!
Voices Sara Takatsuki Kasumi Arimura Susumu Terajima Toshie Negishi Ryoko Moriyama Kazuko Yoshiyuki Nanako Matsushima Hitomi Kuroki Executive Producer Toshio Suzuki Based on the novel “When Marnie Was There” by Joan G.
Robinson Screenplay by Keiko Niwa, Masashi Ando and Hiromasa Yonebayashi Music Takatsugu Muramatsu Theme Song Priscilla Ahn Supervising Animator Masashi Ando Production Designer Yohei Taneda English Subtitles by Taro Goto Subtitle Production by Aura Production Koji Hoshino Studio Ghibli Producer YoshiakiNishimura Directed by Hiromasa Yonebayashi The End