Raccoon, Mr.
Raccoon, Come on out and play Some other time I'm having dinner now What are you eating?
Pickled plums and radish Can you give me some?
Don '2' be such a greedy bum Gel' your own!
POM POKO We used to live near a farmhouse.
But not to steal their food.
In the farms and fields...
there are always frogs, grasshoppers, mice, moles...
persimmons and mulberries.
Much more food than in the mountains.
Then suddenly last spring the humans went away.
They didn't come back, so we decided to move in.
That was such a wonderful year.
A house with a garden, it was like a dream!
But then...
We usually don't have strict rules about territory.
But this was different.
Wherever we went for food, we came up against others.
There were fights and our territory was invaded.
And finally...
Pom Poke Year 31, autumn.
In the clear-cut forest of Taka near Suzu...
the raccoons of the Tama Hills faced their final battle.
Gonta the Brave led the Taka forces.
Seizaemon the Elder led the raccoons from Suzu.
It's a little-known fact, but when humans aren't around...
raccoons stand and walk on two legs, just like this.
The battle was fierce but it didn't last long.
Fight, fight!
Taka!
Suzu!
Taka win!
Suzu win!
Both of you lose.
Let the losers be killed.
Taka's forest is gone today.
Suzu's will be gone tomorrow.
Too many raccoons, no place to live.
Too many raccoons, where will they go?
There's no place to go.
You're all finished.
Taka win!
Suzu win!
Both of you lose.
Let the losers be killed.
Let the losers die for the sake of all.
It will be a blessing!
The fewer the better.
You survivors, take care!
Have no more babies.
Or there won't be enough forest to hold them.
Urged on by Granny Oroku...
the raccoons looked and were stunned by what they saw.
The hills had vanished...
and the earth had been stripped bare.
The land was empty and cold.
It's insane!
This is no time for fighting!
In the 1960s, Japan's economy was booming.
Demand for housing near Tokyo skyrocketed.
Construction spread to the hills and farmland surrounding the city.
The biggest housing development was called Tama New Town.
30,000 acres would be developed for 300,000 people.
Mountains were deforested, stripped and leveled.
Farms were bulldozed, old houses were demolished.
The Tama Hills became a residential development.
The forested hills became a sprawling suburban community.
It was the largest urban development project ever.
Those humans are truly amazing.
I always believed they were animals just like us.
But now I think humans must be as powerful as gods.
There was no time to lose.
The raccoons gathered from all over the Tama Hills...
for a midnight meeting in the abandoned temple of Manpukuji.
Tsurukame the priest was 105.
He was the chairman of the meeting.
Given this dire situation...
we must give up our nocturnal habits...
and be ready for action during the daytime.
Their plan was to try to stop the development.
Then it's unanimous!
The meeting broke up at once.
All decisions would be made by the council of elders.
They announced a 5-year plan to study the humans...
and revive the ancient art of transformation.
Messengers would be sent to far-off Shikoku and Sade...
to seek help from famous Transformation Masters.
But the journeys would be perilous.
Nobody volunteered to go.
They all pretended to be asleep.
I suppose we'll just have to leave it to the younger raccoons.
Agreed!
Getting down to business...
they proceeded to research McDonald's hamburgers.
The meeting ended with everyone well satisfied.
NO DUMPING They decided that an old TV would be the best way...
to collect in-depth information on humans.
Good evening.
Good evening!
The TV aroused great interest.
Raccoons started to hang out at headquarters...
just to watch the TV all day.
Transformation requires extreme physical and mental discipline.
Truly, shape-shifting is the greatest miracle.
Less-skilled animals like chameleons use mimicry.
Only raccoons, foxes and a few cats can transform themselves.
Gonta!
See how you did that?
You already have the gift of transformation.
It's quite easy once you get the hang of it.
At least in theory.
I'll give you a demonstration.
Don't you need a big leaf?
That's only for beginners.
It's been a while.
With Granny Oroku as their teacher...
transformation training proceeded rapidly.
All the youngsters were eager to practice their new skill.
Excellent, Shokichi!
I've always been interested in humans.
We're not supposed to get too close to them...
but my dear departed father never stopped me.
Detailed knowledge of humans is the key to transformation.
Dad knew it would be useful for my future.
Of course, some students lagged behind.
In fact, many were just hopeless.
The key to transformation is extreme discipline of mind and body.
Foxes work hard at it, but raccoons are easily distracted.
Some of them played hooky.
Hey!
Ponkichi!
Ready, set, let's all transform!
My friend Ponkichi never got the hang of transformation.
He just wanted to be an ordinary raccoon.
A human looked up at the evening sky...
and saw the moon rising over the mountains.
Then a tree branch blocked the moon.
The human said, “That's strange.
There was no branch before.” The branch disappeared and stuck out on the other side.
The human saw this and said...
“Wait!
There were branches on both sides.” So a branch stuck out on the other side too.
Then boom, both branches fell.
What really fell?
A raccoon!
Yes!
And why did he fall?
Gonta?
Because he was stupid.
I would never fall.
Good.
That's the spirit.
Sasuke, why did he fall?
He lost hold of the tree.
Very good.
And what does this teach us?
Shokichi?
That you shouldn't believe everything humans say.
Right.
We raccoons are too trusting.
It's easy for humans to fool us.
Then we get into trouble.
Does everyone understand?
Yes, Tsurukame.
Now, what if I start singing?
Raccoon, raccoon Come on out and play.
We're in the middle of a lesson!
See?
You fell for it.
That's what I was afraid of.
The raccoons were still hard at work when spring arrived.
Flowers were blooming.
It was the season for love.
Following Granny Oroku's warning...
many of the raccoons abstained from mating...
to keep the population under control.
Especially the females.
They controlled their maternal instincts with firm willpower...
rejecting the lovesick advances of the males.
Meanwhile, work continued on the massive development.
More forest disappeared, more land was cleared for housing.
The raccoons were sad and angry.
They called the site “the bald hills”.
Mr.
Mailman, you dropped something.
The females, who were just as independent as the males...
were also just as skilled at transformation.
When males transformed into girls, it sometimes looked unnatural...
so the females coached them.
Some females also transformed into men.
Class is over, but I want the boys to stay here.
One day Tsurukame gave the males a special lecture.
Boys, there's something special about the mat you're sitting on.
I won't beat around the bush.
It's my testicles!
150 square feet.
Here's your proof.
After basic training, the students went into the field.
It's like learning to drive.
You need someone experienced to come with you...
and back you up if you get in a tight spot.
The art of transformation requires a great deal of energy...
especially when transforming into humans.
The dark circles around raccoons' eyes...
are from sheer fatigue.
Even experienced transformers...
...need an emergency energy boost every now and then.
Too much fatigue might mean changing back into a raccoon.
Recently, fast-acting energy drinks have become very popular.
To graduate from field training...
each student had to work as a human and earn 1,000 yen.
I'm beat!
Some raccoons pretended to be one worker.
Others posed as monks begging for alms.
A few females worked in bars to earn money for energy drinks.
One even tried his luck at pachinko.
One broke into a temple donation box.
But all he got was a few coins.
Granny Oroku saw right through him.
I told you, never turn leaves into money!
An urgent report interrupted Gonta's training at headquarters.
He rushed to the Taka Forest and was shocked by what he saw.
Developers had turned his homeland into bald hills.
Furious, he rushed back to headquarters.
He called a meeting of the council...
and demanded total war against the humans.
I'm against it.
Why?
It's too soon.
You need more experience.
We finished our training.
We can do great things.
What do you think, Granny?
Are they up to it?
They certainly have the basic skills.
But...?
They lack experience.
The humans might see through them.
We need to know, Gonta.
Why are you proposing this?
Is it because of what happened to your home forest?
Is that it?
No, I swear.
It's for the happiness of all the raccoons in Tama.
What a lot of nonsense.
It was you who tried to take over Suzu forest.
Shut up!
Even if you won't join me...
the Taka raccoons will fight.
If Gonta's going, then I'm going too.
You Will, Shokichi?
Thanks!
All right men, there's no turning back now!
Wait!
You can't stop us, Granny.
I'd better teach you a special skill for emergencies.
If the humans see through you, this disguise will last for five days.
Well, what is it?
A dead fox.
Pom Poke '(ear 32, summer.
Gonta and a band of brave followers...
set out to test their new transformation skills...
in a surprise attack on the humans.
Their counterattack had finally started.
Here they come!
This way!
We did it!
This afternoon, at the Tama New Town site...
five more workers were killed or injured...
in a landslide and accident involving a trailer.
One building under construction was completely destroyed.
Heavy rains and poor visibility were blamed for the accident.
Because so many accidents have occurred simultaneously...
questions are being asked about the project's overall management.
Local residents are concerned...
and some are demanding that the development be cancelled.
Hold on there!
The humans who died were victims of this war.
First we should pay our respects to the memories of those who died.
Tsurukame is right.
Let's have a minute of silence for the victims.
Hurray!
Minute of silence!
Let us remember.
- We won!
We won!
- Let's celebrate!
A big party!
Gonta's back!
The heroes have returned.
You did great, Shokichi.
You young people give us hope for the future.
And we're just getting started.
Listen up!
Everyone must join the fight.
We'll kill them!
Destroy them!
Run them out of these hills forever!
Say something, Shokichi.
Then we'll plant lots of our favorite persimmon trees.
Hurry, persimmon seed, sprout' a free If you don't, I'll chop you up Out with the humans!
Kill them!
Destroy them!
All right, that's enough war talk.
Let's just celebrate, shall we?
I'm a little worried about something.
What?
Do we have to drive out every human?
Of course!
Can't we let a few stay?
Like before?
No!
They're our sworn enemies!
They're monsters!
We have to exterminate them!
Are you sure?
Of course, I hate them too.
Some of them are all right.
No, I hate them all!
But...
But what?
If they all go away, we'll never eat tempura again.
Or sardines...
Or corn...
Hamburgers!
Donuts!
Fried chicken!
Potato chips!
Turkey!
I can almost taste them!
Well Gonta, what if we let a few humans stay?
It can't be helped.
Let's hear it for Gonta and his men!
In the garden of Manpukuji Temple The moon shines bright.
Everyone come out.
Come out.
Hurry, hurry, all our friends.
Tsurukame, come out!
Everybody look at Granny!
You gotta get a look!
Everyone's gotta get a look!
The government has declared that the needs of a growing population...
are too urgent to even consider cancelling the New Town project.
- Hey!
- What did he say?
It was an unfortunate accident.
Brave Gonta suffered compound fractures and ruptured organs.
He would be sidelined for at least a year.
The news report cast a pall of gloom over the celebrations.
But the humans' fear of divine retribution...
gave the raccoons a new idea.
Maybe it was a mistake to tear down those shrines.
What do you mean?
Maybe the guardian spirits are punishing us with these accidents.
I hear you had to relocate many of the shrine statues.
Of course we made offerings to the spirits...
...and held purification rites first.
What do you think, Professor?
Each locality has its own guardian gods and spirits.
Altering the landscape without their permission...
will naturally invite their anger.
I think there is a lo! more bad luck f0 come.
I have an idea.
The raccoons promptly put Shokichi's idea to the test.
When one of the land owners checked his property before selling...
he found more guardian statues than he was expecting.
He decided it might be better to delay the contract.
The purification rite at a shrine that was about to be relocated...
was interrupted by a raccoon posing as the shrine guardian.
He appeared on the roof.
Terrified by the fox's wailing, the humans panicked...
and the relocation was cancelled.
Instead, the residents requested that the new road be diverted.
Now the raccoons were fired up.
They competed with each other to use their transformation skills...
in this new guerrilla war.
Come this way.
Leave our forest alone.
Take it with you.
Let's pack the leftovers.
Wait!
Leave the food.
ls something wrong, miss?
What's the matter?
I have no face.
A goblin!
L...I just saw...
A murder?
No.
Not a murder?
Oh, well.
It was a woman.
A vampire?
No, she was...
Did she look something like this?
Did she...
look something like this?
It was such fun scaring the humans...
that they decided to have another party.
But the hero of the first battles was disappointed that his injuries...
were not healing quickly.
His wife nursed him well, but he was not ready to fight.
He thought the others were losing their aggressive spirit.
Last night's news was great! “Goblins appear in New Town.” That cop was on the show.
Everyone laughed at him.
He lost his temper.
I laughed myself sick.
Idiots!
Do you think this will stop the project?
If you're going to transform, do what I did.
Kill the humans!
Just as Gonta predicted, the construction didn't stop.
Rivers were lined with concrete.
Roads were cut through the bald hills.
Housing construction was already under way.
However, the mysterious incidents received so much media coverage...
that the New Town goblins were famous all over the country.
The raccoons' spirits rose higher and higher.
Pom Poke Year 32, autumn.
The raccoons competed for the honor...
of going in search of the Transformation Masters.
Tamasaburo was chosen to journey to Shikoku.
Bunta would go to Sado.
At the next full moon...
the two young raccoons set off on their long journeys...
after a tearful farewell.
The others settled down to wait for the Masters...
while they continued to haunt New Town.
Even if it didn't stop the development...
it was their favorite sport.
Daddy!
Can we really chase the humans away with these cheap tricks?
What if we slip up and they see through us?
Should we fight like Gonta says?
No, killing one or two humans won't make any difference.
To go on or not to go on.
That is the question.
KW o'?
What are you doing?
Does your neck hurt?
I was posing.
I thought you might say I was pretty.
Oh, sorry.
Now my neck really does hurt.
You looked pretty.
Too late.
But I mean it.
It's okay.
I'm out of practice anyway.
Everyone likes that song.
I guess I do too.
How about “Where Are You From?” Nobody sings that now.
That song...
A raccoon was on Senba Mountain Along came a hunter..
A hunter killed my grandpa.
Sorry, I didn't know.
It's okay.
But they didn't eat him, like in the song.
They sold his pelt for a lot of money.
Your pelt's pretty too.
I was hoping you'd say that.
What about that song?
My dad used to sing it.
He was a good ball bouncer too.
He must have been a character.
And when he finished singing, he would always start preaching.
What did he say?
“Listen well, children.” “Like the song says...” “they kill us, cook us and eat us.” “Humans are cruel by nature.
That's what the song says.” Hey, let's play ball.
Are you good?
Sure am.
Now it's my turn.
Where are you from?
From Higo...
Where's Higo?
From Kumamoto...
Where's Kumamoto?
From Senba...
Where the mountains are full of raccoons.
When are you going out on that raid you talked about?
I'm getting tired of that stuff.
But I liked your idea.
Really?
Why don't we do it tonight?
Together?
Are you afraid?
No, it's not that, but...
Then let's do it.
It'll go just fine.
Okay, you're on.
With you, I'm sure it'll go great.
I'm so happy!
My, what adorable little children.
We just got back from the stars, but now our house is gone.
The stars?
From the red-eyed Scorpion, we crossed over the Eagle's wings.
We looped the coiled Snake, to the top of the Bear Cub's brow.
We scatter dew and frost as we travel through the stars.
Who are you two, anyway?
We're lost and we're cold!
Mister, do you know the way home?
We don't know what you're talking about.
We don't know.
Now go away!
Better call the cops.
They're not kids.
They're gremlins!
Forgive us!
Forgive us, little gremlins.
Wait a minute.
We can work this out.
Come on, I'll raise your pay.
I'm going home.
I can't take it any more.
This place gives me the creeps.
Come on, don't say that.
I heard Tokyo was a scary place...
but this is too much.
You better forget this whole project.
Something doesn't want it to happen.
The raccoons cheered.
That night's party was especially grand.
The heroes of the evening were Kiyo and Shokichi.
The construction site was quiet and deserted.
But next morning...
More humans showed up to continue the work.
Despite the raccoons' hard work...
there seemed to be an unlimited supply of humans.
Some say these strange events are the work of foxes or raccoons.
If that were true, all we'd need to do is kill a few animals.
This made the raccoons at headquarters very nervous.
But it's just like the old folktales.
No wonder rumors are spreading.
Whoever is spreading them must want the project to fail.
Rumors?
We saw it with our own eyes!
Very well.
We'll just have to get rid of these dangerous animals.
Just let us know when you catch them.
That is, if you can prove they did it.
It was starting to look as if transformation wouldn't be enough.
Long ago, there was a golden age of raccoons.
The art of metamorphosis was at its peak.
Raccoons were a favorite subject for artists and writers.
But we abused our powers.
The humans turned against us.
As Japan modernized, we were trapped by the thousands.
Our pelts became brushes and fur collars.
This was their revenge, but we brought it on ourselves.
You must learn from this terrible experience.
Remember that we have been able to live in peace...
only because we stopped using our powers recklessly.
Transformation is a great gift.
But if used carelessly...
it will only rekindle the humans' desire for revenge.
I urge you all to be careful.
The young transforming raccoons were not sure what to do next.
But now it was autumn, the best season for raccoons.
It was time to store up fat for the winter...
and grow their thick winter coats.
They forgot about transforming and stuck to the job of getting food.
One day, an exhausted raccoon arrived at the construction site.
It's okay, we're raccoons.
Thank you.
You look exhausted.
Where did you come from?
From Fujino Mountain.
Is that in Shikoku or Sado?
It's in Kanagawa, just beyond those mountains.
Kanagawa?
You mean you're not from Shikoku?
I'm sorry, I seem to have disappointed you somehow.
It's just that we've been waiting for some visitors.
Anyway, what is it that brought you here?
I was looking for the source of the landfill...
they're dumping on our mountain.
According to this raccoon named Hayashi...
dirt and construction waste was being dumped...
in Fujino's forest.
The dumping was hurting the environment...
and making survival hard for raccoons and other animals.
To find the source of this trouble...
Hayashi hitched a ride on one of the dump trucks.
But his transforming skills were rusty, and he fell asleep.
Before he arrived in Tama, he changed back into a raccoon.
It's not just Fujino, it's other places too.
They keep building dump sites and golf courses.
They destroy our hills and cause us trouble.
Then they dump the waste in Fujino, and cause you trouble.
How far will this insanity go?
When I arrived here I couldn't believe it.
I thought for sure the waste was coming from the big city.
But this isn't the city!
They level one mountain and dump it on another.
What in the world for?
I don't understand it one bit.
Then if we stop the development...
the Fujino raccoons will be better off too.
I'm so grateful to hear you say that!
Please use all your power...
to help save our homeland as well as your own.
We'd like to, but unfortunately it's easier said than done.
What happened to Bunta and Tamasaburo, anyway?
When in the world are they coming back?
There was still no sign of the Transformation Masters.
Now it was winter.
During the raccoons' winter rest...
the humans forgot the “New Town Goblins”...
and people's attention shifted elsewhere.
The media was busy with the private lives of movie stars...
and political corruption scandals.
In the garden of Manpukuji Temple.
Raining, raining cotton candy, ice cream, snow cones!
All our friends, Pom Poko, Pom!
Pom Poke '(ear 33.
New Year's morning brought a fresh blanket of snow.
Most of the construction workers had gone home for the holidays...
and were enjoying long-awaited family reunions.
Our golden bells s Wing and s wing, though there '.s not a breath of Wind.
Baby raccoon sees our swinging balls and swings his too.
We really saw them.
A bunch of raccoons did it.
It's the truth!
Three workers at the Tama New Town construction site...
were arrested for destroying a bulldozer.
They maintain that raccoons did it.
Investigations are under way, but the snow has already melted.
Look what you've done now, Shokichi.
It's no big deal.
The whole thing's pointless.
He was just trying to help the others participate.
What do you think, Tsurukame?
I think it Will be okay.
Tsurukame was right.
The workers were released for lack of evidence.
The raccoons weren't blamed.
The case remained a mystery.
Spring came at last.
Once again, the season for love.
The raccoons had been chaste for over a year.
Now they couldn't resist.
Courtship rivalries and sweet nothings filled the air.
Even the sky was rose-colored.
Wait up, Hanako!
Hanako, wait!
You can't catch me!
Everyone has spring fever.
We're just like trees and flowers.
When spring comes, the sun shines.
Our flowers blossom...
and we bear fruit.
But we must obey Granny's orders.
Until our battle is won, we will be chaste.
Shokichi, you really are a wonderful raccoon.
I'm so glad.
Our love is forever.
Shokichi!
That was their big mistake.
Their love grew passionate.
And sure enough, they ended up like the others.
That spring, Shokichi and Kiyo had four baby raccoons.
The previous autumn, Tamasaburo had finally reached Shikoku.
He went to Kincho Shrine, home of the Masters...
to explain the problem and appeal for their help.
But then he fell ill.
Koharu, the Master's daughter, cared for him...
and he recovered miraculously.
That spring the two fell in love and had three babies.
In the shrine, the Masters of Shikoku debated endlessly.
They agreed that it was important for all of Japan...
to stop the New Town project.
They had to act quickly.
But who would go, and who would stay to guard the shrine?
Hundreds of questions were raised and discussed from every angle...
but no conclusions were reached.
Another summit meeting.
They never seem to end.
And on such a lovely day.
The year is half gone already.
When will they reach a decision?
I never want them to decide!
When I think of you leaving us to go back to Tama...
I feel so lonely that I'm sure my heart will break.
Koharu, I don't want this happiness to end either.
Then why don't you stay?
I'm going to ask Father.
I want you to stay here and become his successor.
While Tamasaburo was absorbed in the trials of youth...
Bunta, who had journeyed to Sado, roamed the fields and mountains...
searching for a Master called Danzaburo.
He searched high and low...
but no one he met had heard of the master.
From summer to autumn, the raccoons faced a serious dilemma.
Not only was their forest disappearing...
but the population multiplied with a spring baby boom.
Bad weather caused an extreme shortage of food.
Persimmons, nuts and other autumn fruits were scarce.
Transforming raccoons managed to get food from the humans...
but it wasn't enough to feed all the babies.
Even the non-transforming raccoons were forced...
to scavenge food from the humans.
Some of the careless ones were hit by cars or caught in traps.
Many lives were lost.
I've had enough!
It's time to confront the humans.
Right, Shokichi?
Are you sure you're all right, Gonta?
Of course!
Watch this!
This calls for a celebration!
When's the party?
Granny, this is no time for a party.
I think we should wait until the Masters get here.
You too, Shokichi?
I'm sick of you wimps.
We mustn't underestimate the humans.
If we attack now, we're sure to lose.
We've already waited too long!
Hold on.
Let's hear Shokichi's opinion.
Until the Masters arrive, I have three proposals.
First, equal distribution of food to raccoons who can't transform.
We should make it a system.
Second, a traffic safety training program.
Third, a rescue squad for anyone who gets caught in a trap.
Shokichi, you sound just like a human.
No, I'm a full-blooded raccoon.
Okay, we'll worry about details later.
For now, let's see who agrees.
Hands up!
Agreed!
What is this, Gonta?
Shut up!
It's a coup.
Anyone who stands in our way will be killed by my guards.
Those are dangerous words, Gonta.
That's “Gonta, Sir!” Hear me out!
The humans are strong indeed.
But not invincible.
We can kill them!
As the saying goes, “A cornered mouse will bite the cat.” A mouse?
How?
It's silly.
We'll stake everything on victory.
Right.
If it fears nothing, even a mouse can win.
We're not mice.
Biting a cat won't help us.
You know, a mouse would taste good right about now.
Mouse tempura is the best.
No, fried mouse nuggets are tops.
I like 'em breaded and deep fried.
Those crispy fried tails!
What are you talking about?
All I can say is...
Mouse tempura is my favorite.
Listen, Gonta.
As you see, we're not ready.
We'd better just wait for the Masters from Shikoku.
I'm sorry.
Just be careful not to have any more babies.
But I guess that's too much to expect from us raccoons.
No!
Instead of fewer raccoons, we need fewer humans!
All the places they've infested used to be our homes.
They're intruders!
Drive them out.
Kill them!
Drive them out!
Meanwhile...
Hey, Taxi!
I'll tell them we're here.
Tamasaburo!
I've brought the Masters from Shikoku.
Well done, Tamasaburo!
Friends!
On the way here, we saw your devastated mountains.
You have our deepest sympathy.
We would like to hold a general meeting tonight.
Pom Poke Year 33, autumn.
That evening, the raccoons assembled to listen to the Masters.
There's a good moon out tonight.
My name is Hage of Yashima.
Soon I will celebrate my 999th birthday.
Why is Tama being developed but Shikoku is not?
It is because we have protected our homeland vigilantly.
In Shikoku, the humans know well that if they anger us raccoons...
great misfortune will befall them.
The humans worship me and my distinguished companions...
at every temple and shrine in Shikoku.
They bow down before us.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am the Supreme Leader of Shikoku.
My name is lnugami Gyobu.
I am Kincho VI, lord of Kincho Shrine.
We shall drive out the humans...
by uniting our powers for a goblin attack.
This battle will require us...
to merge our spirits into one powerful force.
We three may not even survive this battle.
However, if you complete this operation flawlessly...
you will regain the respect the humans once had for you.
We must be fearless.
If we focus our combined strength...
we can stop this insane development.
Stop it in its tracks!
We have a full arsenal of tricks.
We have built a great boat.
An unsinkable boat!
A boat that will carry us far.
Board our boat and find peace of mind.
What a beautiful summer moon.
We like full moons.
Let us pray to this moon for success.
Shall we?
The raccoons began intense training for Operation Goblin.
Congratulations on your 999th birthday!
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Master, please perform that scene from the Battle of Yashima!
Of course, why not.
The time is ripe.
Pom Poke Year 33.
Year's end.
Operation Goblin was about to begin.
Slightly cloudy, no wind.
Cool but not cold, humidity 65%.
A perfect day for goblins.
From ancient times, raccoons have been skilled at transformation.
But this time was different.
Not only their energy...
but the energy of the cosmos itself had to be harnessed...
to guarantee the success of Operation Goblin.
Accumulating and channeling that energy was vital.
Under the direction of the Three Masters...
the raccoons generated an indescribable amount of power.
Males, females, skilled and unskilled alike...
all contributed their energy.
That evening, the raccoons united...
to use their full strength as it had never been seen before.
Hey look!
What's that?
Let the trees blossom in the middle of winter!
Wow, a big parade of goblins!
I used to see those sorts of things.
Like a parade of foxes.
I know, I saw them too.
With little lanterns and everything.
And the lanterns would go marching along.
I wonder what that was all about?
Can foxes really do that?
It sure seems like they can.
I mean, you can see them.
It's just nerves.
All this talk about goblins.
All those old stories about foxes and lanterns.
It's all in your head.
You just think you saw them marching.
Your mind plays tricks.
Of course.
It's foolish to believe it.
The human mind is a frightening thing.
You're sure they're real.
But they can't be real.
Those are real.
They're all in your mind.
Welcome home.
Sachiko!
I summon the six elements!
Form is emptiness!
Master Gyobu!
That was scary.
Aw, is it over already?
That was so cool!
It's time for bed.
All right.
And brush your teeth.
I feel like I was dreaming.
Me too.
What could that have been?
Maybe UFOs are real too.
Strange things really do happen.
Long ago, when the Matsuyama Clan was at war...
Gyobu defected to the enemy, causing the downfall of his clan.
He regretted it so deeply, that he made a solemn vow...
to fight for justice.
His death must not be in vain.
Let us carry on his noble ideals.
We will fight to the end, until the day of triumph.
Ga-te ga-te para-ga-te Raccoons of the Sweetcake Hills Victory is ours!
We drink lots of sake and transform.
Operation Goblin was a big success!
But with all the excitement, they forgot to monitor the news.
We're looking for video of this mysterious parade.
No one has come forward yet.
Investigators are perplexed.
I shot all that video, but none of it came out.
This is really weird.
The goblin slipped in through here and it was terrifying!
Nobody could have faked that.
Something fishy is going on in New Town.
I wish I could move, but...
At 12:20 tonight, we will bring you a special program...
with in-depth coverage of this mystery.
As the humans investigate what happened...
they will realize that this wasn't their imagination.
They'll be face to face with reality.
Then, when they realize that their science and logic...
are powerless to unlock the riddle...
They will be dumbfounded by the mystery of the cosmos...
and realize how insignificant humanity really is.
Good fortune awaits us, but let's not wait for it.
Let's wake it up.
Let's celebrate!
Drink up!
Sing!
Dance!
But the next day...
things took an unexpected turn.
Last night's unauthorized parade in Tama New Town...
was a publicity stunt for Wonderland theme park, now under construction.
The police investigation is ongoing.
Nonsense!
However, local residents confirm that it didn't look like a publicity event.
Of course not!
The president of Wonderland confessed to last night's stunt.
What?
I would like to apologize to the public for this disturbance.
He's crazy!
We are still working on the construction of Wonderland.
But to let everyone know what a splendid park we're building...
we decided to provide some free entertainment.
As president of the park, I ordered the surprise parade.
- Liar!
- What's he talking about!
Fortunately, we've received an enormous outpouring...
of enthusiastic praise and support from the public.
We are overwhelmed at the enormous response.
If they must lock me up for this...
I'm prepared to pay the price.
- What the...
- Why?
Something is very wrong here!
If they must lock me up for this...
That fool!
The news threw the raccoons into a panic.
Meanwhile, Wonderland's boss searched for the parade's organizers.
Just find them.
I want the organizers.
I don't care what it takes.
I'll pay them whatever they ask.
As much as it takes!
It was raccoons.
What?
Then get me a raccoon!
Any raccoon.
Contact their manager!
Raccoons?
What did you say?
I was only joking.
Who are you?
How did you get in here?
Your secretary.
I phoned earlier.
My name's Ryutaro.
You seem to be in a tight spot.
But only I can contact the people who staged that parade.
All right, I'll give you a million dollars.
While this mysterious stranger explained his proposal...
the raccoons were enraged that their glory had been stolen.
They cried with resentment and sank into helplessness.
And since there was no video of the goblin parade...
media coverage tapered off.
You're a fox, aren't you?
Precisely.
I'm Ryutaro, transforming fox of Tama.
I've heard many tales of the Great Kincho from Shikoku.
This is an honor.
My ancestors were far greater than I.
So tell me, why are you here?
I was deeply moved by your fabulous parade.
You knew it was us?
Indeed.
And I understand your despair and discouragement.
I see, I suppose as a fox you would understand.
And I knew things would turn out this way.
You did?
Ryutaro invited Kincho to join him in Ginza...
in a private room at a certain well-known club.
Welcome!
Don't worry, all these ladies are foxes.
Would you prefer them as foxes?
Or shall I have them change into raccoons?
Let's be frank.
Raccoons have no future in Tama.
The foxes already died out.
The foxes died out already?
Yes.
It's a pity.
Now only a few of us...
survive as humans, like this.
Humans?
It's the key to survival in the big city.
I invited you here to persuade you raccoons to do likewise.
Just a moment!
I understand your shock.
But times like these...
call for drastic measures.
You must bear the unbearable.
Your only hope for survival is to get jobs at Wonderland.
What, and go to work for our enemy?
Let's think calmly.
At this point raccoons have no choice.
That much is given.
Living as a human fakes big money.
Ano' how do you earn a living?
You use the talents you have.
The question is which job would pay the best money.
Unfortunately Wonderland pays the best rates.
And the benefits are considerable.
This is the salary...
and these are the benefits.
Of course, only I will know that you're raccoons.
Bon appétit.
Let's think about it over dinner.
Enjoy the food, Master Kincho.
You must be tired of scraps from the garbage in Tama.
That's not important.
I have one question.
If we must live as humans, what about those who can't transform?
They have to fend for themselves.
At least the strongest ones will survive.
We too had to abandon our weaker members.
And they... perished.
Yes.
It was a heart-wrenching decision.
What a tragedy!
But you raccoons are lucky.
You can eat just about anything.
I wouldn't worry too much.
In Kincho's absence...
the Tama raccoons gathered to decide what to do next.
But only a handful showed up.
They talked big but they didn't deliver.
We never should have waited for them.
I say, “Don't sell the pelt until you've skinned the raccoon.” Not even Buddha could help us.
We must not blame the Masters.
“Tricky like a raccoon.” That's what humans call someone like the president of Wonderland.
You talk about humans too much, Shokichi!
I'm just trying to learn more about them.
Shut up!
We must kill all the humans!
Control yourself, Gonta.
Our only choice is to tell the humans...
that Operation Goblin was the work of us raccoons.
Have you lost your mind?
That's just what we mustn't do.
She's right.
If they find out, they'll come after us.
But it's so tragic.
That parade was a work of art.
Why can't we take the credit?
I can't bear this.
I want to shout it out!
We are the ones who did it!
But Tsurukame...
how would we get them to believe us?
We should make a public declaration.
Call the TV stations or send letters.
They'll probably think it's just a prank.
Then we'll go on TV and show them our transformations.
That's ridiculous.
They'll say it's just a trick and we'll be humiliated.
This is a waste of time.
This much was true.
The debate went back and forth, and on into the night.
This whole discussion is a waste of time.
But if we turn terrorist, the humans will kill us all.
That's why we shouldn't reveal our secret.
Then there's not much we can do.
Our only hope is to stick together.
We've got to try again.
We've got to launch Operation Goblin 2.
What's the point?
It'll fail the same way.
We'll perfect a new plan and a new strategy.
You just don't want to do anything.
You're like some stinking girl.
Watch your language, Gonta.
Girls don't stink.
Well if they did, he'd be one.
I'm going to get ready for Operation Goblin 2.
And who will follow you?
Who's going to follow you?
You watch your mouth!
Knock it off.
Listen everyone!
There's only one way for us to avoid conflict...
and it requires the use of our special talents.
Our powers overwhelmed the humans in Operation Goblin.
But unfortunately, they thought it was the work of men with inhuman talents.
Then what should we do?
We have to be creative.
Like Columbus and his famous boiled egg.
- Wow!
That's great!
- Bravo!
Is your plan that creative?
From now on, we will live as inhuman humans.
You must be joking.
No, this is no joke.
But what about the others?
Where did Tsurukame go?
APPEAL FROM THE RACCOONS While Tsurukame was absent from the meeting...
Kincho's plan was rejected.
Raccoon solidarity started to unravel.
Most of the raccoons went back to gathering food.
Hard-line Gonta went around recruiting troops for his battle.
Master Hage gathered the non-transforming raccoons...
and gave them faith with a new dancing religion.
These are chaotic times.
All we can do is dance.
Save us, merciful Buddha.
Look what has become of venerable Hage.
Tokyo is such a frightening place.
In Shikoku, a parade like that would have an instant impact.
Offerings at our shrine would go up five... no, ten times!
Master Kincho, take me back to Shikoku with you...
to continue my training.
I can't wait any longer.
Really, Tamasaburo?
Yes.
You're ready to be my successor?
Yes, Master Kincho.
I'm relieved to hear that.
But I have to ask you.
You're not the kind of raccoon...
who would abandon your comrades, are you?
Of course not.
But...
But what?
You've lost everyone's support.
What can we possibly do?
We're not finished yet.
I'll show you.
This is quite a fancy restaurant.
We spared no expense to please you.
This is astounding.
We'll be bigger than Disneyland!
To get revenge on the president...
Kincho and the raccoons ruined his deal with Ryutaro.
The president told the police...
that raccoons had stolen a million dollars from him.
But they wouldn't listen.
That same day, Gonta's army began their operations...
to stop the next phase of development.
Attention eco-terrorists!
Stop interfering with development and leave these woods at once.
You could be arrested for theft...
possession of dangerous weapons and illegal trespassing.
If you fail to evacuate immediately, we will use force to remove you.
Gonta's troops had the police and workers completely blocked.
They refused to budge.
By nightfall, both sides were still holding their positions.
If we can't stop Gonta, we have no choice but to help him.
The riot police are already there.
It's too late.
I'll check it out.
- Stop!
You'll be caught!
- We're going too!
Everyone ready?
In the spirit of honor, if we are sacrificed in battle...
our brother raccoons will continue to fight...
with undying determination until our day of victory.
Our raccoon balls Sway in the wind Back and forth To and fro Amen.
Special orders!
Stand aside!
Gonta, wait!
Let's go!
Gonta...
They used their balls in a last-ditch attack.
Mr.
Raccoon, Mr.
Raccoon.
Just then, in another part of the forest...
a TV crew was searching for the raccoons.
Won't you please come out?
You can transform or come as you are.
“World Telereporter” is on your side!
They seem quite reluctant.
Mr.
Raccoon, Mr.
Raccoon Can we talk?
We have nothing to eat.
They answered!
The letter we received was genuine.
We want your side of the story.
Won't you come out?
Here they are!
It's the raccoons!
Are you really responsible for the goblin parade?
Yes, we are.
We want our viewers to believe you.
Won't you give us a demonstration of your transforming talents?
Some of us raccoons can't transform.
We need our forest to live.
Please, raccoons.
If you don't come out, no one will believe you.
After all, you contacted us.
Please stand behind your words.
Tsurukame!
Please tell the humans our side of things.
There's one!
He transformed into a raccoon statue!
Mr.
Raccoon, a word for our viewers.
We...We...
Yes?
Please go on.
We staged the parade!
This is our home!
Please don't take it away from us!
This is the wish of all living things!
The people I saw yesterday are gone today.
The people I see today will be gone tomorrow.
Nobody knows about the day after that.
But someday people will be sorry.
999 years ago, the Battle of Yashima...
was witnessed by Hage...
the venerable Master of raccoons.
He had seen enough.
He was ready to leave this world.
With a song of triumph, they stretched his massive testicles...
into a treasure ship adorned with lacquer and gold.
He filled it with treasure, gold and jewels.
Buddha would carry them from earth to heaven.
Singing and dancing, the non-transforming raccoons...
boarded the ship for their journey to the shores of bliss.
The treasure ship sailed down the Tama River...
beneath the moon, rocking and swaying.
The sail filled with wind and they steered for the sea.
The river foamed beneath the prow.
The moon glinted off the water.
The treasure ship sailed on, rocking under the moon.
It was like a dream, with bells, flutes and drums.
Laden with raccoons, gold, silver and coral...
the treasure ship sailed away down the river.
Before it sank beneath the waves, the others watched tearfully.
The ship entered the mist like a dream on a night in spring.
As they looked up at the moon, Buddha beckoned them to heaven.
And they crossed over to the other world.
All the raccoons perished on that journey of death.
A journey with no return, a journey of death.
Poor raccoons, on a journey of death.
We're no match for the humans after all.
Bunta!
Is that Bunta?
Tamasaburo!
- It's good to see you back!
- Sasuke!
Shokichi!
What happened to the elder from Sado?
Master Danzaburo?
After searching all this time, I found that 45 years ago...
he was shot by a hunter during the famine after the war.
I see.
I was hoping to meet him.
Thanks for your hard work, Bunta.
Why is everything so different?
I've only been away three years.
We tried to stop them.
But nothing is the same.
Or have I gone crazy?
We know how you feel.
Was it the humans?
Yes, this is their work.
Impossible!
Only raccoons could be this tricky.
Not humans.
Those humans cheated us.
They were raccoons after all.
Old, stinking raccoons!
Give us back our hills!
Give us back our fields!
Give us back our home!
Let's change it back.
Our final operation.
Make it the way it was.
Why not?
We could hit the humans with one last illusion.
Interesting.
I can see the old scenery already.
All right.
One more try.
But, what would it prove to do something like that now?
Nothing.
But it will be amusing.
You're right.
A raccoon without a playful spirit...
is not a raccoon.
Will you help us too, Kincho?
Of course, if you don't mind a little southern flair.
Ponkichi!
I'm here!
Let's gather everyone who's left.
Can we count on you too?
Naturally!
Hey, wait for me!
Oh, that looks like Mother.
It's Yotchan.
Yotchan!
That's us when we were little!
Look, raccoons!
Gosh, they're so cute!
Look Mom, raccoons!
They're still around.
Even in a place like this.
Wait, raccoons!
Aw, they left.
I wanted to feed them.
Can raccoons really change into something else?
So we lost our battle.
And development just goes on, as if we'd never existed.
Humans quickly forget how things used to be.
At least for them, life is comfortable.
Trendy new condominiums stand on Manpukuji Hill.
And as it turned out...
showing ourselves to the humans had one good effect.
They take better care of nature.
They set aside the last bits of forest...
and built a few parks.
“In harmony with the raccoons,” as it said in the papers.
But for us it was too late.
We'd lost our home.
Some of us went over the mountain to live in a town called Machida.
But there were raccoons there already...
and development was hurting them too.
Many were killed on the road.
Life got harder and harder.
So we decided to bear the unbearable.
That's right.
Those of us who can transform...
are living as humans, just like the foxes.
I have a desk job.
My wife, Kiyo, works at a bar.
Some of us got greedy and made big money...
by working with the developers.
But most of us are tired and want to go back to the forest.
It's amazing that humans can actually live like this.
Some of us dropped out and survive on scraps...
from the bars and clubs of Shinjuku.
But what about Ponkichi and the other raccoons?
No matter how tough things get, raccoons are survivors.
They bear things without complaint and live happily and freely.
They have children with a carefree spirit, and then they die.
Ponkichi!
Shokichi!
- Welcome back!
- You haven't changed a bit!
On TV, they're saying that foxes and raccoons...
have disappeared because of urban sprawl.
Could you stop saying that?
Of course, some raccoons and foxes can transform.
But what about the rabbits and the other animals?
Some of us can't just disappear.
VOICES Narration by Shincho Kokontei Makoto Nonomura Yuriko lshida Norihei Miki Nijiko Kiyokawa Shigeru lzumiya Gannosuke Ashiya Takehiro Murata Kobuhei Hayashiya Akira Fukuzawa Beicho Katsura Bunshi Katsura Kosan Yanagiya Executive Producers Yasuyoshi Tokuma Seiichiro Ujiie and Ritsuo lsobe Planning by Hayao Miyazaki Original story and Screenplay by lsao Takahata Music by Shang Shang Typhoon English translation by Rieko lzutsu-Vajirasarn Nao Amisaki, Steve Alpert & Jim Hubbert English subtitles by AURA A Studio Ghibli Film Produced by Toshio Suzuki Directed by lsao Takahata  © anoXmous   @ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous