Dad, do you want some candy?
Thanks.
Aren't you tired?
All right We're almost there Mei, hide It wasn't a policeman Hello Are your parents around?
Thanks I'm Kusakabe We've just arrived A pleasure to meet you Welcome Thank you Here we are Wait Mei, there's a bridge A bridge?
See that flash?
Fish too So, you like it here?
Dad, it's terrific Look, a tunnel of trees Is that our house?
Come on It's a wreck Wreck Looks like a haunted house Haunted?
And it's all rotten It's gonna fall down Fall down Look, Mei See?
It's huge Dad, there's a huge tree It's a camphor tree Camphor tree Oops An acorn Show me Another one It's mine Out of the way I can't open the screens Acorns There's acorns in the house They dropped from up there Maybe there are squirrels in here Squirrels, really?
Or rats; they like acorns too I'd rather have squirrels Where shall I put this?
Here I'll get the door for you Satsuki, open up the kitchen Okay It's just round the back Mei, come on Wait for me Hurry Ready?
Bathtubs There's nothing here That's the bathroom Dad, there's something in here A squirrel?
I don't know A bunch of black things but not roaches or mice Really?
Can you see 'em?
I think they were dust bunnies Dust bunnies?
Like in my picture book?
That's right Ghosts don't come out on days like this When you walk into a dark room from outside your eyes dim and so the dust bunnies come out Oh, I see Come here, dust bunnies Come out, come out wherever you are Let's get to work See if you can find how to get upstairs Get up there and open all the windows Sure I'm coming, too Toilet Not here Nothing here Nothing Nothing here Nothing Nothing Nothing Nothing Mei, it's here It's pitch black Dust bunnies Another acorn Come out, dust bunnies Are you there, Mr.
Dust bunny?
Nothing Dad There's definitely something here That's exciting I've always wanted to live in a haunted house I'm coming I got it, Satsuki Mei You're full of energy This is Nanny She's come to look after the house I'm Satsuki and this is my sister, Mei Nice to meet you Nice to meet you both I'd have cleaned up If I'd known you'd be this quick No, you've done plenty Lately I've been so busy in the rice paddies I only did a bit of dusting Mei, what have you done to your hands?
The dust bunny got away Your feet, too Mine are black, too That must be the soot spreaders Those little black, fuzzy things that fly?
That's right They breed in empty old houses and cover them with soot and dust I could see them when I was little Now you can too, huh?
Are they like goblins or something?
Naah, nothing so scare If you keep smiling they'll soon leave the house They're probably deciding where to go next, right now Mei, they're going away That's no fun What happens if a huge one comes out, like this?
I wouldn't be scared Okay then I won't walk you to the bathroom at night Okay, cleaning time Could you get some water from the stream?
From the stream?
I'm coming, too Mei, wait there Did you get a fish?
Nanny, it's coming out Good keep pumping 'til the water gets cold Okay May I help you?
Huh, my Mom for Granny Yes?
Wait, what is it?
Is that you, Kanta?
You live in a haunted house Kanta, stop it I did the same kind of thing when I was his age I hate boys But, I really love Nanny's rice cakes Eat as much as you want Thank you Thank you very much for your help Good bye Dad, the house is going to fall down I hope not we've only just moved in Come on, let's laugh to keep the bogeymen away I'm not scared I mean it.
I'm not scared One-two, one-two...
Come on keep up the good work Okay, Washing finished Here we go Nanny Hello Hard at work?
Where're you all heading?
To visit Mommy in the hospital That's nice Give her my regards Okay This way...
Hello Hello, there Mommy So glad you came, my dear Daddy took the wrong road Really?
Hello, Satsuki It's a school holiday, today How nice Daddy is talking to the doctor It's so good to see you all Have you settled into the new house?
A haunted house?
Mom, do you like ghosts?
Of course, I do I can't wait to see them See, I told you, Mei Mei was worried that you wouldn't like ghosts What about you two?
I love them I'm not scared of them Are you fixing Mei's hair, Satsuki?
It's really good Lucky girl, Mei But she always gets mad at me That's 'cuz you won't stay still Come here, Satsuki Isn't yours too short?
No, I like it like this Do mine, Mommy Mine, too Wait your turn Wavy hair, just like mine when I was your age Will it be like yours when I grow up?
Probably You take after your Mom Mom looked really well You're right The doctor says she'll be home soon Soon?
Like tomorrow?
You always say this Tomorrow is a little too soon Mom said she'll sleep with me in my bed Weren't you saying you're big enough to sleep alone?
Mom is special Dad Time to get up Wake up Sorry, I overslept again I've got to bring a box lunch today I totally forgot about it It's all right I've made something for all of us It's burning Let me do it Here, this is yours, Mei It's for me Mei, sit down and eat Here Wrap yours Satsuki I'm coming You made a friend already?
She's calling you Yup, that's Michiko Gotta go See ya See you later Morning Hi, let's go Daddy Do I look all grown up?
Yes, dear And where might you be going?
I'm just going out Daddy, is it lunch yet?
Already?
You be the flower shop, Daddy Pole tads Got no bottom Gotcha Who are you?
A big Dust bunny?
To-to-ro?
You're Totoro I bet you're Totoro Totoro See you Okay, catch you later I'm home Hey there Is it that late already?
Where's Mei?
I'm off to Michiko's We haven't eaten yet Is Mei in the garden?
Mei Mei Mei Mei Dad, I found her hat Mei...
Wake up, Mei You shouldn't sleep here Where's Totoro?
Totoro?
Where?
Were you dreaming?
Totoro was here You mean that troll in your picture book?
Yeah He was all hairy with a big mouth like this There's a tiny one and a little one and a huge one like this There you are This is a great hiding place Dad, Mei said she saw a Totoro here A Totoro?
It's this way Hey, wait for me Is it here?
No It went to a big tree But there wasn't any other path Come back, Mei Mei, back But it's true Totoro was here I'm not lying I know, Mei I didn't lie Neither of us think you're lying You probably met the king of this forest You were very lucky He doesn't come out very often We should go to the shrine to pay our respects Pay our respects?
To this forest Mei, you're getting heavy Daddy, look That camphor tree What a big tree It's here Is that the tree?
Dad, hurry up The hole has gone Are you sure it was here?
The hole disappeared I told you he doesn't come to see us often But, will he come again?
I want to meet him, too If you're lucky, sure What a beautiful tree This tree must have stood here for years and years Trees and people used to be good friends I saw that tree and decided to buy the house Hope Mom likes it too Okay, let's pay our respects then get home for lunch Oh yeah I promised to go see Michiko I want to go, too Attention Thank you for looking after Mei Thank you very much Last one home's a rotten egg That's not fair, Dad Wait Hurry up Wait for me Dear Mother Something amazing happened today Mei met a giant Totoro And I'm hoping to see him myself soon, too Kanta, hurry up You'll be late Coming Mei?
Excuse me Yes, Satsuki?
It's my sister What happened, Nanny?
I'm sorry She insisted that she be with you It's Dad's day at the university You promised to be a good girl at Nanny's I still have two more classes and Nanny's too busy for this She was good up 'til now weren't you?
I'll go talk to my teacher Since Satsuki's mother is in the hospital I want you all to be nice to her Yes What's that?
It's Totoro Mei, you should keep quiet Okay Bye bye, Mei I can't stay after class today We'll let teacher know See you Hurry up, it's going to rain Okay Here it comes Here I won't cry.
Aren't I good?
It's getting worse Dear Guardian Spirit Let us stay until the rain stops But...
That was lucky It's got holes in it Daddy forgot his umbrella I'm going, too I said I forgot it What idiot forgets his umbrella on a rainy day?
Ouch You broke it playing, I bet I did not Excuse me Hello, Satsuki, Mei Grandma I'm sorry about Mei today Not at all Sorry we couldn't do more Kanta lent us this umbrella He did?
A broken old thing like that Mei was with me, so I was glad But I'm so sorry that Kanta got wet Thank you very much Not at all It probably cleaned him up a little Are you off to meet your father?
Yes What good girls you are Bye bye, Mei Bye bye Who was that?
I don't know Just in time Getting on?
All right, drive on Daddy wasn't on it He'll be on the next one Why don't you wait at Nanny's?
Are you okay?
Mei, sleepy?
I told you Wanna go to Nanny's?
It won't be much longer Hang in there It's late Come on Are you Totoro?
Wait a minute You can use this Take it, Mei's slipping off Hold it like this Here's the bus He took Daddy's umbrella I'm sorry All right, drive on The train was late and I missed the bus Were you worried?
We met him, Dad He was here And the cat bus What?
It was huge With big eyes like these We met him We met Totoro How wonderful Come on, Daddy Dear Mother I can't tell you how excited I was today It was the scariest funniest day I've ever had Totoro gave us a lovely present wrapped in bamboo leaves and tied with dragon whiskers When we opened it it was full of magic nuts and seeds We decided to plant them in the garden to make a lovely forest But they haven't sprouted yet Mei sits there all day waiting for them She looks like a little crab It's nearly summer vacation Dearest, dear Mom get well soon Love, Satsuki Come on.
Bed time Lights off Wait, Dad Daddy, do you think they will come out tomorrow?
Well, I'm sure Totoro would know Good night Wake up, Mei That's where we planted the seeds Wow, we did it We're the wind There are no trees Yes It was a dream...
But it wasn't a dream...
We did it Mr.
Kusakabe.
Telegram Mr.
Kusakabe Telegram Anyone home?
Nanny I'm here This one is ripe What about this one?
That's good, too Your garden's a treasure house Let's take a little break These should be cold now Looks delicious So good The sun blessed these So they're really good for you Would they help my Mom, too?
Of course If she eats my vegetables she'll get better right away She's supposed to be back next Saturday She'll sleep in my bed At last That's wonderful But it's only for a couple of days To get used to the new house I see We'll feed her lots of vegetables, then I'll give her this corn I picked I'm sure she'll be very pleased I know There was a telegram for you For us?
Dad won't be back till late what shall I do?
Open it it might be important PLEASE CONTACT, HOSPlTAL It's from Mom's hospital Something's happened to her Nanny, What shall I do?
Calm down Do you know where your Dad is?
I know his office number But we don't have a telephone Kanta take her to use the phone in the main house Mei, stay here with me Stay with Nanny, Mei Hello I'd like to make a long distance call, please It's Tokyo 31-1382 Yes A cute girl, Kanta Hello?
Yes Hello, may I speak to Dader.
Mr.
Kusakabe?
It's his daughter, Satsuki Yes Daddy?
It's me, Satsuki Hello, what's up?
From the hospital?
Okay I'll call them right away Is there anything wrong with Mom?
Don't worry I'll check up and call you right back I'm hanging up now stay there May I stay here until he calls back?
Stay as long as you like Satsuki No This corn is for my Mommy No, it's my Mom's Listen, Mei Mom's not well So she's not coming home this time No There's nothing we can do You don't want her to get worse, do you?
No It's just for a few more days No So you don't care if she dies, do you?
No Stop being silly.
I'm going Let's go, Mei I hate you, Satsuki We should bring the washing in Don't worry too much, Satsuki Nanny's here to help so cheer up Your Dad said he'll stop by the hospital to check on her Besides, it's just a cold she'll be back next week They said it was just a cold when she went into hospital But what if she dies Don't be silly, Satsuki Maybe Mom will Stop it Nobody would leave two pretty little girls like you There, there Don't cry I'll be here until Daddy comes back, okay?
Mei Mei Mei Did she come back?
Wasn't she at the bus stop?
That's strange Where has she gone?
I was nasty to her 'cause she was being silly Maybe she's heading for the hospital The hospital?
It would take a grown up three hours I'll go look Kanta, hurry Tell your dad that Mei is missing Stupid Mei Always getting lost Mei Excuse me Have you seen a little girl pass by?
She's my sister No, I don't think so I'm sure I would've noticed Maybe she wasn't here Are you sure she came this way?
I don't know Mei Please, stop Jerk.
What are you doing?
I'm looking for my sister Have you seen a little girl?
Your little sister?
She's four I think she's heading to the hospital Did you see anyone?
No.
We just came from there but we didn't see anyone Thanks anyway Where have you come from?
From Matsugo Really?
Good luck See you Satsuki Kanta Find her?
No And you?
Dad and the others are looking for her I'll go to the hospital you go back home I guess she got lost on the way to the hospital They found a sandal by the pond We're not sure if it's hers or not Did you find her?
Dear Lord please protect her and...
It's too deep here better search further away Hey, are there any poles left?
Grandma, Satsuki's here Nanny Look, is it hers?
No, it isn't Thank heavens I was sure it was hers Hey, Nanny was jumping to conclusions It's not hers Where's she gone then?
Let's start from scratch We better hurry it'll be dark soon I really appreciate your help, everyone Please, help me Totoro Mei is lost It'll be dark soon I'm sure she's scared somewhere Totoro Totoro, Mei is lost and we can't find her She must be scared please help me find her I don't know what to do They can't see the bus "FOREST-SWAMP" "CEMETERY-SHRlNE" "MEl" Mei...
The trees are moving out of the way Mei Satsuki...
Mei Mei Satsuki You silly girl I'm sorry You wanted to take the corn to Mom?
"HOSPlTAL" Will you take us to the hospital?
Thank you so much I'm sorry They didn't need to send a telegram just for a cold The girls must be worried I'm sorry to upset them They'll be fine As long as you're okay We've all learned to cope This'll just postpone the enjoyment They've put up with it so well I'm especially sorry for Satsuki she's so sensitive You're right I 'm going to spoil them for a while when I come home Oh no She's laughing Looks like she's fine I can't wait to get back on my feet Look Where did that come from?
What?
I could swear I just saw Satsuki and Mei laughing up in that tree Maybe they were too Look "For Mother"