Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network, Dentsu, Hakuhodo DYMP, Walt Disney Japan, Mitsubishi, Toho and KDDI present THE WIND RISES The wind is rising!
We must try to live.
Here it is.
May I borrow it?
- It's in English.
- I have a dictionary.
- Very good.
Give it a go.
- Thank you.
- Knock it off.
- Butt out!
Better get going.
Jiro...
No more bullying, okay?
You look quite the hero.
I slipped and fell.
- Fighting is never justified.
- I know.
Go have your snack.
Thank you.
Big brother, you're back!
I was waiting for you.
Let's pick bamboo grass.
Big brother!
I want to pick bamboo grass.
You promised to go with me.
I've got homework.
That's not homework.
It's an English magazine.
What a stupid moustache.
He's a famous Italian aircraft designer.
His name is Caproni.
It says he's a count.
- Your face is scratched.
- Leave it alone.
I better put some iodine on it.
Would you be quiet?
Big brother, what are you doing?
You're not allowed up here.
You're not wearing glasses.
Focusing on the stars should improve my eyesight.
- Mother will scold you.
- A shooting star!
There's another one.
They're pretty.
See?
Like that.
There's so many of them.
I'm a Japanese boy.
I think this is my dream.
This is my dream, you know.
It's mine too.
Your dream?
Listen, Japanese boy.
You think we are sharing this dream?
It's strange.
You're Count Caproni, aren't you?
I'm very glad to meet you.
Interesting.
Yes, this is a dream.
This world is a dream.
Welcome to my kingdom.
I'm honored.
Look at them.
They will bomb the enemy city.
Most of them won't return.
But the war will soon be over.
Climb up, Japanese boy.
This is my dream.
When the war is over, I will build this.
Magnificent, isn't she?
Let's fly.
Instead of bombs, she'll carry passengers.
Of course we can't climb up here...
but dreams are convenient.
One can go anywhere.
Come, join me.
You can walk along the spar.
Take a look.
- She's beautiful, no?
- Yes, incredible.
She'll carry a hundred people across the Atlantic.
Mr.
Caproni?
I have a question.
Do you think I could design airplanes?
I'll never be a pilot.
I'm too nearsighted.
Listen, Japanese boy.
I'm not a pilot.
I don't even know how to fly.
To fly airplanes is simple.
But I am a creator of airplanes.
An aeronautical engineer!
Yes!
Listen to me, Japanese boy.
Airplanes are not tools for war.
They are not for making money.
Airplanes are beautiful dreams.
Engineers turn dreams into reality.
Yes!
Arrivederci.
We'll meet again.
Jiro, you should go to bed.
You startled me.
I heard you talking to someone.
Mother, I'm going to be an aeronautical engineer.
Really?
That's a wonderful dream.
Airplanes are beautiful dreams.
That's what he told me.
I want to design beautiful airplanes.
You, there.
Come, take my seat.
Pardon me.
Please.
The wind feels wonderful.
Miss, you'll lose your hat.
Don't worry, Kinu.
Watch out!
Are you all right?
Safe!
Nice play.
Thank you.
"Le vent se l