Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network, Dentsu, Hakuhodo
DYMP, Walt Disney Japan, Mitsubishi and Toho present
Planning & Screenplay by Hayao Miyazaki
Produced by Toshio Suzuki
Based on the Original Graphic Novel by Chizuru
Takahashi & Tetsuro Sayama Screenplay by Keiko Niwa
Music by Satoshi Takebe
FROM UP ON POPPY HILL
"Summer of Farewells" Performed by Aoi Teshima
"Ue wo Muite Aruko" Performed by Kyu Sakamoto
Character Design Katsuya Kondo Imaging
Atsushi Okui Sound Design Koji Kasamatsu
Masami Nagasawa
Junichi Okada
Keiko Takeshita Rumi Hiiragi
Yuriko Ishida Jun Fubuki
Takashi Naito Shunsuke Kazama
Nao Omori Teruyuki Kagawa
Directed by Goro Miyazaki
The pot is bubbling,
The rice is steaming
The cutting board is standing by
The tofu is jiggly,
The eggs are slippery
The natto is sticky as can be
Drop the eggs in a frying pan
Stir the miso in a pot
Pile the rice in a server
Everything is ready to go
Time to wake up the house
Get everyone to the table
Now dig in, eat hearty
It's another sunny day
Another beautiful breakfast together
And I made it all for you
Hurry up, dig in now
But be sure to taste every bite
Another beautiful breakfast together
And I made it all for you
Hurry up, dig in now
But be sure to taste every bite
Morning!
Good morning.
Is Sora up yet?
Still in front of the mirror.
Morning.
Night shift again?
And tonight too.
Shall I save dinner for you?
Yes, thanks.
That's real service.
- The hospital's short-handed.
- I got a hole in my sock!
Leave it by the sewing machine.
More holes?
My socks keep shrinking.
This is for you.
Pack me a jumbo lunch.
Don't you eat enough already?
- Here Riku, have my fried egg.
- All right!
You need it more, Dr. Hokuto.
Who's the doctor here?
You drown everything in soy sauce.
- I like it that way.
- Me too.
Breakfast is ready, Hiro.
Good morning, Hana.
Good morning.
You can share your mother's.
Thanks.
Can I make you some tea?
No thanks, I've had some.
Good morning.
Thanks.
Please go ahead, everyone.
Let's eat!
You're late.
I can't get my hair right.
You look very pretty.
I'm starving.
Evening rounds again, Dr. Hokuto?
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Good morning, Tomoko.
Need a lift?
- Thanks, I'll walk.
- Suit yourself.
- Can you hang the laundry?
- Of course. See you this afternoon.
Bye, then.
KONAN ACADEMY
There she is.
Look what's in the school paper.
There's a poem about you.
Who else raises flags every morning?
'Fair girl, why do you send
Your thoughts to the sky?'
'The wind carries them aloft
To mingle with the crows. '
'Trimmed with blue,
Your flags fly again today. '
See? It must be about you.
I guess.
So it's about you.
Try a note
in a bottle next time.
Back off Math Club creep!
He practically lives
at the clubhouse.
All rise!
- We grabbed a table.
- See you there.
Nobuko, over here!
- I'm famished.
- What, curry udon again?
Why not? I like it.
Anyway, you're one to talk.
So? I like bread.
Umi's lunches look so good.
You should try making your own.
I could, I just don't
have enough time.
What are those guys
up to now?
All right, drop the banners.
LATIN QUARTER
ANTI-DEMOLITION LEAGUE
Go.
Go for it!
Look this way, you guys.
That was cool.
Are you okay?
So stupid...
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
- Thanks, Tomoko.
- My pleasure.
That should do it.
Today's fish was really cheap.
Thanks. I think I'll deep fry it.
I have to see Grandmother.
Grandmother? It's me.
Come in.
In the black again this month.
You're managing things beautifully.
Only because you're covering
Tomoko's wages for us.
It's nothing.
I'd have hired her anyway,
even without the boarders.
But isn't this
too much work for you?
I worry sometimes.
It doesn't feel so lonely
with everyone here.
I know. But still...
It makes me so sad, watching you
raise those flags every day.
No one knows how much
you miss your father.
I hope you find
someone wonderful soon.
Then you won't need
those flags anymore.
- Mrs. Matsuzaki?
- Come in.
I'm finished for the day.
Thank you, Tomoko.
I should get dinner going.
That was quite a stunt.
No kidding.
Some of the girls
are even starting a fan club.
What's his name?
Shun Kazama.
He's a live wire.
- The electrician's son?
- Hiro, you're so dense.
'Fair girl, why do you send
Your thoughts to the sky?'
Thus the Principality of Wallachia
was hemmed in...
by the Ottoman Turks and Russia,
and its territory was coveted by both.
SAVE OUR CLUBHOUSE
FROM DEMOLITION
Umi!
Sora? What's going on?
I bought this for 30 yen.
30 yen just for that?
Isn't he cool?
I've got to have his autograph.
Please come with me.
I've never been inside the clubhouse.
Neither have I.
I'm not going in there.
- Please!
- No way.
Come on, just this once.
Come on...
DON'T DEMOLISH OUR CLUBHOUSE
Read)/-7
Excuse me?
- Today's spots are very distinct!
- And they form a straight line.
A textbook magnetic field.
Excuse me.
What?
We're looking for the
school newspaper office.
Third floor, same room
as the Archaeology Club.
Thanks.
Don't they ever clean this place?
Hey.
Hi, we're looking for the
Archaeology Club.
Upstairs.
Look for the Lit Club sign.
Thanks.
At last, inquiring minds!
The Philosophy Club wants you.
New members!
How long has it been?
My struggle was not in vain.
We're just heading for the
Archaeology Lit Club, actually.
Now don't be shy.
Shall we discuss existentialism?
Or perhaps you prefer Nietzsche?
Chem Club! How dare you
disturb our contemplation?
Better run, you guys.
You'll be there all day.
Show some respect,
you second-rate alchemists.
At least we do experiments.
Your ideas can't even be proved.
'New poets! Draw energy
from clouds, light, storms... '
'Show us the direction
humanity should take... '
'A Copernicus for a new age,
to set us free... '
CQ! CQ!
This is a high school student
from Japan.
LITERATURE CLUB
LATIN QUARTER WEEKLY
This is it.
Matsuzaki.
Yamazaki...
Hey,Shun!
Couple of VIPs to see you.
Welcome to the Lit Club.
Or was it the Archaeology Club?
Don't tell me you're here
about that rag we publish.
Knock it off, Mizunuma.
Come in and close the...
They'll shut us down!
We're down to two members.
The Archaeology Club is doomed.
Can you sign this?
Do it for her, hero.
Thank you!
Your hand...
Just a cat scratch.
This isn't from the jump.
A cat...?
Wait, could you cut
some stencils for Shun?
We're all pretty busy
with the anti-demolition campaign.
You're the little sister?
Yes, I'm Sora Matsuzaki.
You help them, Umi.
My handwriting is terrible.
You're joking. Why should I...
PHYSICS MIDTERM FORECAST!
You're a junior.
Got Suzuki for physics?
Suzuki? Yes.
Then you need this.
Mizunuma's exam forecasts
are usually spot on.
But not guaranteed.
Bring your own luck to the test.
See you at six.
Shall we go?
Oh, yes!
Miss Matsuzaki,
I'd better see you out.
Our resident philosopher
might ambush you.
Oh, thank you!
From here to the end.
We've got to do something.
Yes, for the honor of those
who went before us!
Meeting, Shun.
Care to join us, Matsuzaki?
It's the anti-demolition meeting.
Is it that late?
I finished.
Thanks, that really helps.
Meeting!
All hands on deck.
Time for today's meeting.
I'm home.
Hi, Umi.
I'm running late. Let's do curry.
Can you cut the vegetables?
Sure.
- I'm back.
- We were waiting.
Riku, I need some pork.
Can you run down for me?
What, right now?
Sora?
But the program just started.
You didn't ask Tomoko
to get some?
I used it for lunches.
Start the rice
in 10 minutes, okay?
Okay.
Shopping?
Sort of.
Hop on.
Bottom of the hill, right?
Don't worry, my hand's okay.
I can use the brake just fine.
How was your meeting?
Still going strong.
But I've got curfew.
Did you finish printing the paper?
You must be kidding.
I'll do it tomorrow before school.
Listen, Shun.
Can I ask you something?
That poem in the paper...
- You were saying?
- No, it's okay.
Thanks.
400 grams of sliced pork.
Two to go.
- Here you go. 240 yen.
- Thanks.
Come again.
Thanks.
Dig in.
I need energy to get home.
Where's your house?
- By the harbor.
- Gosh, that's far.
See you.
Thank you!
This is nice.
Can I come in?
Don't you feel well?
Go on ahead, Sora.
I'm coming in.
Wow...
I shouldn't paint at night.
The colors are all wrong.
It's beautiful.
What's this?
That tug goes by a lot.
I think it's answering your flags.
Guess you can't see
the tug from there.
Answering my message?
I need food.
Good morning.
All printed up.
Your handwriting's great.
Thanks.
Listen...
Can I help with anything else?
Of course.
But I can't stay late.
I'll give you some stencils.
You can transfer copy at home.
There's a debate after school.
Why don't you come?
Sorry, I'm busy today.
Bye.
Umi, wait!
Let's get ice cream.
No club meeting?
It was canceled for the debate.
Sorry, Tomoko's off today.
I have to be back early.
Come on everybody,
the debate's starting.
RESOLVED: THE LATIN QUARTER
SHOULD BE PRESERVED!
Good, hold it right there.
This'll get rough.
Afternoon. Heading home?
Got some nice flounder fillets.
Okay, I'll take some.
- Your mom back yet?
- Not yet.
I'll come back later!
What's going on?
We've had peace for nearly 20 years.
The Olympics are coming soon.
It's a whole new era.
Japan is changing radically.
We must build a new society
on the ruins of the old.
Tearing down the Latin Quarter...
and building a new clubhouse
is a historical necessity.
And the students want it.
Umi!
What's happening?
I don't know exactly.
We surveyed the students
about the new clubhouse.
80 percent of the student body
want to rebuild.
I believe we must accept
the board's plan!
You're like the old men
who run this country...
just blindly following the crowd.
Silence! I have the floor.
Who cares about percentages
when you're wrong? Blockheads!
Wait your turn!
Is this the tyranny of the majority?
You can't grasp
the meaning of democracy.
Want to demolish something?
Demolish your own heads.
I have the floor!
Destroy the old and you
destroy our memory of the past.
Don't you care about the people
who lived and died before us?
There's no future for people...
who worship the future
and forget the past.
Democracy doesn't mean
you can ignore the minority.
Throw the anarchists out!
Scrum!
Eject them!
Stand fast, men!
Get off the stage. You're history!
A white flower was blooming
That day long ago,
in my homeland far away
When at last we parted
You looked away
And didn't say a word
I remember your long braids
And the sadness in my heart
As that white flower bloomed
So what did you think?
It was amazing.
Everybody's so passionate.
Debates are always like that.
Most everyone thinks
the clubhouse should go.
Mizunuma's fighting a losing battle.
You think?
Maybe you could
clean the place up.
It's old, but
it's such a nice building.
Make it like new again.
Invite the girls to come see it.
- Then they'll get it.
- Maybe you're right.
But the guys think
all that dust is part of history.
The physics midterm forecast
was a big hit.
Everybody's waiting
for the math forecast.
Me too.
Thanks. You've been a big help.
- See you soon.
- So long.
Umi! Thanks.
Oh no... the fish!
...then everyone started singing.
The teachers were totally fooled.
It sounds like nothing's changed
since I graduated.
Your president Mizunuma
is my classmate's little brother.
- Was his brother a genius too?
- Sister. She's an astrophysicist.
Wow...
What's all the excitement in here?
- Great idea.
- This is the best.
I'll slice some cheese.
- Can I taste it?
- Sorry, too young.
Umi, why don't we invite
some Konan graduates...
to my farewell party?
Who?
You know... the guys.
Guys?
Hey.
H-O-K-U-T...
Hokuto.
You read signal flags?
The gate's open.
Coming.
Why not get married
and start a practice right here?
We'd have to move out!
You'll be married by then.
I'd better start looking.
Bet you find
a real nice guy.
You're the best.
- The trustees are the problem.
- The principal's a good guy.
- He goes where the wind blows.
- The chairman's an old fox.
When's the principal going to quit?
I think we can handle them,
but we need a strategy.
Even with a strategy,
what can we actually do?
We need more glasses.
I'll wash some.
Here, take this out.
The sushi's here.
Finally!
This building is 60 years old.
It used to be a hospital.
My great-grandfather loved cats.
Compared to the clubhouse,
it looks like it was built yesterday.
You really take good care of it.
So I guess your dad
must've been a doctor too?
No, he was a ship captain.
From this Valley
They say you are going
We will miss your bright eyes
And sweet smile
For they say
You are faking the sunshine
So your mom married a sailor.
Grandma and Grandpa
were totally against it.
They tried to stop her.
So Mom ran away and they eloped.
I bet that took guts.
I heard your mom's a professor.
And the signal flags...
Your dad taught you?
Yes, when I was little.
He said they helped him
find his way back to us.
So I raised them every day.
I'd raise them from the balcony
until his ship docked again.
I never missed a day.
Then his ship sank
in the Korean War.
And that was that.
But I never stopped
raising those flags.
After I moved here,
I wouldn't stop crying.
There was nowhere
to raise Dad's flags.
So Grandpa built me
that flagpole.
I'll open the curtains.
This used to be Grandpa's office.
Now it's my mom's study.
It looks like a library.
This is your family?
Yes.
Your father?
That's Grandpa.
My dad's right there.
Isn't he handsome?
That's when they got married.
This is the picture I really like.
Yuichiro Sawamura...?
That's my dad.
Matsuzaki is my mom's name.
Come on, it's speech time.
We better go down.
I'm back.
You're late.
You'll worry your mother.
- Shun, what about dinner?
- I already ate.
He swings... Nagashima strikes out!
ONODERA SAWAMURA
TACHIBANA
Yuichiro Sawamura...
Thanks for coming.
What's going on?
Welcome, volunteers.
The Latin Quarter is all yours.
You have our deepest thanks...
for helping us to preserve
this magnificent cultural landmark.
Remember, men.
The heavy lifting is up to you.
Let's do it!
My shrine to Reason!
- No exceptions, that's the rule.
- Okay, ready.
Here we go.
Be careful, will you?
Hey, watch it!
1st Year Math... 2nd Year Math...
These are old exams.
We use those for forecasts.
Here's Dr. Hokuto's math final.
She got a perfect score.
Take over for me.
We need everything moved.
I'll give you a hand.
Heads up, Matsuzaki.
Mizunuma said to pitch anything
we're not sure we need.
It's so filthy.
Didn't you guys ever clean?
Not since I've been here.
We better bring
the badminton girls tomorrow.
Please do.
Sora, I'm going now.
Okay.
I'll be home by dinner.
Did something happen?
Not a thing.
See you tomorrow.
Dad, can I ask you something?
I'm working. Make it short.
Yuichiro Sawamura.
He's my real father, right?
We've been over that.
You're my son.
It was blowing hard
the night Sawamura brought you.
He had his Family Register with him.
We'd just lost a child
of our own.
Next thing I knew,
your mother was nursing you.
She wouldn't let you go.
Sawamura was a good sailor.
His supply ship sank
during a battle in the Korean War.
Until the end,
he helped us out.
You remind me of him
more every day.
But you're still our son.
Thanks, Dad.
Is it out there?
Not yet.
Guess it's not coming by today.
THE LATIN QUARTER REBORN!
May I...?
Come in, Umi.
You're really leaving.
Thanks for all your help.
- I wish I could see you off.
- Go on, I'll be fine.
We'll miss you.
I'll drop by now and then.
You'd better get to school.
Good luck with Shun.
Take care.
Extra, extra!
Extra edition of
The Latin Quarter Weekly.
We'll need your help today.
Latin Quarter gets a facelift!
Extra, extra!
I'll be there again today.
Hi. You're working hard.
Hey, see you there, okay?
Here, Matsuzaki.
Extra, extra!
Get your Latin Quarter.
Extra!
Next label, please.
He's so brave.
- This is great.
- Let's go look.
If you don't like me,
just say so.
Yuichiro Sawamura.
He's my real father.
It's like some cheap melodrama.
I don't understand.
Dad told me years ago.
I even checked at City Hall.
But then...
We're brother and sister.
What should we do?
We forget whatever it was
we felt about each other.
We'll just be friends, like before.
Sora, did something happen
to Umi at school?
No, at least
I don't think so.
Are you sure?
That dinner tonight
was pretty strange.
And she was soaked.
Something must've happened.
She's never come home that late.
Umi, the bath's ready.
Not tonight.
Don't you feel well?
Umi...
Good morning, Umi.
Did you sleep well?
Mom? When did you come back?
Don't be silly.
I've been here all along.
Umi, I'm hoisting the flags.
Come give me a hand.
Dad...?
I'll be home for a long time.
You're such a big girl now.
Need more supplies?
Just ask this guy.
He's in construction.
- Come on, no more freebies.
- Why not? Business is good.
HOPE YOU guys win.
Thank you.
Unbelievable.
We owe this to Dr. Hokuto.
No, even more to Umi.
She's our goddess of good luck.
Hi guys-
This is practically
a construction site.
What are you doing?
Give me that for a sec.
Let me show you
how the pros do it.
Incredible!
My dad's a plasterer.
Beautiful...
What's that?
The wall, I mean.
WHAT?
Hey.
That's it for today.
Thanks for staying late.
You don't have to go back?
Sora's covering for me.
Can I help out with anything?
Could you do this?
Can I have two days?
That'll really help, thanks.
- See you.
- So long.
VISIT THE NEW LATIN QUARTER!
MAJORITY OF GIRLS
OPPOSE DEMOLITION!
MIDTERM RESULTS ANNOUNCED,
TEST FORECAST VINDICATED!
MAJORITY OF ALL STUDENTS
OPPOSE DEMOLITION!
Ready, everybody?
Umi, don't go.
Shun, it's bad news.
The board just voted
to tear us down.
The principal won't listen to reason.
All our hard work!
- They won't even come?
- Then they'd have to back down.
Right!
Mob the principal's office!
Let's go straight to the chairman.
Of the Tokumaru Foundation?
He's pretty hard to see.
You guys go see him.
Tell him how it is.
Yes, please go.
Mizunuma, we've got to go to Tokyo.
Please!
It's worth a shot.
Umi, we need you too.
Tell him, Umi!
Umi, good luck tomorrow.
Good morning.
Did you skip class?
No, I told them yesterday
I'd be absent.
Then we'd better get going.
FOR A SUCCESSFUL OLYMPICS,
MAKE TOKYO BEAUTIFUL
Let's give it our best shot.
Yes, that's what they say.
No appointment?
We're appealing directly
to Mr. Tokumaru.
Something about a direct appeal.
Yes, students from Konan Academy.
Three of them.
All right.
Take the elevator
to the fourth floor and wait there.
Fourth floor.
Don't forget to sign in.
One name is fine.
Are you the Konan students?
Yes.
The president's very busy.
I can't guarantee
he'll have time for you.
We're sorry to disturb him.
We didn't think he'd agree
to an appointment.
You may just be
wasting your time...
but please wait here if you like.
We'll Wait!
Oh come on,
Kimura has the best pastries.
Nakamura's hard to beat.
I can't believe you'd say that.
You don't know your pastries.
Thank you.
It's as plain
as the nose on your face.
Come on in, kids.
Excuse us.
Have a seat.
Be with you in a minute.
So you see how it is.
Yes, give him my regards.
Sit.
Now, why aren't you kids
in school?
We escaped.
Escaped?
I did that a lot myself.
You're here about
your clubhouse, I suppose.
Yes, we'd like to ask you
to come and inspect it yourself.
You're welcome any time.
What year are you?
I'm a junior. Umi Matsuzaki.
I help out with the school paper.
What do you care
about that old shack?
We all love it.
We spent hours making it look new.
Please see for yourself.
You cleaned it up?
What does your father do?
He was a ship captain
in the Korean War.
His ship hit a mine.
A supply ship?
Yes.
I see.
It must've been hard
for your mother, raising you alone.
She did a fine job.
Thank you.
All right, I'll go.
Thank you!
It's me.
What's on tomorrow?
Let's see, that's in the evening.
Move the rest to Friday.
It's settled.
Tomorrow afternoon.
I'll contact your principal
and do an official inspection tour.
- Some grownups are pretty cool.
- Don't count your chickens.
I'm glad we came.
I have to swing by my uncle's place.
See you tomorrow.
What are you doing
after graduation?
I can't afford much tuition.
I'll apply to a national university.
What about the Weekly?
I'll find somebody to take over
after things are settled.
What about you?
I haven't decided.
I'd like to be a doctor, though.
Are you the one
who wrote that poem?
I saw you raising your flags
every morning from my dad's tug.
I can't see the tug passing by
from the garden.
That's why I never noticed
you were answering me.
Shun?
Listen, I...
Those flags
were a message to my dad.
I think he sent you to me.
That's what I want to believe.
I'm in love with you, Shun.
Umi...
Even if we're related,
even if you're my brother...
my feelings will never change.
I feel the same about you.
I'm back.
Let's try it.
Mom!
Umi, I'm home.
Finally! How was America?
I was busy learning every day.
Any boyfriends yet, Sora?
Not yet.
This is great stuff, Mom.
It's called jerky.
Is it pork?
Hiro, it says beef
on the package.
Mom?
You're up pretty late.
I wanted to ask you something.
Ask away, then.
I'm wide awake.
Sorting through these books
woke me up even more.
There's this boy at school.
His name is Shun Kazama.
He came for the farewell party.
I showed him Dad's picture.
He had the same photo.
He says his real father
is Yuichiro Sawamura.
This one?
I'm afraid this is all
a little bit complicated.
I told you about how
your father and I eloped.
You remember, don't you?
Our first place
was that second-floor apartment.
Yuichiro was away a lot.
I was pregnant with you
and working on my degree.
I loved school so much.
I was determined to do well.
Yuichi...
Yuichiro, whose baby is that?
It's Tachibana's boy.
He's ours now.
Tachibana was killed in an accident
on a repatriation ship.
His wife died giving birth.
The Bomb killed their relatives.
If we don't register him as ours,
he'll end up in an orphanage.
Yuichiro registered the baby
as his son and brought him home.
The war had just ended.
It was happening everywhere.
But I was already pregnant.
There was no way I could raise him.
Yuichiro's friend lost a child,
so we gave the baby up.
Is he doing well?
I'm so glad.
Your father was so good-hearted.
Maybe just a little impulsive.
Without his help,
I couldn't have finished school.
But what if Shun
was really Dad's son?
If he was really Yuichiro's son?
I'd like to meet him.
Does he look like this picture?
Umi...
See you tonight.
Have a nice day.
Welcome to the Latin Quarter.
LATIN QUARTER WELCOMES
CHAIRMAN TOKUMARU
I never realized this building
was so impressive.
Thank you, sir.
What are you studying?
Sir! The Astronomy Club
has studied sunspots for 10 years.
10 years?
And what did you discover?
The sun is very old,
and our lifespan is short.
No discoveries so far!
Excellent answer.
The Philosophy Club?
Wouldn't you like
a brand new clubhouse?
What about your junior members?
Sir, we philosophers
can be content with just a barrel.
Diogenes! Very good.
Principal, your students
are really quite impressive.
Shun Kazama?
Hello, Dad?
The third man
in the photo is here.
He can tell you
about your father.
His ship leaves at four o'clock.
He won't be back for months.
Get down here!
Should the world sink
Beneath the indigo waves
Stand fast, sink not
Beneath that horizon
Stand fast against the flood
Like a great range of mountains
With pinnacles thrust high
Into the Winds of the future
Should the World sink
Beneath the indigo waves
Stand fast, sink not
Beneath that horizon
My friends, you have shown me
the Latin Quarter's true value.
How can we educate the young
without protecting our culture?
I'll just find a different site
for the new building.
All right!
Umi, you did it.
We all did it.
Awesome! Magnificent!
On to the next experiment.
Umi, we owe this to you.
But I didn't do anything special.
Fixing things up was your idea.
She's right.
Thank you, Umi.
Good for you. Umi.
Umi!
The perfect couple.
Please excuse them, sir.
Something very important
is happening to both of them.
They have to hurry.
Escape.
It's great to be young.
Shun!
Give us a ride.
Umi?
Don't worry Umi,
I'll get you there in time.
We'd better run.
Thanks!
Good luck, Umi.
Come on, Shun. Hurry!
Thanks.
That's my dad's tug.
Here they are, captain.
Push our departure back
15 minutes.
So you're Tachibana's boy.
And you must be
Sawamura's daughter.
Both fine-looking youngsters.
It's Shun, right?
Your father was Hiroshi Tachibana.
Front row, fourth from the right.
You can see Sawamura
next to him.
We three were close friends.
Take the seat of honor, Tachibana.
Why me?
You're our leader.
You belong there.
All right, let's do it.
Just don't die before me, okay?
Same goes for you.
Here we go.
I was away at sea
when your parents passed on.
Otherwise I'd have done
exactly what Sawamura did.
Meeting you two
is like seeing my old friends again.
Thank you both.
I've never been so happy.
A cross the shining sea,
A ship disappears in the sunlight
Its horn trails a note of farewell
If I walk down that gentle slope
Will I feel a breeze the color of summer?
My love is a melody
I sing it high and low
My love is a seagull
That soars and swoops
If I call out to you at twilight
Will I see you there my sweet?
Swaying branches along the path
Leave farewell shadows on the ground
A weather vane rooster, an old chapel
Will I see a city
Steeped in summer hues?
Yesterday's love is my fears
They dry and vanish with time
Tomorrow's love is a refrain
Words without end
If we meet at twilight
Will you hold me in your arms?
Translation by
Jim Hubbert and Rieko Izutsu-Vajirasarn
Subtitles by Aura
A Studio Ghibli Film
The End
Events and characters
depicted in this film are fictional.