Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network,
Dentsu, Hakuhodo DYMP.
Buena Vista Home Entertainment,
Mitsubishi and Toho PRESENT
Only in silence the word,
only in dark the light,
only in dying life:
bright the hawk's flight
on the empty sky.
- The Creation of Éa
Ease the sail!
It's blowing too hard!
Curse it! A storm this time of year?
Where's my Weatherworker?
What are you waiting for?
Calm the waves before we sink!
What's wrong?
Captain... I can't remember them.
I can't remember the True Names
of wind and waves.
What? Are you mad?
Captain!
There's something above the clouds!
Where?
What is that?
A dragon!
What is it doing here?
There's another one!
Dragons fighting? That's impossible!
More than 2, 000 sheep
have taken the fever in Enlad alone.
Half of them have died.
Seven hundred cattle
have been infected.
We've lost 50 head so far.
In fact, a baby on Taon
has also come down with the fever.
Silence!
If we panic,
what will become of the People?
Seal off the affected areas.
Send every healer
in the kingdom to find a cure.
Send provisions
to those who need them.
Wizard Root!
Find out what's behind this.
Your Majesty.
And the drought
in the provinces?
We sent Weatherworkers
but the results were disappointing.
Soon it may be too late
for the spring planting.
Why have these misfortunes
befallen us, Root?
I sense the Light dimming,
Your Majesty.
The Light?
The Light of the Balance
that sustains the world.
Your Majesty!
What now?
Terrible news!
Dragons have been sighted
off the coast!
- Dragons?
- Two, Majesty. One was killed.
Dragons here, in the East?
Can this really be true?
Long ago, dragons
and men were one.
But men who coveted possessions
chose the land and the sea.
Dragons who wanted freedom,
chose wind and fire.
Since then, dragons and men
remained apart.
To hear that dragons have been seen,
and were even fighting...
The twilight that threatens
us is ever deepening.
Bring the captain to me.
I would hear more of this.
Root, I want you there too.
Please... Your Majesty!
- We'll get in trouble!
- I have to!
- What is it?
- Have you seen Prince Arren?
He's been gone since last night.
Prince Arren? Gone?
That's enough.
His Majesty is occupied.
Surely you can see that.
Forgive me.
It's just... he seems so sad lately.
We were worried.
That's absurd!
Arren is 17, not a child.
Forgive this disturbance, Your Majesty.
Your people are more important.
- Very well, then.
- Your Majesty.
I must tend
to my correspondence.
We await your command, sire.
I'm imagining things.
Arren!
So you are my death...
Are you hurt?
Steady there, lad!
Is this what you seek?
This is dangerous country
for travelers.
You were lucky this time.
You must be hungry.
It's not much,
but you're welcome to it.
What is your name, lad?
My name is Arren.
Arren, is it?
It means sword, doesn't it?
So you hail from Enlad.
How did you know?
That blade
was forged with magic.
I doubt you could unsheathe it.
What is it?
It's nothing.
Arren?
If you have nowhere to go,
why not come with me?
I doubt our meeting here
was an accident.
And I'd welcome
a companion on the road.
Arren! Are you coming?
What should I call you?
Call me Sparrowhawk.
Another abandoned farm.
Farmers leaving their land...
There's more to this
than poor harvests.
Come, Arren.
We'd better push on.
Lord Sparrowhawk?
Sparrowhawk will do.
What is it?
Sparrowhawk?
Where are we heading?
First. we go to the next town.
But after that...
...even I don't know.
- Getting tired?
- No.
Come along.
We're almost there.
There it is.
Hort Town.
Are they prisoners?
They are slaves.
Here, people are goods
to buy and sell.
Trading in human lives!
Two guineas, gentlemen!
Do I hear two guineas?
I have two guineas!
Three! Sold to the gentleman
for three guineas!
No, sorry!
Couldn't possibly find room!
Gauzes from Sowl!
Silks from Lorbanery!
Furs and felts and woolens!
Is this a market day?
No. It's like this year round.
Silks and satins!
Canvass and fleecefells!
What can I show you?
This is Lorbanery's finest silk!
Fine as a mayfly's wing!
I don't have a wife.
I need a cloak for my friend.
Wizards! No girlfriend, eh?
- But I don't need a cloak.
- You can't go about like that.
You should hide
that thing on your belt.
What about this?
Fleece from Gont.
Highest quality.
Four warp strings.
This is Andradean work.
On Gont they use six or more.
You used to be a sorceress.
Why are you selling fakes?
People don't believe
in foolish tricks any more.
My goods are
not what I claim.
But at least they're real...
...not mere lies and air
like magic and sorcery!
Sparrowhawk!
Thank you!
What!
Unhand me!
Calm yourself, young master.
I have something for you.
It's the door to bliss.
What is it?
Hazia, my lord. Ha-zi-a.
Take one.
Leave sorrow and fear behind.
No more sorrow or fear...
You'll never be troubled
with the pain of this world again.
You needn't pay me.
It's my pleasure.
Arren.
What are you doing?
Is this your friend, my lord?
And what about you?
Don't wizards have troubles too?
I'm sorry. I have no use
for what you're selling.
Save us from the arrogance
of sorcerers!
I suppose you've lost
your powers too!
Hazia is not something
to toy with, Arren. Look!
The hazia eater feels
himself in paradise.
Then the spirit leaves the body
and wanders aimlessly in darkness.
When it returns? More hazia.
And finally, death.
What's the matter?
Feeling better?
The wind is fresh up here.
Something's wrong with this town.
Not only this town, lad.
Farmers' crops wither.
Their sheep and cattle are falling sick.
Even people's minds
have lost their way.
Is it some sort of pestilence?
No. A pestilence
is how the Balance restores itself.
But this? I fear someone
is trying to destroy the Balance.
There's only one creature
in Earthsea capable of such evil.
Only one.
Well then.
Shall we go back to the inn?
I'd like to rest a little longer.
Very well.
I'll be waiting.
Keep your wits about you.
I will.
Slave takers?
A witch, are you?
And an ugly one at that!
Won't fetch much with that face.
Just a few guineas.
But we can still have a little fun.
Oww! My finger!
The witch has spirit!
I'm going to enjoy this.
Who's there?
Step forward and show yourself!
Well, well.
What are you
doing here, boy?
Go ahead. Take him!
No hard feelings, boy.
Just following the boss's orders.
I'll make it quick.
Or maybe you'd like to be a slave?
Beg for your life!
Changed your mind?
Life is nothing to me.
So you want a fight, eh?
Draw your sword!
All right. Now it's my turn.
Uh oh.
Hold on there son.
You don't care about the girl?
Do it.
If you want her so much,
here she is!
Come on men!
Let's go!
Are you...
Therru!
Therru...
A bird...
So! We meet again, boy.
Take him!
He'll fetch a good price.
Don't be too rough.
Take him away!
Just an old piece of junk.
Couldn't give it away!
Give it up, it's no use.
Quiet!
Silence!
Or I'll feed you to the hounds!
Come on!
Get moving!
What's going on?
I don't know.
Move, you lazy animals!
Confound it! What's wrong?
Sparrowhawk...
Let's go, Arren.
Can you stand?
What about the others?
I left none bound.
Now it's up to them.
How did you know
where to find me?
When you didn't come,
I scoured Hort Town.
Finally, someone told me
a young man was taken by slavers.
I had to make
a spell of finding.
I am sorry, I was foolish.
No, it was my fault.
I should've been more careful.
I'm sorry.
Who's there?
It's me, Sparrowhawk.
Sparrowhawk?
Someone's been hurt.
I'm sorry. It's late.
It's been a long time, Ged.
He's asleep.
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid you've lost your bed.
It's his now.
Here, this will warm you.
Thanks.
You haven't changed.
No.
You're keeping well, Tenar?
I suppose.
It hasn't always been easy.
And you?
Do you still wander?
That was good.
It has been a long time.
Yes, it has.
As Archmage, I have no time...
...to wander as I once did.
And what brings the Archmage
so far from home?
Evil tidings come
from every corner of Earthsea.
Things are out of balance...
...as if the sun's light
were ebbing.
Is the Art Magic ebbing too?
Yes. As if our very blood
were flowing from our veins.
So you search for the answer?
Yes.
Oh dear, we woke you up.
Come, child. Don't worry.
This man is an old friend of mine.
This is Therru.
She's been with me five years.
Call me Sparrowhawk.
I'm sorry I woke you.
Hawk?
Well, you should be honored.
Therru never speaks to strangers.
What is it?
Could she really be...?
Lord Cob.
Enter.
Forgive my intrusion.
I beg leave to speak.
What is it?
I'm afraid some
of our slaves escaped.
I see. You let
my precious merchandise go.
No. We've captured most of them.
And?
What about the others?
We're scouring the countryside.
We'll find them.
You're a fool.
Do you think
I can't manage without you?
It was a wizard!
A wizard with a scar on his face!
What?
A scar on his face?
It's Sparrowhawk.
The Archmage pays me a visit.
Find him for me,
Hare... or else.
I won't fail you, my lord.
I've waited long
for this day... Sparrowhawk.
Tenar! I brought the water in!
Where is she?
Tenar? Are you still asleep?
Tenar?
Are you sick?
Who was that?
It's that girl!
That must've been a surprise.
I'm sorry dear. I should've told you.
Don't worry. Arren is with me.
You have nothing to fear.
Sometimes his eyes are wild,
but he has a good heart.
Good morning.
I'm done eating!
Well!
Did you sleep well?
How do you feel?
I'm all right.
I didn't do anything to her.
Of course you didn't.
Come have breakfast.
Can't work if you don't eat.
Work?
Ouch...
Are you getting blisters?
Yes.
Shall we rest a bit?
What a good smell.
- But...
- Yes, lad?
You're a wizard, aren't you?
Oh, I see.
You want to know why a wizard
toils in the field like a farmer?
Yes.
Listen, Arren.
Everything under the sun
and stars depends on the Balance.
The wind and seas.
The power of earth and light.
All that these do is well
and rightly done within the Equilibrium.
But now, men hold
the power to control the world.
So Man must learn
to keep the Balance...
...and do what leaf and whale
and wind do of their own nature.
You know everything
has its True Name.
Magic is the power to command,
if you know a thing's True Name.
Use that power in ignorance
and the Balance is easily damaged.
Spells should be made
only of necessity.
You've been busy.
I suppose you two
deserve some lunch.
Are you feeling better, Arren?
Now eat hearty,
or you won't get your strength back.
What about the girl?
Oh, Therru?
One of the spring lambs is sick.
She's nursing it today.
Shall we change places?
No, I can manage.
- How did it go?
- That's it for today.
Dinner will be ready soon.
Better wash up.
- I'll put the ox in the stable.
- Thanks, lad.
There, you should be feeling better.
Now you need your mother's milk.
That's it.
Good girl.
What do you want?
Oh... nothing.
Why did you come here?
To hurt me?
To kill this little one?
You don't understand!
I was just...
Stay away! Get out of here!
I hate anyone who doesn't value life!
I'm sorry.
Step aside!
Let's eat.
It's so good having men
to help with the farm.
Even you two.
I'm no good with a plow,
but I do know animals.
You used to be a goatherd.
What's wrong, Arren?
Aren't you hungry?
No.
What is this place?
Come, Arren. This way.
Sparrowhawk?
Come. Take my hand.
Arren!
No! Leave me alone! Stop!
Arren! Wake up!
Arren!
What's wrong?
A bad dream, I think.
A dream...
Spring is very short, you know.
I need all the help I can get.
I'm sorry, Tenar.
I have an errand that cannot wait.
I still can't rely on you.
Come now, Tenar.
Should you be taking Arren's horse?
He's better off without it.
Tell him I borrowed it.
Tenar. Keep a close eye
on him for me.
I promise.
I'll be back tonight!
And back at work tomorrow!
I certainly hope so.
Haven't seen him around here.
And that scar!
He must've come
from that woman's house.
She's a witch.
I don't like the looks of it.
Yes, she's an odd one.
And that little girl she keeps!
That child will bring
bad luck on us all.
No! Don't say that out loud!
Who was that?
He's not from around here.
He's a friend of ours.
He's helping us out.
Is that so?
Can I help you?
My child has a fever ma'am.
I need that potion again.
All right. Just wait there.
Quit sticking to me!
I'm afraid!
Spare us from evil!
That's enough!
There. If the child's not better,
come see me again.
Thank you kindly, ma'am.
Actually, I was wondering...
Yes, I know.
Pay me when you can.
Thanks ma'am. You're very kind.
Hope she feels better!
I wish there were more
decent people in the world.
Therru never hurt anyone.
Well, at least the woman
looks after her own.
As for Therru, her parents
abused and abandoned her.
They burned her.
That's how she got that scar.
What a frightful child!
My goodness!
Did you see her eyes?
Please, have mercy!
No one will buy
an old woman!
Nothing to fear ladies.
Maybe you can even help me.
Seen any strangers around here?
Be much obliged for any help.
And I'll pay.
There's one at Tenar's farm!
And one with a scar
on his face!
Tenar? Who's that?
The witch! She lives
right up this road.
Thanks for the help, old hags!
Wait! Where are you going?
Stop! Liar!
You promised to pay!
There it is! That's it!
What's that?
What are you doing?
You're looking fit, boy.
Didn't think I'd find you here.
Swine!
What are you doing here?
Now, now. I'm not here to fight.
Where's your wizard friend?
He's gone!
Sparrowhawk's not here.
You'd better not be hiding him.
Why should I?
You're no match for him.
Looks like she's telling the truth.
All right, we'll be back!
Till then!
Never come back, you swine!
Lord Cob will reward me for this!
So that's what happened.
Neither of you
said a word about it.
I think we fixed most of it.
Let's rebuild the fence.
Tenar? Have you known
Sparrowhawk for a long time?
Yes, I guess I have.
A long, long time.
He's always been a wanderer.
It's the life he chose.
He does it because he has to.
And finally he became Archmage,
the greatest of all wizards.
Head of the Great House of Roke?
Yes. But years before that,
he rescued me.
Rescued me, and
led me into the light.
One man, all alone.
He brought me out
of the Tombs of Atuan.
Welcome.
Don't get many wizards.
Looking for a weapon?
Show me that sword.
Can't recommend this one.
Very unusual workmanship,
so I bought it.
But it's rusted solid.
Can't be drawn.
You there, wizard!
Are you deaf?
I'm talking to you!
You said something, sir?
Is there something
stuck to my face?
Wrong wizard!
You! If you see a wizard
with a scar on his face...
...tell him Lord Cob
wants to see him!
Cob? Never heard that name
back where I come from.
You will, when he's Lord
of the Two Lands!
Don't forget it!
Yes sir.
I'll take the sword.
How much?
Wait a minute... your face!
What's wrong?
Nothing... I suppose.
Have you heard of
this wizard named Cob?
Careful! Keep your voice down.
Only wizard in these parts
who still has his powers.
Can't say he's loved
by people around here.
He lives in the fortress outside town.
Best keep away from there.
I never thought
I'd find you here, Cob.
You're good at farm work.
You hardly seem a beginner.
Thank you.
Won't you stay on
for a while and help?
Therru would like that too.
But...
You don't have to decide now.
Think about it, all right?
All right.
Stable the ox for me.
Yes, Tenar.
I'm home!
Therru? Now where is she?