Arren! I can't find Therru.
Check the back pasture for me.
Tell her to come inside
before dark.
I will.
Therru?
Therru...
Far, far above the clouds
against the setting sun
A falcon flies alone
soaring in the wind
I hear his lonely cry
so sad must he be
Riding the silent wind
a falcon flies alone
Reaching out with his wings
grasps the empty sky
Riding the silent wind
never can he rest
What it is within my heart
none can ever know
A heart like a falcon's
is this very heart
What it is within my heart
none can ever know
Lonely falcon in the empty sky
I walk alone along
deserted country roads
Walking with me side by side
you are always there
I feel your loneliness
lonely you must be
Crickets whispering
in the grassy fields
You walk there by my side
you walk the path with me
But you never say a word
never do you speak
What it is within my heart
none can ever know
Here inside this heart
that walks its path alone
What it is within my heart
none can ever know
The sadness of one
who always is alone
I killed my father.
I stabbed him and ran away.
I don't understand it.
Why did I kill him?
Did he hurt you?
No. My father
was a great man.
I am nothing. I failed my father
and I fail myself.
And yet, I'm filled
with a rage I can't control.
It's as if there were
someone else inside me.
You saw it too, didn't you?
You were right.
I shouldn't be here.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean...
No, you were right.
If I don't leave,
it will come again.
A woman?
She lives past the marshes.
And the Archmage is with her?
He was seen in the town.
There are many witnesses.
Splendid.
My lord.
Let's go, men!
A greeting from the Archmage.
Thank you, Sparrowhawk.
Therru! Arren!
Dinner is ready!
Where's Arren?
Isn't he with you?
No.
Maybe he's resting.
Therru, go see if he's there.
Yes, Tenar.
He's not here.
That's strange.
Where's he gone?
I'll look outside.
Arren...
Tenar, Therru... take care.
Doesn't matter
which way I go.
Looks like a dead end.
It's here!
I wonder if that's Arren?
Arren?
Sparrowhawk?
That's odd.
What are you doing?
It's you! You're back!
So sorry, but it seems
you'll do in place of the wizard.
What?
Tenar, what's wrong?
Run away!
What a surprise!
Fancy meeting you here, princess.
No! Leave her alone!
Therru!
Well now princess,
where's your prince?
Hey! Watch those teeth!
I need you to deliver a message.
Tell this to the wizard!
If he wants his woman...
...he can find her
at Lord Cob's castle.
Take her away!
Therru!
Tenar!
Let me go, I tell you!
Let me go!
Therru!
Are you all right? Therru!
Stop it! Let her go!
You stay here and be good
till the wizard gets back!
Lord Cob's waiting.
Let's get moving!
Tenar!
I'm sorry. I'm afraid
he's coming with me.
Go!
Where am I?
You're safe now.
The Shadow can't follow you here.
You saw it?
I know a bit of Magic myself.
I know what
you're running from.
You were wise
to flee from that man.
What man?
Sparrowhawk.
That is, the Archmage.
Here, drink this.
It will soothe you.
What's wrong?
It's not poisoned.
Now lie still
and rest here for a bit.
The Archmage is more dangerous
than you can imagine.
No... Sparrowhawk is a good man.
He protected me.
Then tell me. Did you ever
wonder what he seeks?
No.
He seeks eternal life.
Eternal life?
The Archmage stands
at the pinnacle of sorcery.
Only the secret of eternal life
lies beyond his grasp.
And yet, he covets it.
But as he covets, so does he fear
another will discover it first.
That would be unbearable
to one so proud as the Archmage.
What does that have
to do with me?
Because it is you
who have been chosen...
...to gain the secret
of eternal life.
That's why Sparrowhawk
follows you. To kill you.
To bring me death...
Arren, will you come with me?
I've already found it.
I found the door
between life and death.
Together we can open that door.
And together,
we will live forever.
We will conquer every form
of fear and suffering.
Fear and suffering...
Come with me, Arren.
The face of death is terrible!
I don't want to die.
Listen to me, Arren.
Tell me your True Name.
Then you will have that
which you most desire.
Come, give me your True Name.
Lebannen...
Now I'm ready for you,
Sparrowhawk.
Where are you, Hawk?
Hawk!
What's wrong, Therru?
They came and took
Tenar away!
You have to go
to Cob's castle!
Where is Arren?
He left! He said it would
come again if he didn't go!
Cob...
Don't worry, Therru.
I'm going to help Tenar.
Wait for my return.
Keep this sword.
Arren will need it.
Stay home, Therru!
Here-we-are!
Come on!
I'm not going anywhere!
Lord Cob.
We brought the woman.
Just as you ordered.
You've done well, Hare.
It was nothing, my lord.
My pleasure is to serve you.
Stand aside!
Why, you!
Are you the boss?
Why did you kidnap me?
Let me go right now!
So sorry for the rough treatment.
I have business with Sparrowhawk.
You're a wizard, aren't you!
You should be ashamed!
Go find him yourself!
He's an old friend of mine.
I'd like to invite him here.
And I'm the bait!
You're going to hurt him!
Women tax my patience.
Put her in the dungeon.
Do it!
Answer me!
If something happens to
Sparrowhawk, so help me!
- Arren...
- This way!
Come, Lebannen.
I have something special for you.
Get in there!
Make yourself at home.
You'll see your wizard soon enough.
This place reminds me
of the Tombs.
Sparrowhawk...
Cob! Are you making
the same mistake again?
At ease!
Any sign of the wizard?
Not yet, sir.
Where is that confounded wizard?
Let's see...
There he is!
Take your positions!
Here he comes!
Don't let him escape! Now!
Hear me! Open the path!
Stop! Wait!
He tricked us!
Well? Don't just stand there!
Cob! It's Sparrowhawk.
I'm here!
Show yourself!
It's been a long time,
Sparrowhawk.
I've been waiting.
Cob of Havnor!
I left you at the border...
...of the land of death.
I hear you're the Archmage now.
Congratulations.
I'm here, Cob.
Now release Tenar!
You're pitiful, Sparrowhawk.
The great Archmage,
smitten by a woman.
You used her to lure me here.
What do you want?
What do you think?
I haven't forgotten
how you dragged me...
...to the gates of the Dry Land.
But you've forgotten why!
You used
the Pelnish Lore...
...to toy with the spirits
of the living and the dead.
Isn't that enough to repent?
You taught me a splendid lesson
there at death's door.
Now I know I can
never accept extinction.
So I gathered every
ancient lore book I could find.
Alas, some of their owners
were not cooperative.
What evil are you planning, Cob?
I've done it, Sparrowhawk!
I've woven the greatest spell of all.
The door between life and death
has been closed...
...since the beginning of time.
But I will open it!
That is forbidden!
Don't you understand?
Those with power
must wield it with wisdom.
Would you destroy the Balance
that sustains the world?
What nonsense!
The Balance is long gone.
You know that
better than anyone.
The Balance was destroyed by Man.
You think you can limit
Man's desire? It's impossible!
I will live forever.
I will gain existence without end!
Cob! Without the cycle
of death and rebirth, there is no life!
I am above Nature!
Sparrowhawk! There's someone else
who wants to meet you.
Arren! What are you doing here?
Lebannen! This man would
deprive you of eternal life!
Arren! Did you reveal
your True Name?
I'm going to live forever!
I'm tired, Sparrowhawk.
Tired of living in fear.
Arren! Life without death is not life!
Refuse death, and
you refuse life as well!
Don't lie to me!
Listen to me, Arren.
No man nor any thing
in this world lives forever.
But only to us is it given
to know that we must die.
And that is a precious gift.
This life that is our torment
and our treasure does not endure.
It is a wave on the sea.
Would you force the sea
to grow still, to save one wave?
To save yourself?
Arren...
Thought you made
a fool of me?
There's more than
one entrance to this castle!
What's happening?
I'm getting weak.
Coming here was another
of your blunders, Sparrowhawk.
Your powers are useless
in this place.
Hare! Put him in the
dungeon with the woman.
I'll finish them tomorrow...
...in the most painful
and humiliating way.
Yes, my lord.
On your feet, chickenhawk!
Sparrowhawk!
Sparrowhawk! Are you all right?
It'll all be over tomorrow.
Say your goodbyes
while you still have time!
Sparrowhawk! Sparrowhawk!
Tenar...
How did they do this?
You're the Archmage!
I'm sorry, Tenar.
I keep getting you into trouble.
Stop talking nonsense!
Which way should I go?
Arren?
Arren! Wait!
Arren! Cob's men came
and took Tenar away!
I have your sword!
Sparrowhawk said
to give it to you!
Follow you?
Tenar is a prisoner here.
Sparrowhawk too.
Even Sparrowhawk.
This is yours, isn't it?
Sparrowhawk brought it for you.
We've got to hurry.
They need our help!
I can go no further.
You must go alone.
Bring me that sword.
I know you can do it.
What do you mean?
You're right here.
I'm not here.
Cob is holding me
against my will.
Then who are you?
Stay away! Get back!
Don't come closer!
Arren's heart was always
full of fear.
The fear filled his heart
with darkness.
Fear of what?
The darkness stole his body
and ran away with it.
But it left something
important behind.
Wherever there is darkness,
there also you will find light.
Now the light
that was left behind...
...wanders alone,
like a shadow.
A shadow?
What you see now is just
a shadow chasing its body.
Father...
You are Arren, aren't you?
Don't worry.
I'll be with you.
I'll give you my True Name.
My True Name
is Lebannen... Lebannen.
Lebannen...
It's him.
He should be ashamed
to call himself Archmage!
Remember who
he was up against.
No wizard in Earthsea
is a match for Lord Cob!
Well spoken!
By the way, what's our
little friend up to?
He shut himself in his room.
Arren's really here!
He's a lucky one, that boy.
It's just like Lord Cob
to steal the wizard's apprentice.
He's not much
use though, is he?
None at all.
When we're through with
the wizard, we'll sell the boy!
All right! Go get
Sparrowhawk and his woman.
The Archmage's time
has finally run out!
They're going to kill them.
Arren!
Arren?
What are you doing here?
Did they kidnap you too?
Here. This belongs to you.
I'm not worthy to hold
my father's sword.
Arren, they've got Tenar
and Sparrowhawk.
They're going to kill them.
Please! Help them
like you helped me!
I can't help anyone.
All I can do is fail.
What's wrong with you?
They'll die
if we don't do something!
They'll die!
We'll lose both of them!
We'll lose the most important
thing in the world.
Therru?
What's the most important thing?
Life is the most important thing!
We'll all die someday.
What does it matter?
Why fight for life?
We know it's going to end anyway.
No! Life is precious because
we know we're going to die!
You're not afraid of death.
You're afraid of life!
You want to live forever,
then you say nothing matters.
It's the same thing!
You're afraid to live
the only life you have!
Therru...
You think your life
belongs to you?
Tenar gave me life.
That's why I have to live...
...to give life to someone else.
Lebannen...
That's the only way
we live forever.
Therru... how did you know
my True Name?
You told me yourself.
Now I'll tell you mine.
My True Name is...
Tehanu... it's Tehanu.
Tehanu...
It'll be dawn soon.
Come on, Therru.
We've got to help them!
Arren, wait!
What is it?
There!
It's Sparrowhawk and Tenar!
Come on!
Jump!
I can't! It's too far!
Don't worry!
You can do it!
Let's go!
Sparrowhawk!
Time to say goodbye,
Sparrowhawk.
Your lover is going
on a journey.
Why don't you
send him off yourself?
Don't worry, Sparrowhawk.
This world will be
in good hands after you're gone.
What can I do, Sparrowhawk?
Tenar.
It's not over yet.
The sun will rise soon.
What do you mean?
Don't you hear it, Tenar?
Help is almost here.
That's enough time
for goodbyes.
Do it! Finish him!
No!
Let them go!
It's you!
Arren! Therru!
Stay out of this, boy!
Don't show him any mercy!
Get back!
Take him!
Please don't hurt me!
I'm disappointed.
I thought you
and I had an understanding.
Silence!
You don't control me any ore.
Then you shall see
the face of death, Lebannen!
A summoning spell!
Arren!
Stay back!
Now die!
Please! Let me draw it.
For Life!
That sword was
forged with magic!
He's an old man!
Disguised by sorcery.
Lord Cob!
You can't stop me.
I will never accept death.
Wizards shouldn't fear death!
You wretched girl!
I'm not like you!
I'm better than you.
Insignificant worms!
I studied the wisdom of the ages!
I wield power! I am almighty!
Scorned as a fool by
the wizards of Roke.
Driven out like a dog!
But I'll have my revenge.
I will never die.
I'll be the supreme Archmage!
Therru!
That little fool!
Hear me, stones.
I unbind you!
Sunrise...
Let me go!
Does it hurt, girl?
Cob!
Let her go!
Stay back!
Death is terrifying!
Don't do it!
So terrifying.
Wait!
So terrifying... very terrifying...
Cob! You're just like me.
You turn away from light
and see only darkness!
No! Keep away!
You forgot that all life
is connected.
Life can't be hoarded,
it can only be given!
Deny death,
and you deny life!
No! You're wrong!
Face the truth, Cob!
Everyone fears death!
No! I don't want to die.
Cob!
No!
Therru!
Therru... Arren...
Arren!
Time to die! Time to die!
And you will join him.
Let her go! Don't kill her!
All who oppose me must die!
She's dead, she's dead.
Poor thing.
Sun is rising.
Hurry... must hurry...
Stop!
Therru!
Eternal life!
Shadow, return to darkness!
Give me life!
I want life... life!
Life!
I want to live!
Tehanu!
So you're safe too.
What about them?
They'll be fine.
They have wings.
Thank you... Therru.
I'm going back
to pay for my crime.
And to face myself.
Arren.
Can I come to see you
again someday?
Come on.
We have to thank
Sparrowhawk and Tenar.
The lone hawk in the sky
Struggles against the wind
Here there is only light and darkness
He has the sky to himself
You who looked up to the sky and wept
You who live alone
Let me hear your True Name
For one day you'll be gone
As light dissolves into darkness
Your song passes straight
through my heart
Let me sing it for you
The End
Voices
Junichi OKADA
Aoi TESHIMA
Yuko TANAKA
Teruyuki KAGAWA
Jun FUBUKI
Bunta SUGAWARA
Based on the "Earthsea" series by
Ursula K. LE GUIN
Inspired by "Shuna's Journey" by
Hayao MIYAZAKI
Screenplay by
Goro MIYAZAKI and Keiko NIWA
Music by
Tamiya TERASHIMA
Theme song performed by
Aoi TESHIMA
English translation by
Jim HUBBERT
Evan MA, Kenzo OCHIAI,
Rieko IZUTSU and Steve ALPERT
English subtitles by
Aura and Nippon Cine Arts
Production
Studio Ghibli
Producer
Toshio SUZUKI
Directed by
Goro MIYAZAKI