Sometimes, I think I'm cursed.
'Cause of something that happened
before I was even born.
See, a long time ago,
there was this family.
The Papá, he was a musician.
He and his family
would sing and dance
and count their blessings.
But he also had a dream.
To play for the world.
And one day...
he left with his guitar...
and never returned.
And my Mamá...
She didn't have time to cry
over that walk-away musician.
After banishing all music
from her life...
she found a way
to provide for her daughter.
She rolled up her sleeves...
and she learned to make shoes.
She could have made candy.
O-o-or fireworks.
Or sparkly underwear for wrestlers.
But no.
She chose shoes.
Then she taught
her daughter to make shoes.
And later, she taught
her son-in-law.
Then her grandkids got roped in.
As her family grew,
so did the business.
Music have torn
her family apart.
But shoes held
them all together.
You see that woman...
was my great-great-grandmother...
Mamá Imelda.
She died way before I was born.
But my family still
tells her story...
every year. And her little girl...
she's my great-grandmother,
Mamá Coco.
Hola, Mamá Coco.
How are you, Julio?
Actually, my name is Miguel.
Mamá Coco has trouble
remembering things.
But it's good to talk to her,
anyway.
So, I tell her
pretty much everything.
I used to run like this.
But now I run like this,
it's just way faster.
The winner is...
luchadora Coco!
I have a dimple on this side,
but not on this side.
Dimple, no dimple.
Miguel, eat your food.
My abuelita, she's
Mamá Coco's daughter.
Aw, you're a twig, mijo.
Have some more.
No, gracias.
I asked if you would like
more tamales.
S-Si?
That's what I thought you said!
Abuelita runs the house
just as Mamá Imelda did.
No music!
♪ aunque la vida ♪
I think we're the only family
in Mexico who hates music.
And my family's fine with that.
But me...
Be back by lunch, mijo.
Love you, Mamá!
I'm not like the rest
of my family.
- Hola, Miguel.
- Hola.
- Muchas gracias!
- De nada, Miguel!
He-hey, Dante!
Sit.
Down.
Roll over.
Shake.
Fist bump.
Good boy, Dante!
I know, I'm not supposed
to love music.
But it's not my fault.
It's his.
Ernesto de la Cruz.
The greatest musician
of all time.
Here in this very plaza,
the young Ernesto de la Cruz
took his first steps
toward becoming
the most beloved singer
in Mexican history.
He started out a total nobody
from Santa Cecilia, like me.
But when he played music,
he made people
fall in love with him.
He starred in movies.
He had the coolest guitar.
He could fly!
And he wrote the best songs.
But my all-time favorite is...
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Though I have to say goodbye ♪
♪ Me ♪
Until 1942.
When he was crushed
by a giant bell.
I wanna be just like him.
Sometimes, I look at de la Cruz...
and I get this feeling.
Like we're connected somehow.
Like if he could play music...
maybe someday, I could too!
If it wasn't for my family.
Ay, ay, ay, muchacho!
Huh?
I asked for a shoe shine,
not your life story.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
I just can't really talk about
any of this at home, so.
Look, if I were you,
I'd march right up
to my family and say,
"Hey, I'm a musician.
Deal with it!"
I could never say that.
You are a musician, no?
I-I-I don't know.
I mean, I only really
play for myself.
Ah! Did de la Cruz become
the world's best musician
by hiding his sweet,
sweet skills?
No!
He walked out onto that plaza
and he played out loud!
Ah, Mira, Mira, they're
setting up for tonight.
The music competition for
Día de Muertos.
You wanna be like your hero?
You should sign up!
Unh-unh. My family would freak!
Look, if you're too scared,
then, well, have fun making shoes.
Come on, what did
de la Cruz always say?
Seize your moment?
Show me what you got,
muchacho.
I'll be your first audience.
Miguel!
Ah!
Abuelita!
What are you doing here?
Um... oh... uh...
You leave my grandson alone!
Doña, please! I was just
getting a shine.
I know your tricks, mariachi.
What did he say to you?
He was just showing me
his guitar.
Shame on you!
My grandson is a
is a sweet little
angelito, perrito, cielito!
He wants no part
of your music, mariachi.
You keep away from him.
Y-ay!
Ay, pobrecito!
Estas bien, mijo.
You know better than
to be here in this place.
You will come home.
Now.
How many times
have we told you?
That plaza is crawling
with mariachis.
Yes, Tío Berto.
No, no, no, no, no.
Hey, go away, you. Go!
It's just Dante.
Never name a street dog.
They'll follow you forever.
Now, go get my shoe.
I found your son in
Mariachi Plaza.
Ay, Miguel?
You know how abuelita
feels about the plaza.
I was just shining shoes.
A musician's shoes.
But the plaza's where
the foot traffic is.
If abuelita says, "No more plaza",
then no more plaza.
But what about tonight?
What's tonight?
Well, they're having
this talent show.
- A-and I thought I might...
- Sign up?
Well, maybe?
You have to have talent
to be in a talent show.
What are you gonna do?
Shine shoes? Oh!
It's Día de los Muertos.
No one's going any where.
Tonight is about family.
Ofrenda room. Vámonos.
Don't give me that look.
Día de los Muertos is the
one night of the year
our ancestors can come visit us.
We put their photos
on the ofrenda
so their spririts can cross over.
That is very important.
If we don't put them up,
they can't come.
We made all this food.
Set out the things
they loved in life, mijo.
All this work to
bring the family together.
I don't want you sneaking off
to who-knows-where.
Huh! Where are you going?
- I thought we were done.
- Ay, Dios mío.
Being part of this family means
being here for this family.
I don't want to see you
end up like...
Like Mamá Coco's papá?
Never mention that man!
He's better off forgotten.
- But you're the one who...
- Eh, thchhsss!
- I was just...
- Tchsshh!
- But...
- Tchshh.
- I...
- Shhh.
Papá?
Papá is home?
Mamá, cálmese, cálmese.
Papá is coming home?
No, Mamá, it's okay.
I'm here.
Who are you?
Ay... rest, Mamá.
I'm hard on you
because I care, Miguel.
Miguel?
Ay.
What are we going to do
with that boy?
Ha ha ha, you're right.
That's just what he needs.
Huah!
Oh, it's you. Get in here.
Come on, Dante. Hurry up.
You're gonna get me
in trouble, boy.
Someone can hear me.
I wish someone
wanted to hear me.
Other than you.
Ew, okay!
Perfecto.
I have to sing.
I have to play.
The music, it's...
it's not just in me.
It is me.
When life gets me down.
I play my guitar.
The rest of the world may
follow the rules, but I...
must follow my heart.
Ugh.
You know that feeling...
like there's a song in the air
and it's playing just for you?
♪ A feeling so close ♪
♪ You could reach out
and touch it ♪
♪ I never knew ♪
♪ I could want something
so much ♪
♪ But it's true ♪
You must have faith, sister.
Oh, but Padre,
he will never listen.
He will listen to music!
♪ Only a song, only a song ♪
♪ Has the power
to change a heart ♪
Never underestimate
the power of music.
But my father,
he will never give
his permission.
I am done
asking permission.
When you see your moment,
you mustn't let it pass you by.
You must seize it.
Señor de la Cruz,
what did it take for you
to seize your moment?
I had to have faith
in my dream.
No one was going to hand it to me.
It was up to me to
reach for that dream.
Grab it tight...
and make it come true.
No more hiding, Dante.
I gotta seize my moment.
I'm gonna play in Mariachi Plaza
if it kills me.
Día de Muertos has begun!
No, no, no, no, no.
We have to make a clear path.
The petals guide
our ancestors home.
- Mamá!
- Hunh!
Where should we put this table?
In the courtyard, mijos.
You want it down
by the kitchen?
Si, eh, next to the other one.
Get under, get under!
Miguel?
Uh, nothing.
Mamá, Papá, I...
Miguel, your abuelita have
the most wonderful idea.
We've all decided...
it's time you joined us
in the workshop!
What?
No more shining shoes.
You will be making them,
every day, after school.
Oh, our Miguelitititito
carrying on the family tradition.
And on Día de los Muertos!
Your ancestors
would be so proud.
You'll craft huaraches
just like your Tía Victoria.
And wing tips just like
your Papá Julio.
But what if I'm no good
at making shoes?
Ay, Miguel.
You have your family here
to guide you.
You are a Rivera.
And a Rivera is?
A shoemaker...
through and through.
That's my boy!
Haha! Berto!
Break out the good stuff!
Mm, mm, mm, mwah!
Dante!
No, Dante, stop!
Hunh!
Ah!
No, no, no, no, no!
No.
De la Cruz' guitar?
Ah?
Papá?
Mamá Coco.
Is your papá Ernesto de la Cruz?
Papá! Papá!
Haha!
Papá, Papá!
It's him!
I know who my
great-great-grandfather was!
Miguel, get down from there.
Mamá Coco's father
was Ernesto de la Cruz!
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna be a musician!
What is all this?
You keep secrets
from your own family?
It's all that time he spends
in the plaza.
Fills his head
with crazy fantasies.
It's not a fantasy.
That man was
Ernesto de la Cruz.
The greatest musician
of all time.
We've never known
anything about this man.
Or whoever he was,
he still abandoned his family.
It's no future for my son.
Well, Papá, y-you said
my family would guide me.
Well, de la Cruz is my family.
I'm supposed to play music.
Never! That man's music
was a curse.
I will not allow it.
- If you would just...
- Miguel.
You will listen to your family.
No more music.
Just listen to me play.
End of argument.
You want to end up
like that man?
Forgotten?
Left off your family's ofrenda?
I don't care if I'm on some
stupid ofrenda.
- Hunh!
- No!
- Mamá!
There.
No guitar.
No music.
Aw, come.
You'll feel better after
you eat with your family.
I don't wanna be in this family!
Miguel, Miguel!
I-I wanna play in the plaza.
Like de la Cruz.
C-can I still sign up?
You got an instrument?
No. But if I can borrow a guitar.
Musicians gotta bring
their own instruments.
You find a guitar, kid,
I'll put you on the list.
Hey, excuse me,
can I borrow your guitar?
Sorry, muchaco.
You guys have a spare guitar?
No.
I need a guitar
just for a little bit.
Get outta here, kid.
Great-great-grandfather.
What am I supposed to do?
No, no, no, no.
Dante, stop.
Cállate, shh.
I'm sorry.
Señor de la Cruz.
Please don't be mad.
I-I'm Miguel.
Your great-great-grandson.
I-I need to borrow this.
Our family thinks
music is a curse.
None of them understand.
But I know you would have.
You would have told me
to follow my heart.
To seize my moment.
So, if it's all right with you...
I'm gonna play in the Plaza.
Just like you did!
Huh?
What's going on?
Somebody stole
de la Cruz' guitar.
The window is broken, look!
All right, who's in there?
I'm sorry, i-it's not
what it looks like.
De la Cruz is my...
Huh!
There's nobody here!
- Miguel!
- Mamá!
Miguel, come home!
Dios mio, little boy!
Are you okay?
Here, let me help you.
Thanks. I...
- Aaah!
Aah!
Do you mind?
- Aah!
Look how big she's getting.
Uh! Dante?
You can see me?
Wait! What's going on?
Dante! Dante!
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Miguel?
- Miguel?
Y-you're here!
Here here.
And you can see us?
Our Miguelitititito!
Remind me how I know you?
We're your family, mijo.
Tía Rosita?
Si.
Papá Julio?
Hola!
Tía Vic...toria?
He doesn't seem
entirely dead.
He's not quite alive, either.
We need Mamá Imelda.
She'll know how to fix this.
Oye!
It's Mamá Imelda!
She couldn't cross over!
She's stuck!
On the other side!
Tío Oscar?
Tío Felipe?
Oh, hey, Miguel.
I have a feeling this has
something to do with you.
But if Mamá Imelda
can't come to us...
Then we are going to her!
- Whoa!
- Vámonos!
Whoa.
Come on, Miguel, it's-it's okay.
Dante?
Dante!
Dante, wait up!
You've gotta stay with me, boy.
You don't know...
where...
This isn't a dream, then.
You're all really out there.
You thought we weren't?
Oh, I don't know.
I thought it might have been
one of those made-up things...
that adults tell kids, like...
vitamins.
Miguel, vitamins
are a real thing.
Well, now I'm thinking
maybe they could be.
Hunh!
Mija, it's not nice to stare at...
Ay, Santa Ma...
Are those?
Alebrijes!
- But those are...
- Real alebrijes.
Spirit creatures.
They guide souls
on their journey.
Watch your step,
they make cacitas everywhere.
Welcome back
to the Land of the Dead.
Please have all offerings
ready for re-entry.
Welcome back.
Anything to declare?
Some churros, from my family.
How wonderful!
If you're experiencing
travel issues...
Agents at the Department of
Family Reunion
are available to assist you.
Next family, please.
Oh, your photos are
in your son's ofrenda.
Have a great visit.
- Gracias.
And remember to return
before sunrise.
Enjoy your visit!
Next?
Your photo's on your
dentist's ofrenda.
Enjoy your visit.
Grashiash.
Next?
Yes, it is I, Frida Kahlo.
Shall we skip the scanner?
I'm on so many ofrendas
it will just overwhelm your
blinky thingy.
Whoa, shoot.
Looks like no one
put up your photo...
Frida?
Okay, when I said
I was Frida, just now...
That.
That was a lie.
And I apologize for doing that.
No photo on an ofrenda,
no crossing the bridge.
You know what?
I'm just gonna zip right over.
You won't even know I'm gone.
Haha!
Almost... there...
Just a little... further...
Ugh.
Upsy daisy.
Fine. Okay. Fine, who cares?
Dumb flower bridge!
Aw, I don't know what I'd do
if no one put up my photo.
Next?
Oh, come mijo, it's our turn.
Welcome back, amigo.
Anything to declare?
A-as a matter of fact...
Yes.
Hola.
Paging Marta Gonzalez Ramos...
Marta Gonzalez Ramos...
Please report to level seven.
Whoa.
I miss my nose.
Come on, help us out, amigo.
We gotta get to a
dozen ofrendas tonight.
We are not visiting
your ex-wife, Stanley,
por Día de Muertos.
I demand to speak to the
person in charge.
I'm sorry, señora, it says here
no one put up your photo.
My family always, always
put my photo up in the ofrenda
That devil box tells you
nothing but lies.
Mamá Imelda?
Oh, mi familia.
They wouldn't let me
cross the bridge.
Tell this woman and her
devil box
that my photo is in the ofrenda.
Well, w-we never
made it to the ofrenda.
What?
We ran into a...
um...
Hunh! Miguel?
Mamá Imelda.
What is going on?
You the Rivera family?
Well, you're cursed.
What?
Día de los Muertos
is a night to give to the dead.
You stole from the dead.
But I wasn't sealing the guitar.
Guitar?
It was my
great-great-grandfather's.
He would have
wanted me to have it.
Ah-ah-ah! We do not speak
of that musician.
He is dead to this family.
Uh, you're all dead.
Achoo!
I am sorry, uh,
who's alebrije is that?
That's Dante.
He sure doesn't look
like an alebrije.
He just looks like
a plain old dog.
Or a sausage someone
dropped in a barbershop.
Whatever he is, I am-
achoo!
terribly allergic.
But Dante doesn't have any hair.
And I don't have a nose
and yet here we are.
Achoo!
But none of this explains
why I couldn't cross over.
Oh...
You took my photo
off the ofrenda?
It was an accident.
How do we send him back?
Well, since it's a family matter...
The way to undo a family curse is
to get your family's blessing.
That's it?
Get your family's blessing
and everything should
go back to normal.
But you've gotta do it by sunrise.
What happens at sunrise?
Híjole, your hand!
Huh!
Whoa, Miguel.
Can't have you fainting on us.
But not to worry.
Your family is here.
You can get your
blessing right now.
Cempasuchil, cempasuchil.
Aha!
Perdón, señora.
Oh.
Now, you look at the living
and say his name.
Miguel.
Nailed it.
Now say,
"I give you my blessing."
I give you my blessing.
I give you my blessing
to go home...
To put my photo back
on the ofrenda...
And to never play music again.
What? She can't do that!
Well, technically, she can add
any condition she wants.
Fine.
Then you
hand the petal to Miguel.
Ha!
No skeletons.
Mariachi Plaza, here I come.
Two seconds and you
already break your promise.
This isn't fair, it's my life.
You already had yours.
Papá Julio,
I ask for your blessing.
Tía Rosita?
Oscar?
Felipe?
Tía Victoria?
Don't make this hard, mijo.
You go home my way,
or no way.
You really hate music
that much?
I will not let you go down
the same path he did.
The same path he did.
He's family.
Listen to your Mamá Imelda.
She's just looking out for you.
Be reasonable.
Con permiso,
I need to visit the rest room.
Be right back.
Ah, should we tell him
there are no restrooms
in the Land of the Dead?
Vámonos.
We got a family looking
for a living boy.
I wanna be a musician,
I need a musician's blessing.
We gotta find my
great-great-grandpa.
Hold it, muchaco.
Huh!
I found that little boy!
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me, folks.
Excuse me.
Oh.
Dante.
Disturbing the peace.
Fleeing an officer.
Falsifying a unibrow.
That's illegal?
Very illegal.
You need to clean up
your act, amigo.
Amigo?
Oh, that's-that's so nice
to hear you say that because
I have just had a really
hard Día de Muertos
and I could really use
an amigo right now.
And amigos, they help
their amigos.
Listen, you get me across
that bridge tonight...
and I'll make it
worth your while.
You like de la Cruz?
He and I go way back.
I can get you front row seats
to his sunrise spectacular show.
I-I'll get you backstage.
You can meet him.
You just gotta let me
cross that bridge.
I should lock you up
for the rest of the holiday.
But my shift's almost up and...
I wanna visit my living family.
So I'm letting you off
with a warning.
Can I at least
get my costume back?
Uh... no.
Ser maldito.
Hey.
Hey!
You really know de la Cruz?
Who wants to... ah! Ay!
You're alive!
Yeah, I'm alive.
And I want to get back to
the Land of the Living...
I need de la Cruz' blessing.
That's weirdly specific.
He's my great-great-grandfather.
He's your gr-gr-gr-
what?
Ew.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait.
Hunh!
Wait. No. Wait, wait, wait, wait
Wait, uh, wait,
Wait, uh, wait, wait,
Wait, uh, wait, wait, wait,
Wait, uh, wait, wait, wait, wait,
Wait, uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
Wait, uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Yes! You're going back
to the Land of the Living!
You know what? Maybe this
isn't such a good...
Niño, niño, I can help you.
You can help me.
We can help each other.
But most importantly,
you can help me.
- Miguel!
- Huh!
- I'm Héctor.
- That's nice.
Esperame, chamaco!
Ay! He is going
to get himself killed!
I need my spirit guide...
Pepita.
Who has that petal
Miguel touched?
Here... n-nice alebrije.
Hey, hey, hold still.
Look up, look up.
A ver, a ver.
Look up, up, up!
Okay.
Eh. Ta-da!
Dead as a doorknob.
So listen, Miguel.
This place runs on memories.
When you're well remembered,
people put up your photo...
and you get to cross the bridge
and visit the living on
Día de Muertos.
Unless you're me.
You don't get to cross over?
No one's ever put up my picture.
But you can change that!
This is you?
Eh, Muy guapo, eh?
So, you get me to my
great-great-grandpa...
Then I put up your photo
when I get home?
Such a smart boy!
Yes! Great idea, yes!
One hiccup, de la Cruz
is a tough guy to get to...
and I need to cross that
bridge soon. Like tonight.
So, you got any other
family here, you know?
Someone a bit more, eh,
accessible?
Um... nope.
Don't yank my chain, chamaco.
You gotta have
some other family.
Only de la Cruz.
If you can't help me,
I'll find him myself.
Ugh. Okay, okay, kid.
Fine, fine.
I'll get you to your
great-great-grandpa.
It's not gonna be easy,
you know.
You know, he's a-
he's a busy man.
Wait, what are you doing?
I'm walking like a skeleton.
Blending in.
No. Skeletons don't
walk like that.
It's how you walk.
No, I don't.
Stop it!
Whoa!
Ernesto de la Cruz'
Sunrise Spectacular?
Que padre?
Wuacch, every year,
your great-great-grandpa
puts on that dumb show
to mark the end of Día de Muertos.
A-a-and you can get us in!
I'm...
Hey, you said you had
front-row tickets!
That...
that was a lie.
I apologize for that.
Cool off, chamaco, come on.
I'll get you to him.
How?
'Cause I happen to know
where he's rehearsing.
Ugh.
You better have
my dress, Héctor.
Hola, Ceci!
Ay!
Hola.
Cezi!
I lost the dress.
Ay, diosa Mia!
I've got to dress 40 dancers
by sunrise.
- And thanks to you...
- Cezi, Cezi...
- I'm one Frida short
- Cezi...
of an opening number.
- Dante.
Dante!
We shouldn't be in here.
Dante! Ven acá!
You!
How did you get in here?
I-I just followed my...
Hunh! Oh, the mighty Xolo dog!
Guider of wandering spirits.
And whose spirit
have you guided to me?
I don't think he's a spirit guide.
Uh-uh-uh! The alebrijes of this
world can take many forms.
They are as mysterious
as they are powerful.
Or maybe he's just a dog.
Come! I need your eyes.
Your are the audience.
Darkness!
And from the darkness...
A giant papaya!
Dancers emerge from the papaya.
And the dancers...
Are all me!
And they go to drink
from the milk of their mother.
Who is a cactus.
But who is also me!
And her milk is not milk...
but tears.
Is it too obvious?
I think it's just the
right amount of obvious.
It could use some music.
Oh, what if you did like...
Tun-tun-tun-tun-tun?
Oh, and then it could go...
Darala-dalala-dalala-dalala
Whenk?
And what if everything was on fire?
Yes! Fire everywhere!
Inspired.
You. You have
the spirit of an artist.
The dancers exit. The music fades.
The lights go out.
And Ernesto de la Cruz
rises to the stage.
Huh?
He does a couple of songs.
The sun rises. Everyone cheers.
Excuse me, where's
the real de la Cruz?
Ernesto doesn't do rehearsals.
He's too busy hosting that
fancy party at the top of his tower.
Chamaco, you can't
run off on me like that.
Come on, stop pestering
the celebrities.
You said my great-great-grandpa
would be here.
He's halfway across town
throwing some big party.
That bum. Who doesn't show up
to his own rehearsal?
If you're such good friends,
how come he didn't invite you?
He's your great-great-grandpa.
How come he didn't invite you?
Hey, Gustavo! You know
anything about this party?
Sh-it's the hot ticket!
But if you're not on the guest list,
you're never gettin' in,
Chorizo.
Hey, it's Chorizo!
Ah-ha, very funny, guys.
Very funny.
Chorizo?
Oh, this guy's famous.
Go on, go on.
Ask him how he died.
I-I don't wanna talk about it.
He choked on some chorizo!
I didn't choke, okay?
I got food poisoning
which is a big difference.
This is why I don't like musicians.
Bunch of self-important jerks!
Hey, I'm a musician.
- You are?
- Well...
If you really wanna get to Ernesto...
there is that music competition
at the Plaza de la Cruz.
Winner gets to play at his party.
No, no, no, Chamaco!
You are loco if you think...
I need to get my great-great-
grandfather's blessing.
You know where
I can get a guitar?
Ay... I know a guy.
Have you found him, Pepita?
Have you found our boy?
A footprint!
It's a Rivera boot.
- Size seven!
- And a half.
- Pronated.
- Miguel.
Why the heck would you
wanna be a musician?
My great-great-grandfather's
a musician.
Who spent his life performing like
a monkey for complete strangers?
Blech! No, no, thank you, no.
What do you know?
So, how far is this guitar, anyway?
We're almost there.
Keep up, chamaco, come on!
Cousin Héctor!
Hey! These guys!
Héctor!
Hey, tío, qué onda?
These people are all you family?
Eh... yeah, in a way.
We're all the ones with
no photos or ofrendas.
No family to go home to.
Nearly forgotten, you know?
So we all call each other
"cousin" or "tío" or-or whatever.
- Héctor!
- Tía Chelos! Hey!
Muchas gracias.
Save some for me.
Is Chicharrón around?
In the bungalow. I don't know if
he's in the mood for visitors.
Ah, who doesn't like a
visit from cousin Héctor?
Huh!
Buenas noches, Chicharrón.
I don't want to see your
stupid face, Héctor.
Come on, its Día de Muertos.
I brought you a little offering.
Get outta here!
I would Chich, but the thing is...
me and my friend Miguel...
we really need to
borrow your guitar.
- My guitar?
- Yes.
My prized, beloved guitar?
I promise we'll bring it right back.
Like the time you promised
to bring back my van?
Eh...
- Or my mini fridge?
- Oh, you see...
Or my good napkins,
my lasso, my femur?!
No, not like those things.
Where's my femur, you...
Oh, oh.
You okay, amigo?
I'm fading, Héctor.
I can feel it.
I couldn't even play that
thing if I wanted to.
You, play me something.
Oh, you know I don't
play anymore, Chich.
The guitar's for the kid.
You want it?
You've got to earn it.
Ay, only for you, amigo.
Any requests?
You know my favorite, Héctor.
♪ Well, everyone knows Juanita ♪
♪ Her eyes each a different color ♪
♪ Her teeth stick out ♪
♪ And her chin goes in ♪
♪ And her... ♪
♪ Knuckles they drag on the floor ♪
Those aren't the words.
There are children present.
♪ Her hair is like a brier ♪
♪ She stands in a
bow-legged stance ♪
♪ And if I weren't so ugly ♪
♪ She'd possibly
give me a chance ♪
Brings back memories.
Gracias.
Wait, what happened?
He's been forgotten.
When there's no one left in the
living world who remembers you...
you disappear from this world.
We call it "The Final Death."
W-where did he go?
No one knows.
But I've met him.
I could remember him...
when I go back.
No, it doesn't work
like that, chamaco.
Our memories...
They have to be passed down
by those who knew us in life.
In the stories
they tell about us.
But there's no one left alive
to pass down Chich's stories.
Hey, it happens to
everyone eventually.
Come on, de la Cruzito,
you've got a contest to win.
You told me you hated musicians.
You never said you were one.
How do you think I knew
your great-great-grandpa?
We used to play music together.
Taught him everything he knows.
No manches.
You played with
Ernesto de la Cruz?
The greatest musician
of all time?
Oh! Oh, you're funny.
Greatest eyebrows
of all time, maybe.
But his music, eh, not so much.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Welcome to the Plaza de la Cruz.
Showtime, chamaco.
Querer lo, t-shirts, bobbleheads.
Bienvenidos a todos!
Ow! ha-hah-ay!
Who's ready for some música?
It's a Battle of
the Bands, amigos.
The winner gets to play
for the maestro himself...
Ernesto de la Cruz
on his fiesta tonight!
That's our ticket, muchacho.
Let the competition begin!
So, what's the plan?
W-what are you gonna play?
Definitely "Remember Me."
No, not that one. No.
Come on, it's the
most popular song.
Ah, it's too popular.
♪ Remember me
though I have to travel far ♪
♪ Remember... ♪
♪ Don't let it make you cry ♪
Um, what about...
Poco Loco?
Epa! Now, that's a song.
De la Cruzito!
You're on standby.
Los Chachalacos,
you're up next.
Los Chachalacos!
You always this nervous
before a performance?
I don't know.
I've never performed before.
What? You said
you were a musician!
I am! I mean, I-I will be.
- Ay!
- Once I win.
That's your plan?
No, no, no, no.
You have to win, Miguel.
Your life literally
depends on you winning.
And you've never
done this before?
- I'll go up.
- Uh, n-no!
- I need to do this.
- Why?
If I can't go out there
and play one song...
how can I call myself
a musician?
What does that matter?
'Cause I don't just want
to get de la Cruz' blessing.
I need to prove that...
that I'm worthy of it.
Oh. Oh, that's such
a sweet sentiment.
At such a bad time!
Okay! Okay, okay. Okay.
Okay, you wanna perform?
Then you've got to perform!
First, you have to loosen up.
Shake off those nerves.
Now, give me your best grito.
My best grito?
Come on, yell. Belt it out.
Haooeyy-he-he-hey!
Oh, it feels good.
Okay, now, now, now you.
A-a-eh.
Aeh...
Ay...
Ay...ay...
Ay...ay...ay.
Oh, come on, kid.
De la Cruzito!
You're on now!
Miguel, look at me.
Hey, hey, look at me.
Come on, let's go!
You can do this.
Grab their attention
and don't let it go!
Héctor...
Make them listen, chamaco.
You've got this.
De la Cruzito!
Arriba-Ba! Hey!
Eh...
What's he doing?
Why isn't he playing?
Bring back the singing dog!
Hunh!
Aah-aaah-aaayy!
♪ What color is the sky? ♪
♪ Ay, mi amor, ay, mi amor ♪
♪ You tell me that it's red ♪
♪ Where should I put my shoes? ♪
♪ Ay, mi amor, ay, mi amor ♪
♪ You say, "put them on your head!" ♪
♪ You make me un poco loco ♪
♪ un poquititito loco ♪
♪ The way you keep me guessing ♪
♪ I'm nodding and I'm yesing ♪
♪ I'll count it as a blessing ♪
♪ That I'm only un poco loco ♪
Not bad for a dead guy.
Not so bad yourself, gordito.
Eso!
He's close. Find him.
♪ The loco that you make me ♪
♪ It is just un poco crazy ♪
♪ The sense that you're not making ♪
♪ The liberties you're taking ♪
♪ Leaves my cabeza shaking ♪
♪ You are just un poco loco ♪
Numero uno, Miguelito!
Aah-haa-haaoo!
Rrrr-aaayy-aaayy!
We're looking for a living kid.
About twelve?
Have you seen a living boy?
♪ Un poquiti-ti-ti-ti-ti-ti-ti-ti ♪
♪ ti-ti-ti-ti-to loco! ♪
Aaah-aaoah-aah!
Hey! You did good!
I'm proud of you.
Eso!
Hey, where are you going?
We gotta get outta here.
What? You're crazy!
We're about to win this thing.
Damas y caballeros...
I have a emergency announcement.
Please be on the look out
for a living boy.
Answers to the name of Miguel.
Earlier tonight, he ran away
from his family.
They just want to send him
back to the Land of the Living.
Wait, wait, wait.
You said de la Cruz
was your only family.
The only person who
could send you home.
I do have other family, but...
You could have taken my
photo back this whole time?
But they hate music.
I need a musician's blessing.
- You lied to me!
- Oh, you're one to talk.
Look at me, I'm being
forgotten, Miguel.
I don't even know if I'm
gonna last the night.
I'm not gonna miss my one
chance to cross that bridge
'cause you want to live out
some stupid musical fantasy.
- It's not stupid.
- I'm taking you to your family.
- Let go of me.
- You'll thank me later.
You don't wanna help me.
You only care about yourself.
Keep your dumb photo.
- No!
No, no, no!
- Stay away from me!
No!
Hey, chamaco?
Where did you go?
Chamaco?
Sorry!
Come back.
Dante, cállate.
Don't Dante, stop it.
He can't help me.
Dante, stop.
Stop it.
Leave me alone!
You're not a spirit guide,
you're just a dumb dog.
Now get outta here!
It's him!
It's that living boy!
I've heard about him, look!
He's alive.
Huah!
Aah!
This nonsense ends now, Miguel!
I am giving you my blessing,
and you are going home.
I don't want your blessing.
Miguel! Stop!
Come back!
Miguel!
I am trying to save your life.
You're ruining my life.
What?
Music's the only thing
that makes me happy.
A-and you... you wanna
take that away.
You'll never understand.
♪ Y aunque la vida
me cueste, Llorona ♪
♪ No dejaré de quererte ♪
I-I thought you hated music.
Oh, I loved it.
I remember that feeling.
When my husband would play,
and I would sing.
And nothing else mattered.
But when we had Coco...
suddenly, there was something in my
life that mattered more than music.
I wanted to put down rules.
He wanted to play for the world.
We each made a sacrifice
to get what we wanted.
Now, you must make a choice.
But I don't wanna pick sides.
Why can't you be on my side?
That's what family's
supposed to do.
Support you.
But you never will.
Have a good time.
Oh, how exciting!
Oh, El Santo!
I-I-I'm a big fan.
You mind if I?
Gracias, señor.
Invitation?
It's okay, I'm Ernesto's
great-great-grandson.
Heh.
Disculpe, señores.
Hey, hey, guys, it's Poco Loco!
You were on fire tonight.
You too!
Hey, musician to musician,
I need a favor.
Oh, the competition winners.
Congratulations, chicos.
Thanks guys.
Oh.
- Hey, enjoy the party, little músico.
- Gracias.
Ooh.
Look, it's Ernesto.
De la Cruz.
Señor de la Cruz!
Pardon me.
Señor de la...
When you see your moment,
you mustn't let it pass you by.
You must seize it.
We're almost there, Dante.
Señor de la Cruz!
Señor de la...
But what can we do?
It is hopeless.
You must have faith, sister.
Oh, but Padre,
he will never listen.
He will listen to music.
Rrrr-aaoo-aaoo-aao-aahh!
♪ Señoras y señores ♪
♪ Buenas tardes
Buenas noches ♪
♪ Señoritas y señores ♪
♪ To be here with you tonight ♪
♪ Brings me joy,
Que alegría ♪
♪ For this music is my language ♪
♪ And the world es mi familia ♪
♪ And the woo-orld es mi familia ♪
♪ For this music is my Lang-
Ah!
Hunh!
Are you all right, niño?
Huah!
It-it's you.
Y-you are that boy.
The one who came from
the Land of the Living.
You... know about me?
You're all anyone
has been talking about.
Why have you come here?
I'm Miguel.
Your g-great-great-grandson.
I have a great-great-grandson?
I need your blessing.
So I can go back home and
be a musician just like you.
The rest of our family...
they wouldn't listen.
But I... I hoped you would.
My boy, with a talent like yours...
how could I not listen?
Haha! I have a
great-great-grandson!
Look, it's Frida!
Yes, it is I, Frida Kahlo.
It is an honor, señora.
Gracias.
Hey, Negrete, Infante.
Have you met my
great-great-grandson?
My great-great-grandson!
He is alive and a musician, to boot.
Dimple, no dimple.
No dimple!
To our friendship. Haha!
I'd move heaven and earth
for you, mi amigo. Salud!
Poison!
You know, I did all my own stunts.
♪ Though I have to say goodbye
Remember me ♪
All of this came from my amazing
fans in the Land of the Living.
They leave me more offerings
than I know what to do with.
Hey, what's wrong?
Is it too much?
You look overwhelmed.
N-no, It's all great.
- But?
- It's just...
I've been looking up
to you my whole life.
You're the guy
who actually did it.
But did you ever regret it?
Choosing music
over everything else?
It was hard saying
goodbye to my hometown.
Heading off on my own.
Leaving your family?
Si.
But I could not have
done it differently.
One cannot deny
who one is meant to be.
And you, my great-great-grandson...
are meant to be a musician.
You and I, we are artists, Miguel.
We cannot belong to one family.
The world is our family!
Ooh-hoo! Ooh!
The fireworks have begun!
Soon, the party will move across
town for my sunrise spectacular.
Hunh! Miguel, you must
come to the show!
You will be my guest of honor.
- You mean it?
- Of course, my boy.
I can't.
I have to get home
before sunrise.
Oy! I really do need to get you home.
It has been an honor.
I am sorry to see you go, Miguel.
I hope you die very soon.
You know what I mean.
Miguel...
I give you my blessing.
We had a deal, chamaco.
Who are you?
What is the meaning of this?
Oh, Frida. I thought
you couldn't make it.
You said you'd take back my photo.
You promised, Miguel.
You know this uh, man?
I just met him tonight.
He told me he knew you.
H...Héctor?
Please, Miguel.
Put my photo up.
My friend. You're...
you're being forgotten.
And whose fault is that?
- Héctor, please.
- Those were my songs you took.
My songs that made you famous.
- What?
- If I'm being forgotten...
It's because you never told anyone
that I wrote them.
That's crazy. De la Cruz
wrote all his own songs.
You wanna tell him?
Or should I?
Héctor, I never meant to take credit.
We made a great team, but...
you died, and... I-I only sang
your songs because
I wanted to keep
a part of you alive.
Oh, how generous!
You really did play together.
Look, I don't want to fight about it.
I just want you to make it right.
Miguel can put my photo up.
- Héctor.
- And I can cross over the bridge.
I could see my girl.
Ernesto.
Remember the night I left?
That was a long time ago.
We drank together.
And you told me you would move
heaven and earth for your amigo.
Well, I'm asking you to now.
Heaven and earth?
Like in the movie?
What?
That's Don Hidalgo's toast.
In the de la Cruz movie,
"El Camino a Casa."
I'm talking about my real life, Miguel.
No, it's in there.
Look!
This calls for a toast.
To our friendship! Haha!
I would move heaven
and earth for you, mi amigo.
But in the movie, Don Hidalgo
poisons the drink.
Salud.
Poison!
That night, Ernesto.
The night I left.
We've been performing
on the road for months.
I got homesick
and I packed up my songs.
You wanna give up now?
When we're this close
to reaching our dream?
This was your dream.
You'll manage.
I can't do this
without your songs, Héctor.
I'm going home, Ernesto.
Hate me if you want.
But my mind is made up.
Oh, I could never hate you.
If you must go, then I'm...
I'm sending you off with a toast.
To our friendship.
I would move heaven
and earth for you, mi amigo.
Salud!
You walked me to the train station.
But I felt a pain in my stomach.
I thought it must have
been something I ate.
Perhaps it was that chorizo,
my friend.
Or something I drank.
I woke up dead.
You...
poisoned me!
You're confusing movies
with reality, Héctor.
All this time, I thought
it was just bad luck.
I never thought that you might have...
that you...
How could you?
Héctor!
Security! Security!
You took everything away from me!
You rat!
Have him taken care of.
He's not well.
I just wanted to move back home!
No! No!
I apologize.
Where were we?
You were going
to give me your blessing.
Yes... ah... Si.
Miguel...
My reputation... it is...
very important to me.
I would hate to have you think...
That you m-murdered Héctor
for his songs?
You don't think that.
Do you?
I... No... Everyone knows you're the...
the good guy.
Papá Ernesto...
my blessing?
Security?
Take care of Miguel.
He'll be extending his stay.
What?
But I'm your family!
And Héctor was my best friend.
Success doesn't come
for free, Miguel.
You have to be willing
to do whatever it takes to...
seize your moment.
I know you understand.
No! No!
Let go!
No!
Aah!
Help!
Can anyone hear me?
I wanna go home!
Huh?
H-Héctor?
- Kid?
- Oh, Héctor!
You were right.
I should have gone
back to my family.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- They told me not to be like de la Cruz.
- But I didn't listen.
- Hey, it's okay.
But I told them I didn't care
if they remembered me.
I didn't care if was on
the stupid ofrenda.
Hey, chamaco, it's okay.
It's okay.
I told them I didn't care.
- Huh! Oh!
- Héctor!
Héctor?
She's...
forgetting me.
Who?
My daughter.
She's the reason you wanted
to cross the bridge.
I just wanted to see her again.
I never should have left Santa Cecilia.
I wish I could apologize.
I wish I could tell her that her
Papá was trying to come home.
That he loved her so much.
My Coco.
Coco?
Where?
Where did you get this?
That's my Mamá Coco.
That's my Mamá Imelda.
Is that...
You?
We're...
- family?
- Family?
I always hoped I'd see her again.
That she'd miss me.
Maybe put up my photo.
But it never happened.
You know the worst part?
Even if I never got to see
Coco in the living world...
I thought at least one day,
I'd see her here.
Give her the biggest hug.
But she's the last person
who remembers me.
The moment she's gone
from the living world...
You disappear.
From this one.
You'll never get to see her.
Ever again.
You know...
I wrote her a song once.
We used to sing it every night.
At the same time.
No matter how far apart we were.
What I wouldn't give
to sing it to her.
One...
last...
time.
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Though I have to say goodbye ♪
♪ Don't let it make you cry ♪
♪ For even if I'm far away ♪
♪ I hold you in my heart ♪
♪ I sing a secret song to you ♪
♪ Each night we are apart ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
Papá!
♪ Though I have to travel far ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Each time you hear a sad guitar ♪
♪ Know that I'm with you ♪
♪ The only way that I can be ♪
♪ Until you're in my arms again ♪
♪ Remember ♪
♪ Me ♪
H-He stole your guitar.
He stole your songs.
You should be the one
the world remembers.
Not de la Cruz.
I didn't write "Remember Me"
for the world.
I wrote it for Coco.
I'm a pretty sorry excuse for a
great-great-grandpa.
Are you kidding? A minute ago,
I thought I was related to a murderer.
You're a total upgrade.
My whole life...
there's been something
that made me different.
And I never knew
where it came from.
But now, I know.
It comes from you!
I'm proud we're family.
I'm proud to be his family!
Rrrr-aayy!
Haaa-ooei!
Aaah-haha-ha-aayy!
I'm proud to be
his family!
Haooo-whoo-hoo!
Ho-ha-ay!
Dante?
Dante!
It's Dante!
Haha!
Imelda!
Héctor.
You look good.
Dante!
You knew he was my
Papá Héctor the whole time!
You are a real spirit guide.
Who's a good spirit guide?
You are!
Whoa!
Haha!
Dante!
There they are!
Miguelito! Miguelito!
Gracias, Dios mio!
Mijo, I was so worried.
Thank goodness
we found you in time.
And you.
How many times
must I turn you away?
Imelda...
I want nothing to do with you.
Not in life, not in death.
I spent decades protecting
my family from your mistakes.
He spends five minutes with you,
and I have to fish him out of a sinkhole!
I wasn't in there 'cause of Héctor.
He was in there 'cause of me.
He was just trying to get me home.
I didn't wanna listen.
But he was right.
Nothing is more
important than family.
I'm ready to accept your blessing.
And your conditions.
But first, I need to find de la Cruz.
To get Héctor's photo.
- What?
- So he can see Coco again.
Héctor should be on our ofrenda.
He's part of our family.
He left this family.
He tried to go home to you and Coco.
But de la Cruz murdered him.
It's true, Imelda.
And so what if it's true?
You leave me alone
with a child to raise,
and I'm just supposed
to forgive you?
Imelda, I...
Héctor?
Hunh!
I'm running out of time.
It's Coco.
She's forgetting you.
You don't have to forgive him.
But we shouldn't forget him.
I wanted to forget you.
I wanted Coco
to forget you too, but...
This is my fault.
Not yours.
I'm sorry, Imelda.
Miguel...
If we help you get his photo...
you will return home.
No more music.
Family comes first.
I... I can't forgive you.
But I will help you.
So how do we get to
de la Cruz?
I might know a way.
Good luck, muchacho.
Gracias, Frida.
Ah!
Here, let me help you with...
Don't touch me.
Everyone clear on the plan?
Find Héctor's photo.
Give it to Miguel.
Send Miguel home.
Got your petals?
Now, we just have to find de la Cruz.
- Yes?
- Ah!
Don't I know you?
That's for murdering
the love of my life!
- Who the?
- She's talking about me.
I'm the love your your life?
I don't know,
I'm still angry at you.
Héctor? How did you...
And that's for trying
to murder my grandson!
- Grandson?
- She's talking about me.
You!
Wait. You're related to Héctor?
The photo!
Eh...
After him!
Security, ayuda.
You said love of your life?
I don't know what I said.
That's what I heard.
Places, señor.
You're on in 30 seconds.
Miguel, I have it!
Oh!
Hurry, come on!
Ladies and gentleman!
The one. The only.
Ernesto de la Cruz!
Get her off the stage!
Sing!
♪ Ay ♪
♪ de mí, Llorona ♪
♪ Llorona de azul Celeste ♪
♪ Ay de mí, Llorona ♪
♪ Y aunque la vida me cueste,
Llorona ♪
♪ No dejaré de quererte ♪
♪ Me subí Al pino más alto,
Llorona ♪
♪ A ver Si Te divisaba ♪
♪ Como El pino era tierno,
Llorona ♪
♪ Al verme llorar, lloraba ♪
♪ Ay de mí, Llorona, Llorona ♪
♪ Llorona de azul Celeste ♪
♪ Y aunque la vida me cueste,
Llorona ♪
♪ No dejaré de quererte ♪
♪ Y aunque la vida me cueste ♪
- Let go of me!
♪ Llorona ♪
♪ No dejaré de quererte ♪
♪ ¡Ay, ay, ay! ♪
I forgot what that felt like.
You... still got it.
Uh-h-hum...
Oh!
Miguel, I give you my blessing...
To go home...
To put up our photos...
And to never...
Never play music again.
To never forget how much
your family loves you.
You're going home.
You're not going anywhere!
Imelda!
Stay back! Stay back!
All of you, stay back!
Not one more step.
Dante!
Ernesto, stop!
Leave the boy alone.
I've worked too hard, Héctor.
Too hard to let him
destroy everything.
He's a living child, Ernesto.
He's a threat.
You think I'd let him go back to the
Land of the Living with your photo?
To keep your memory alive?
- No.
- You're a coward!
I am Ernesto de la Cruz.
The greatest musician of all time.
Héctor's the real musician.
You're just the guy who
murdered him and stole his songs.
Murdered?
I am the one who's
willing to do what it takes
to seize my moment.
Whatever it takes.
Aah! Aah!
No!
- Miguel!
Apologies, old friend.
But the show must go on.
Haha!
Boo! Boo!
Boo!
Hahaha! Please, please,
mi familia!
- Murderer!
- Get off the stage!
Orchestra, a-one, a-two, a-one...
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Though I have to s- ♪
Hey, creep!
Look!
Nice kitty.
Ah!
Put me down!
Please!
I'm begging you!
Stop, stop!
Aaah!
Aah! Aaah!
Oooh!
Oh! No!
Aaah!
Hunh!
What did I miss?
Good boy, Dante.
Miguel!
Oh!
Héctor!
The photo, I lost it.
It's okay, mijo.
It's...
Héctor!
Héctor?
Coco.
No, we can still find the photo.
Miguel, it's almost sunrise.
No, no, no.
I can't leave you.
I promised I put your photo up.
I promised you'd see Coco.
We're both out of time, mijo.
No! No!
She can't forget you.
I just wanted her to know...
that I loved her.
Héctor!
You have our blessing, Miguel.
No conditions.
No, Papá Héctor. Please!
No.
Go home.
I promise! I-I won't let
Coco forget you!
There he is!
Miguel! Stop!
Where have you been?
Ah! I need to see
Mamá Coco, please!
Huh! What are you doing with that?
Give it to me!
Miguel, stop.
Miguel! Miguel?
Miguel!
Mamá Coco?
Can you hear me?
It's Miguel.
I-I saw your Papá!
Remember? Papá?
Please.
If you forget him.
He'll be gone.
Forever.
Here. This was his guitar, right?
He used to play it to you?
See, there he is.
Papá, remember? Papá?
Miguel!
Mamá Coco, please.
Don't forget him.
What are you doing
to that poor woman?
It's okay, mother.
What's gotten into you?
I thought I lost you, Miguel.
I'm sorry, Papá.
We're all together now.
That's what matters.
Not all of us.
It's okay, Mamita.
Miguel, you apologize
to your Mamá Coco.
Mamá Coco...
Well, apologize.
Your Papá...
He wanted you to have this.
Mamá... wait...
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Though I have to say goodbye ♪
♪ Don't let it make you cry ♪
♪ For even if I'm far away ♪
- Look!
♪ I hold you in my heart ♪
♪ I sing a secret song to you ♪
♪ Each night we are apart ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Though I have to travel far ♪
♪ Each time you hear a sad guitar ♪
♪ Know that I'm with you ♪
♪ The only way that I can be ♪
♪ Until you're in my arms again ♪
♪ Remember ♪
♪ Me ♪
Elena?
What's wrong, mija?
Nothing, Mamá.
Nothing at all.
My Papá used to
sing me that song.
He loved you, Mamá Coco.
Your Papá loved you so much.
I kept his letters.
Poems he wrote me.
And...
Papá was a musician.
When I was a little girl...
He and Mamá would sing
such beautiful songs.
One year later
Remember me
Forgotten.
And right over here,
one of Santa Cecilia's
greatest treasures.
The home of the esteemed
songwriter, Héctor Rivera.
The letters Héctor wrote
home for his daughter, Coco
contain the lyrics for all
of your favorite songs.
Not just "Remember Me."
And that man is your Papá Julio.
And there's Tía Rosita.
And your Tía Victoria.
And those two are
Oscar and Felipe.
There aren't just old pictures,
they're our family.
And they're counting on us
to remember them.
♪ Say that I'm crazy ♪
- Next.
♪ Or call me a fool ♪
Enjoy your visit, Héctor.
♪ But last night it seemed
that I dreamed about you ♪
Papá!
Coco!
♪ When I opened my mouth ♪
♪ What came out was a song ♪
♪ And you knew every word ♪
♪ And we all sang along ♪
♪ To a melody played ♪
♪ On the strings of our souls  ♪
♪ And a rhythm that rattled us ♪
♪ Down to the bone ♪
♪ Our love for each other ♪
♪ Will live on forever ♪
♪ In every beat ♪
♪ Of my proud corazón ♪
♪ Our love for each other ♪
♪ Will live on forever ♪
♪ In every beat ♪
♪ Of my proud corazón ♪
♪ Ay mi familia ♪
♪ Oiga mi gente ♪
♪ Canten a coro ♪
♪ Let it be known ♪
♪ Our love for each other ♪
♪ Will live on forever ♪
♪ In every beat ♪
♪ Of my proud corazón ♪
♪ Ay mi familia ♪
♪ Oiga mi gente ♪
♪ Canten a coro ♪
♪ Let it be known ♪
♪ Our love for each other ♪
♪ Will live on forever ♪
♪ In every beat ♪
♪ Of my proud corazón ♪