Henry, it's time.
Which one did
you say moved?
The one on the left.
Aw.
You're a poppa.
You're a momma.
Hmm?
You little sneak.
Hello, Libby.
Libby.
Hmm?
Hello, Buck.
He's got your eyes.
Get out of there,
you little prickle bush.
All right, this is
gonna be a big one.
Hmm?
Hello, Arlo.
Come on out.
Look at you.
Buck!
Whoa!
That's Clawtooth Mountain.
And this is our farm.
And we're all gonna
take care of it together.
What?
Gotcha!
Libby!
Ha-ha!
Ooh!
Ha-ha. Gotcha back!
Momma, I'm
done watering.
Good job, Libby.
Buck, get back to your chores.
What?
Thanks, Buck.
But I... I...
You're all set.
Can't I do
something else, Momma?
Get going.
Okay.
Who is that?
Oh!
Hey, Eustice.
Aw, you stuck,
little guy?
Let me get that for you.
You're free.
Hello, move. Go find
your poppa and your...
Momma!
Whoa. The river's
not something
to mess around with there, Arlo.
Be careful.
What's the problem?
Poppa, Henrietta is the
worst one in the coop!
Yesterday you said
Footless Fran was the worst.
She's only got one foot.
You don't
have to like 'em, Arlo.
You just have to feed 'em.
That should do it.
Now, this will keep them rotten
critters from stealing our food
because I made this silo
100% critter-proof.
Put your mark on there, Henry.
You earned it.
Yeah, Poppa, do it!
Come on!
Yeah!
Only if your
momma does it first.
If anyone's earned
a mark around here, it's her.
Did you just put your mark
higher than mine?
What? No.
It's just the angle you're looking at it.
The "angle," huh?
Ooh, ooh. Me too!
Me, me, me! My turn!
My turn!
Now hold on.
It's not that easy.
You've got to earn your mark
by doing something big.
For something
bigger than yourself.
Someday you'll
all make your mark
and I can't wait
to see it.
That is how you clear a field.
Attaboy, Buck.
He'll figure it out.
Be just fine.
Go on, Buck.
You earned it.
Good job, son.
You've
got it, Libby!
Just a little bit more.
Beautiful.
You earned your mark, sweetheart.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Arlo!
He'll get there.
All right, you cluckers,
you're about to get fed.
Arlo.
Huh?
Come here.
Buck! What happened?
I came to help you
with your chores.
And then they attacked.
You're gonna be okay.
Tell Momma I love her.
I see a light.
I'll go get help!
Oh, you should
see your face!
I should've known!
Always got to mess me up.
Me?
You mess up your chores
and everyone else's.
- You're such a coward.
- Buck!
I ain't a coward.
And I'm gonna make my mark.
Just like you,
and Libby, and everyone!
You will, darling. You just
need a little more time.
Forget it. I didn't even want
that dumb mark anyway.
I got an idea.
Arlo. Arlo. Wake up.
Huh?
Come with me.
Uh...
Where are we going?
You'll see.
Okay, now take
a walk out there.
By myself?
Go on.
Poppa. Poppa.
Calm down. Breathe.
Oh.
Sometimes you got to
get through your fear
to see the beauty
on the other side.
Wow.
I got a new job
for you tomorrow.
That is if you still
want to make your mark.
The dang wilderness critter's
coming over the fence, eating our food,
and I've had it
up to my snout.
If this keeps up,
we won't have
enough food to
survive the winter.
That's why you are
gonna catch that critter.
Then along comes a critter...
And this is how
you're gonna finish the job.
When that critter's
taken care of,
you'll put your mark on
the silo right next to mine.
I'll take care of the critter, Poppa.
It won't stand a chance.
What are you doing,
you bug?
Get out of here.
Huh! Move along, leaf.
Move along.
You're dead, critter.
Okay. You're free.
What are you doing?
Just leave! Flee!
Stay back! Go! Whoa.
Arlo!
Why'd you let it go?
It was biting, and coming at me,
and screeching, and...
You had a job to do.
You got to get over your fear, Arlo,
or you won't survive out here.
Come on.
We're gonna finish
your job right now.
Out there?
Get over.
But, Poppa, what if
we get lost?
As long as you can
find the river,
you can find your way home.
What do you see?
Uh, tracks?
And they're washing out,
we got to move!
We're losing it!
Arlo, keep moving!
Poppa, wait.
Arlo, what did I
say about keeping...
It's okay.
It's okay, Arlo.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted you to
get through your fear.
I know
you have it in you.
But I'm not like you.
You're me and more.
I think we went
far enough today.
Storm's getting worse.
Let's get you home.
Arlo, move!
Run, Arlo!
Poppa!
Poppa! Poppa! Poppa!
Momma!
If we don't get
this harvest in
before the first snow,
we won't have
enough food for winter.
I know it's hard
without Poppa,
but I need you
to do more, Arlo.
Don't worry, Momma.
I won't let us starve.
You're a good son.
Huh?
You!
You've got some
nerve coming here.
It's all your fault!
My poppa would still be alive
if it weren't for you!
Help!
Momma! Momma!
Momma!
Momma?
You!
I should've
killed you the first time.
This is all your fault.
Get over here.
Get away. Get away.
Get away. Get away!
That's right.
You better run!
Where am I?
Where's home?
Oh.
As long as you can
find the river,
you can find your way home.
You again?
Get out of here.
Ugh!
I told you to
stay away from me.
I am still gonna
squeeze the life out of you.
But before I do,
can you find me some more?
Uh, here, more of these.
You know...
No. Stop.
What are you doing?
Hey, wait.
Can you take me to the berries?
Where are you going?
I knew it.
I'm gonna die out here.
Because of you.
Hey. Hey. What are you doing?
No, no, no. Stop!
Hey. Hey. No. Stop!
Ooh.
Ow. Ow.
Why you little...
Come back here!
Berries!
Oh!
What's with you?
They're right here.
Crazy critter.
Hello.
Hello?
We've been watching you.
We thought you were going to die,
but then you didn't.
That creature
protected you.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm going home. Do you know
how far Clawtooth Mountain is?
Good idea. We want him.
Why?
Because it's
terrifying out here.
He can protect me
like my friends.
This is Fury.
He protects me from the creatures
that crawl in the night.
This is Destructor.
She protects me
from mosquitoes.
This is Dream Crusher.
He protects me from
having unrealistic goals.
And this is Debbie.
Yes, we need him.
What is his name?
A name? I don't know.
Hmm. Then I will
meditate on this.
Hmm...
I name him,
I keep him. Hmm...
Killer.
Hmm... Beast.
Hmm... Murderer.
Hmm...
Uh... Grubby!
Funeral Planner?
Uh, Cootie!
Hmm... Hemorrhoid.
Uh, Squirt!
Uh, Frank!
Stinky!
Maniac!
Funky!
Violet.
Spike!
Lunatic.
Spot!
Spot! Come here,
Spot. Come here.
He is named.
You clearly are connected.
Good for you.
On your path to
Clawtooth Mountain
that creature
will keep you safe.
Don't ever lose him.
No. No. You can't
have him, Debbie.
No, no, no. Debbie!
Debbie! Stop!
You're better than this.
No, no, no!
Come back! Debbie!
Where are you going?
I need to get home.
Ow!
Huh?
Ugh...
Spot, watch this.
Oh.
Huh? Huh?
I miss...
I miss my family.
Family.
That's me.
There's Libby.
And Buck.
And Momma.
And...
And Poppa.
Family.
Huh?
You don't understand.
That's okay.
Yes. That's your family.
I miss him.
Oh...
We should stop.
Stop!
Arlo, move.
Run, Arlo!
Where's the river?
I've lost the river.
I'm never getting home.
Help! Help! Help!
Aw, say, friend,
are you wounded?
No. I'm not hurt.
Oh, good. Thank
goodness for that.
Uh, Coldfront, Downpour,
keep looking
for wounded folk.
Wait. I'm lost.
I need to get home.
Clawtooth Mountain.
Uh...
Clawtooth Mount...
Oh, you mean the mountain
range with the three points.
Yes! Yeah!
Oh, yeah. I've been there.
Uh, but you know, kid... Mmm.
You're not even close.
Still, I know the way.
My name's Arlo.
I'm sorry. I just...
I used to have
a name like that once.
That was before
I started following the storm!
The storm?
The storm swept me out.
I was afraid for my life,
but the storm
gave me a relevation.
And I wasn't
scared anymore.
You mean a revelation?
No! A relevation. Okay?
I was at a real
low point. You know?
And the storm swept me up
to a real high point,
and then left me at
a higher relevation.
Wow.
Yeah, wow.
That's when the storm
gave me my new name
because...
What do we say?
The storm provides.
You can call me Thunderclap.
Thunderclap.
Can you help me get home?
Uh, yeah, well...
Uh, maybe. Oh!
But first, we just
need to check the area.
There's plenty of
folks in a bad way
after a storm like this,
don't you know?
Uh, Thunderclap, I found someone!
Over here!
You know, we could
use your help, friend.
Uh...
Whoa!
Yeah! That is great.
It's a critter.
Ah! A freed critter.
Thanks to you.
You know, I just want
to take a moment
and thank the storm
for this meal.
Don't think
you can mess with me.
I've seen
the eye of the storm!
And I forgot
what fear is!
I'm not afraid
of anything.
No,
I didn't say you were.
Hey, where are
you going, friend?
I'm... I need
to get home.
And I said
we would get you home.
Friend, you have
a critter of your own.
Oh, I smell it.
One of the juicy ones.
Where is it?
He's hiding. Over there.
By that big rock.
The storm provides.
No!
- Spot!
- Get him!
Hey, slow down.
There's no place to hide, yellow belly.
Come back
with that critter!
Help! Help!
Help!
Hey, you okay, kid?
Yes.
I hate those kind.
Lying sons of crawdads
picking on a kid.
Well, ain't you
just the cutest thing.
He likes you.
Imagine that, Ramsey.
Even with your stinky face.
Nash! Boundaries.
This is my personal bubble.
Nah, that ain't your bubble.
This is your bubble.
Nash, get out of
your sister's bubble.
You got no business
being out here.
Yes, sir. I don't.
I'm trying to get home, but I lost the river.
Please, my momma needs me.
Take it easy, kid.
Do you know
where the river is?
What river?
There's tons of rivers around these parts.
By Clawtooth Mountain.
It has three points.
Don't know that one.
We're heading south
to a watering hole.
Come with us.
Someone there might help you.
We ain't got time
for baby-sitting,
we got longhorns
to round up.
My genius brother
lost our whole herd in one day.
I did not
lose them, Ramsey.
How many times I got to tell you this?
They just wandered off.
We still got to find them.
We can't help you, kid.
Wait! But what if
we could help you?
Spot can sniff out anything.
I've seen him do it.
He can find your longhorns.
Hey!
Come on, Spot.
Sniff it out, boy.
Good boy, Spot.
He's got something.
Aw, dang.
Hey, kid, if you're
pulling my leg,
I'm gonna eat yours.
He found the herd.
Whoo-whee! We got 'em.
Wait, do longhorns
have feathers?
Rustlers.
Rustlers?
We got to move.
Yah!
I don't see
any rustlers.
They're out there.
So, how far did you say
that watering hole was?
I got a job for you.
I'm not really good at jobs.
I need you to keep on the dodge
and sidle up the loblolly,
past them hornheads
just hooting and a hollering,
and score off them rustlers.
We'll cut dirt and
get the bulge on them.
What?
He just wants you to get
on that rock and scream.
Uh, but who's
out there?
They'll come right at you.
You hold your ground.
Don't move.
Don't move?
What if they have claws and big teeth?
Don't overthink it.
Howdy.
What are you up to, boy?
Nothing.
Nothing? Oh!
What's your name?
Uh, Arlo.
Well, Arlo,
you don't look like
you're doing nothing.
What's he look like
he's doing to you, Lurleane?
Oh, come on,
Bubbha. Ask me.
Ask me what I think
they're doing.
Pervis, shut your mouth!
Ah, looks like
he's trespassing.
And what do we do with
trespassers? Tell them, Earl.
We kill them!
I got you!
Nash, the herd!
Yah! Yah!
Yah! Giddy up. Come on now.
Giddy up! Yah!
Watch out!
Nobody steals our longhorns.
Finders keepers.
Yee-ha!
Come on now. Momma
wants to play with you.
I know you're there.
I can smell you.
Oh.
Oh, shoot!
That's my favorite tooth!
I'm gonna love ending you!
Come on, we got to drive
this herd out of here.
Yah! Come on now.
Aren't you the cutest?
You and that critter
showed real grit today.
We could use that critter.
How about we trade?
I'll give you my
harmonica for him.
Thanks, but Spot
ain't for trading.
Come here, Spot.
Come here.
Your loss.
That's a good one.
Gonna scar up real good.
That's nothing.
Look at this!
I run into 15
outlaw stegos.
They're all bigger than me
and meaner than me.
What happened?
Fought 'em off, of course.
Was winning, too.
Then one gets his
dang spikey tail
stuck in my foot
and pulls!
Whoa.
Still can't feel my toes.
Which comes in handy
when you're
kicking piles of bull...
She's jealous.
Jealous? Ha!
Once a stampede of longhorns
was coming right at me,
but my tail was stuck between
a rock and a hard place.
I was dead for sure.
So I chewed
the dang thing off!
Who does that?
Nobody does that!
You're crazy!
I'm surprised
you don't have one
right across your face.
Butch, how'd you
get your scar?
I don't know
if you're ready for that story.
I can take it.
Oh, yeah.
You got to tell him, Pa!
That's a good one!
It was 100 degrees
in the shade.
I walked for five
days with no water.
Then I saw it.
A pretty pond.
I bent down to take a drink,
when these crocs
launched out of the water.
One croc bit me on the face.
Ain't no way I wasn't its
supper except for one thing,
I wasn't ready
for dying that day.
I bit one croc in half,
tail-whipped the other,
and the last one...
Well, I drowned that croc
in my own blood.
- Whoa.
- Dang!
Ooh! Look, look,
gives me little goosies every time.
I love that story!
Show him your souvenir.
Ain't that just too good?
Can I touch it
this time?
No.
Huh. You guys would have
liked my poppa.
He wasn't scared of anything.
I'm done being scared.
Who said I'm not scared?
But you took on a croc!
And I was scared doing it.
If you ain't scared of a croc
biting you on the face,
you ain't alive.
Listen, kid,
you can't get rid of fear.
It's like Mother Nature,
you can't beat her
or outrun her,
but you can get through it.
You can find out
what you're made of.
The first snow.
It's early this year.
And I got to
get home to Momma.
We'll get you to
that watering hole.
A deal's a deal.
At first light, we ride.
Let's go!
Yah!
Hey, kid, head 'em off
before those longhorns split.
Yah!
There it is!
Clawtooth Mountain!
There's home!
Whoo-whee!
We've got to drive
this herd down south.
You hurry on
back to your momma.
And don't stop
for nothing!
Thanks! I sure appreciate you
looking out for me!
You'll be all right.
You're one tough kid.
Oh!
Whoa!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo!
Whoa.
Wow.
It's so close.
We're almost there, Spot!
We need to get home.
You're gonna
love it, Spot.
You'll have a warm place to sleep.
Right next to me.
And all the corn
you can eat.
There's lots of space
to run around.
It'll be your farm, too.
We'll all look
after it together.
I can't.
No!
Spot!
No! Spot!
Poppa?
You're alive?
I can't
believe it. It's you.
My friend! Spot!
He helped me and
now he's in trouble.
We have to go back.
Poppa, stop.
Stop!
Poppa?
You're not here.
I'm scared.
But Spot needs me.
I blamed him for
what happened to you,
but it wasn't his fault.
So I got to go help him.
Because I love him.
I knew you had it in you.
You're me and more.
Now go take care
of that critter.
Back off!
Well, look who
got relevated.
Go get him.
Spot.
Spot!
The storm provides.
We're home, Spot.
Henry?
Arlo.
Arlo!