Damned teenagers!
You'd better not in my field making out.
Not in front of my pumpkins.
Now scram!
Back in my day, we had respect
for a man's vegetables.
Kids with your far-out hippies loving...
What in the...?!
MONSTERS VS ALIENS
Mutant Pumpkins from outer space
Oh yeah, the classic
- That was very scary.
Do the creature from "The blue lagoon".
No, not again!
Stop, stop! Have you stopped yet?
What do you think I should be for Halloween?
Chewing gum, football, baseball...
melting snowball. Solar system?
Bad Elvis? "Thank you very much".
You as bad Elvis?
Actually, yeah. Maybe...
Guys, good news! Looks like that Yeti sighting
was just a hokes. So we got the night off.
Enjoy your coffee. It's normal.
Noone is in it.
This could use a little more milk.
Jeez, where is your Halloween spirit?
Hey, I got plenty of Halloween spirit. Just wait
till you see my Zombie cheerleader costume.
Now, where will I get some really huge pom poms?
- Susan...
...you are a real monster now, and that means
you're playing in the big league with the big boys.
I got 50 years of misted Halloween all
smushed up tight inside me just bursting to get out.
This isn't just any night.
It is our night, and when it finally comes...
we got to terrify...
- Perhaps, my fiend friend...
But for some of us all Hallows' Eve
is more trick then treat
I was but a lad. My head filled with dreams
of particle physics and candy.
Sweet candy.
The future before me seemed sugar-coated.
Until...!
My swirly pop!
From that dark day forth,
Halloween was dead to me... forever.
You know, I kinda want to throw you
in the trash right now.
Come on, guys. Like you said, it's our night, right?
So, let's get out and have some fun.
Fun time is over, monsters!
It's a no-go. I repeat, a no-go on Halloweens!
Yes!
- We got us a major situation.
A UFO has entered our airspace over California.
And you ain't going to believe where...
Modesto? Why is it always Modesto?
- I thought it was kinda freaking myself.
Any idea what we are facing, general?
Invasion? Abductions? Croaps?
Unknown. And I hate these some unknow.
So I want you on the ground and searching Modesto
for possible alien intruders.. asap.
Better yet. Pronto!
And let's keep this on a 'need to know' basis.
Meaning: nobody needs to know!
- But what about my parents?
No, not even your parents. It's Halloween after all,
we don't want to go around scaring folks.
Hello? Hey, get down here.
They're giving away pumpkins.
And it looks like they're going fast.
"Free pumpkins for all humans".
I'm a human. Sign me up.
Nobody does Halloween like the Murphys.
- We did it again, Carl.
Susie Q!
Mum! Dad!
I'm so glad to see you.
Oh honey, I can't believe you came.
- I finally managed to get a night off. So, I'm here.
But you're always so busy saving the earth.
It's not healthy.
Yes, we were starting to think Modesto would have
to get invaded by aliens again to see our daughter.
Stop! It's just ridiculous.
Yes, we're just here for the party,
mr and mrs Murphy.
If indeed that's who you actually are!
They're clear.
Clearly ready to throw
the best Towelie party in Modesto?
Oh, we went all out this year, hon.
I included all your own favourites...
death by chocolate fountain...
??? wicked witches, candy-poison appletree and...
children of the candy cornfield!
Yeah, not bad, but you know...
Call me when it's real candy.
You know what I'm saying...
B.O.B., it is real candy.
Oops... Hey guys,
since everything looks fine here,
why don't you go out
and do some 'Trick or Treat'-ing...
You know. Check out the neighbourhood.
- Of course. We'll keep an eye out... for candy.
Wait, where are we going? There is candy in here.
- You're coming, B?
Just try and stay... focused.
Susan, maybe you and your ma can start pealing
the grapes for the eyeballs salad.
I've got to get the farmer's Jeb patch.
Not to point the finger, but...
we need more pumpkins.
No...! Sorry.
Euh, it's not save out there.
You know, kids throwing eggs.
You could get TPed.
So, I'll go get the pumpkins.
It's quite simple, BOB. You ring the doorbell,
then repeat the following: Trick or Treat.
They offer you candy...
They're almost slightly human.
They offer to probe you...
They're almost slightly not.
Wait. They give candy to us!
For free! Are they crazy?
That free candy comes with a price, BOB.
Now focus, we have a mission to attend to.
Oh, this is ridiculous. I've waited 50 years
to scare the caramel out of these kids.
I can't wait any longer.
Just, tell them I got sick, or something.
I do a makeup mission later. I've got to go..
B.O.B!
Fine. I'll do it myself.
Trick or treat. Trick or treat.
Happy Hallowee...
This won't hurt a bit.
All clear.
Oh my god, it's Shrek!
Honey, bring the camera!
Say 'cheese'!
- Trick or treat. Trick or treat. Got it!
All clear.
What?
- Hey there, little genius. You're dressed like me.
Uhm, no. I'm dressed as the Missing Link,
you're dressed like a fat old mermaid.
Yeah, since when does Link have a beer gut?
What is happening right now?
I believe what my colleague intended to say,
was "Trick or Treat".
Oh, what an inventive costume, dear.
Really quite discusting.
You deserve something special.
A swirly pop?
For me?
And this time, no pimply hooligans
will deprive me of my lickable loot.
Come, B.O.B.
We have a new prime directive... candy!
Trick...
Come on, Link! Let's here
to be the best Halloween ever.
Look, mammy! It's Kermit.
- Ridiculous...
Biggest one in a patch, son.
Because that's how we roll.
- I'm going to call you...
Wicked Jack.
That's perfect, son.
Now, what'd say that we gut this sucker?
Waw, that almost looks real, hon?
Booh!
You can talk?!
You just...
Farmer Jeb? Hello?
Jeb?
Hello, guys, are you there?
- Susy.
Are you seeing anything?
I'm just outside of town, and there's nothing.
Not even weird old farmer Jeb.
Same here, Sus.
I think that this is just one big...
Link, are you alright?
What happened?
Sorry, Susan. Creapy clown costume.
But everything is simply delightful here.
No, B.O.B., put it down!
That is my butter picker. A trade is a trade
We'll be in touch, Susan.
Over and out.
Is anybody in there?
They're alive!
Oh, look at that. Everybody is having such fun.
- What's happening?
To think I've spent all those years
poo poop-oing Halloween.
Link, I own you an apology.
Can we, please, forget Halloween,
and find these stupid...
pumpkins.
If I wouldn't have a cockroach head myself...
I'd be freaking out right now.
Hey, pal, you're about to get cool whipped.
- Wait, I think I can reason with them.
My mother was a tomato.
I speak 'Pro Juice'.
What did he say?
- Horrible things, about my mother...
in a salad bar.
Whatever you're after, you won't get it here.
Let go! That is my candy!
Galileo's clock!
Link! Whatever mutated these pumpkins
gave them a sweet tooth.
It's not the children, they're after!
It's the candy...
No!
Just like us. The more candy they eat
the bigger they'll get.
Until the whole world becomes their pumpkin punch.
I'm looking at you, stemhead!
Go away, pumpkin thing.
You're not getting one more piece of candy.
And you're definitely not getting
what's at the Murphy house.
She's right down the street, right there.
Susan! We have a problem.
Only 20 minutes till the party begins.
I get the feeling it's going to be a mad house.
You know it, Wendy!
You think we overdid it on the candy?
You've messed with the wrong monsters, pumpkin.
Nobody steals candy on my watch.
- Nobody freaks these kids out but me.
I'm thinking. Stop pressuring me.
- I hope somebody brought the Net mag.
Halloween belongs to monsters,
and this monster's a pumpkin crushing giant.
Apparently, you're a giant crushing pumpkin!
Well, you'll never get this candy!
Come on, guys!
I can't do this alone.
You know what? Never mind, I can.
I can't believe I'm actually fighting a vegetable.
No!
Technically, he's a fruit, Susan.
In your face, pumpkin! Get it?
Oh no, don't punch yourself.
Oh man, this wasn't the best strategy after all.
Or maybe, it was. If it's candy he wants,
let's give it to him...
It makes them bigger.
Bigger... and bigger... and nausear.
Yes! Loops the lawn and shake the trees.
Kids! Get every piece of candy you can find.
Hold on the fort, children.
Look, it's Missing Link!
- Do you like that?
Say hello to my little friend.
Get some!
It's working!
Let's not overdo it.
Oh, no!
Get a few more pieces!
- We're all out
There must be some...
Farewell...
My precious.
Happy Halloween!
Mum. Dad.
Just give me a sec, ok?
Nobody ruins a Murphy Halloween.
I'm going to say "Trick".
No!
Elvis!
I knew you were still alive.
A swirly pop!
So I guess you did just come into town
to stop an alien invasion...
and not to visit your parents.
- I'm sorry. I can tell you about this.
And I wish I could make it home more often, but...
- Oh, it's ok, Susie Q.
From now on, your mum and I are just
going to have to get used to...
sharing you with the world.
I think you need to talk to those people
about a raise.
Your mother is right, honey.
How are the benefits?
You know what, dad?
They're pretty awsome.
Oh, speaking of awsome...
Who wants to buffer up home?
You got it, Carl. Just stick your face in my body.
- B.O.B?
Booh!
Still got it.
Well done as always, monsters.
I love the smell of mutating pumpkin guts
in the evening.
Smells like... victory.
Also little like pie.
- Glad you could make it to our party, general.