Through the years I have been known by many names.
Diablo Gato, The Furry Lover...
... Chupa Cabra, Frisky Two Times ...
... and then The Gingerhead man.
But to most I am Puss in Boots,
Outlaw!
I'll never forget you, Margarita ...
I mean ... Rosa.
Sorry. I think maybe I should go.
You cannot run forever, Puss in Boots!
What can I say? I was a bad kitty.
... just a fugitive from the law,
forever running
Searching for a way to clear my name.
And I would get that chance
on this one fateful night.
Kitty-kitty!
Raoul, look what the cat dragged in.
Oh, wait! That is the cat!
Bottle of leche, please.
What are you doing here,  Senor ?
Did you lose your ball of thread
So funny!
One leche coming up!
I am not looking for trouble.
I am but a humble gato
in search of his next meal.
Perhaps you gentlemen
can let me find a simple score.
The only thing you'll find tonight
is trouble, Puss in Boots.
Well perhaps if one of us
were to tell the law
that you're in town,
we could split the reward.
You made the cat angry...
You do not want to make the cat angry!
The church if St. Michael has just put up
a golden statue of,
The Virgin of Guadalupe.
I do not steal from churches!
Well, the boys orphanage has been donated
silver candlesticks,
they would look very lovely in your home!
I do not steal from orphans!
- Uh...what about Jack and Jill?
- Shh! Are you crazy?
The what?
The murderous outlaws, Jack and Jill,
have gotten their hands on magic beans.
Do not joke with me about magic beans!
I searched half my life for them.
They do not exist.
No, cat...
We have seen them!
These are the beans of legends...
Grows the vine to the land of giants.
And the golden goose...
golden goose...
Yeah, it's like this could set you up for life.
All nine of them. Show him the golden eggs!
No!
Please uh...you have uh...shown enough.
Only a cat with a death wish
would steal the beans from Jack and Jill.
The only wish I have
is to repay an old debt.
and this is my chance.
Now ...
Where to I find this Jack and Jill?
Sorry, we have no rooms.
I think one just overcomed.
We'd like a complimentary continental breakfast.
And do not even think about
skimping on them baby muffins!
Jack and Jill Mr. and Mrs..
We do not have any baby muffins!
- You know, Jill, I've been thinking
- Uuhh! Get it out.
I um...once we're done
with this magic bean business
and got ourselves all them beautiful golden eggs.
Mmhmm. Go on.
Why don't we cut down on
some of the hijackin' and murderin'.
I mean it's fun and all, but uh...
... I want a baby.
- A baby what, Jack?
- A baby of ours, Jill.
We'll raise it wild,
like a squirrel or somethin'.
Holy frijoles ...
They do exist!
Ever since you fell on that hill and
broke your crown, you've been talking crazy
Hey, what gives?
No!
You, you ... you stop where you are!
Those beans are mine!
Me?
You, snap me?
You snap me?!
You looking for something?
No.
No hablo Ingles.
You are going to pay for that!
Chupacabra!
- Chupacabra!
- You are crazy, woman!
Those magic beans were my score.
You just caused me a chance
of getting the golden eggs, mi amigo.
Put up your paws up!
Very well ...
If it is to be a dance fight,
Then I will tuesday night dance fight you
to the death!
How dare you do the litter box on me!
Can you feel me?
Fear me if you dare!
You hit me in the head with a guitar?
You ... you are a woman?
Amateur!
Wow! Senorita, wait!
Let me buy you some leche!
I am a lover not a...fighter.
Hello? You are hiding from me?
I like to play the games too.
I sense in you a kindred spirit.
I smell something familiar.
something dangerous.
something breakfasty.
It's been a long time, brother.
Maldito Huevo!
Humpty Alexander Dumpty...
How dare you show your face to me!
I know you're angry,
you have every right.
But it is good to see you, Puss!
Are those new boots?
No! They are the same boots
I wore when you betrayed me.
Be...betrayed you?
You left me cracked in pieces on a bridge,
surrounded by soldiers.
They wrote a song about it.
And how did we get on that bridge
in the first place?!
Because we were brothers and
brothers are supposed to look after each other. Not...
Humpty
Remember why we're here
I should have known.
I had the magic beans in
my grasp and you sent this very...
attractive devil woman to interfere
You are a curse on my life!
Woh! Woh! Wait! Here me out, okay?
Yes, yes! I sent Kitty to bring you here,
But she is no ordinary thief.
She's Kitty Softpaws.
The softest touch in Spain
That's a lot of heel for a guy,
don't you think?
Look, with Kitty's skill,
your sword and my brain ,
we've got a fighting chance here.
Puss, come on!
You of all people know that nobody
is ever ripped off the giant's castle
and lived to tell the tale.
You want to survive,
you need a plan.
And I've studied this job my whole life,
you know that.
Alright, let's...let's...let's be honest,
without me you don't even know
where to plant the beans, Puss.
But Jack and Jill do, they're on their way!
We go up the beanstalk outlaws
and we come down legends.
So what do you say? Partner?
No, never again.
I'm sorry, okay?
How long are you going to hold a grudge?
It's been seven years!
That's like 35 cat years!
You need me!
And I...I need you, Puss.
You got any idea what they do
to eggs in San Ricardo prison?
I'll tell you this, my friend.
It ain't over-easy!
Adios, Humpty Dumpty.!
This is bad, this is bad!
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
I know how to speak meow.
Such story,
with your twisted lies...
I should crack you open for it
Look what I found
Someone forgot his money!
You are dangerous ...
Humpty says you like danger.
Just think of all trouble
we can get into ...
The two of us, together,
We can steal a lot of golden eggs.
- And... You owe me.
- I owe you?
- You hit me in the head with a guitar.
- I regret the guitar.
Okay, I forgive you.
So ... You're in?
Only there's one tini tiny
itty bitty problem.
- And what is that?
- You work ... for the egg!
Oh, come on, Puss!
What happened between you and Humpty
that was so bad?
I am afraid with me and
Humpty the scars are too deep.
It all started a long time ago.
Oh, no! No! No! No! You really don't have to
tell me your whole life story, please!
You may want to sit.
- It is at times quite...painful.
- Okay, here we go.
It was the year
in which the rain had not fallen.
The wind was big and
the basket was small.
For days I bounced along
A hungry little kitten with no milk,
no mama and no litter box.
Until I came to rest at a home
for lost children..
Her name was Imelda .
and like a mother she took me
into her heart
and raised me as her own.
Silensio ...
Silensio!
She was an angel of kindness...
... most of the time.
I would like to introduce a new boy joining us.
It's okay, pequeno. You show the face.
Go on ...
- And uh...that was the moment I met...
- Humpty Alexander Dumpty.
Hey, whiskers!
You sit in the middle Boy Blue chair.
Come on! Is this necessary?
What don't you pick up somebody
your own size?
Who asked you, breakfast?
Remember what Imelda says, Boy Blue?
If you going to blow your top,
you blow your horn instead, right?
- Let spin him!
- Please don't spin me!
Not again! I'm gonna yolk!
Eventough he took my beans,
the egg stood up for me.
and I decided that I would always
have his back.
That was very impressive! Thanks!
Hey eggboy!
It was something about this strange
little egg that uh...intrigued me....
Oh, it's you...
I've been collecting for months now.
You never know when we're get lucky,
you know what I mean?
Magic beans,
It's what they are.
Hello?
You going to tell all the other kids
that I believe in magic now?
Is that what you're gonna do?
No? What's your name?
Well you don't say much, do you?
Well I think I'll call you Sparky.
Whiskers?
Zoltar!
How about Puss?
Humpty's mind was full of
imagination and invention.
What is it? 15 feet down there?
Here we go. Give me a pu...
I am flying!
He spoke of legends and adventures
beyond my wildest dreams.
Oh, when I find those magic beans,
they'll grow a vine straight up into the clouds ,
where a terrible and a fearsome giant
hoards his greatest treasure, the golden goose
Oh, the golden goose.
Just one...just one of her golden eggs
could set me for life.
It's my destiny, Puss.
I can't really explain it,
but I just feel like I belong up there.
Well, this is awkward.
This is kind of uh...
a solo dream here
I don't really need a dead weight, you know?
Hold me down
What are you doin'? Oh man, that's good.
The...the...the eye thing that you're doin',
that is really splendid.
Okay, let me just think for a second, alright?
Okay, uh...this is crazy
but I am considering a partnership.
I just need to know one thing.
- Can you commit?
- Si, I can commit.
Oh, you can talk!
Could you help me up?
First rule of bean club,
you do not talk about bean club.
Second rule of bean club,
you don't talk about bean club.
- You ready?
- Ready.
From this day forth, it shall be known.
Never alone, always together.
- Humpty and Puss...
- Brothers forever.
And from that moment on ,
we were united on a great adventure
to find the magic beans.
Help me up!
Paint me!
Humpty was the brain...
- Good gracious!
- I never saw him!
It's really hurt!
...and I was the skill.
Well, we got red beans, we got green beans,
coffee beans, lima beans
but no Magic Beans.
- Would you care for a jelly bean?
- Oh, thank you.
Finding them meant everything to us.
Oh, I Almost forgot the most important thing.
That's me and you, Puss...
me and you.
But we never did find them.
And as the years passed,
the quest for magic beans
seemed more and more
like a dreams of a child.
As teenagers, Humpty and I
looked for trouble
and often found it.
Third time this month, Imelda.
Next time, it's jail time.
But they're just kids...
They are thieves!
You are better than this.
I believe in you with all my heart.
Please do not let me down.
I hate this place!
I can not wait for us to get out of here!
Throw a rock! It'll make you feel better.
Oh boy! we should go.
an instinct, I reacted
- He saves the commandante's mother!
You saved my mother!
Senor Puss,
He is a hero!
Today we see the courage and bravery!
Little did I know that one moment
would change my whole life.
These are for you, my boy.
Wear them as a symbol of honor and justice.
I will make you proud, mama.
You already have. My Puss in Boots.
How strange it was to be a cat in boots,
but woh, I look good!
And as the light of my path grew brighter,
Humpty's road grew ever darker.
Gracias, Commandante!
Be careful of the company you keep.
I know. I know. I never should have tried
something without you.
You're not stealing lollipops anymore, Humpty.
This is getting serious.
You're right!
We have to be smarter about this.
Here, look. We need to think bigger.
I've been casing the silver smith
and it's perfect.
You and me, in and out, fifty seconds tops!
Will you put that away!
This is our home,
these people have done nothing to us.
Our home?
Okay, yeah. I get it now.
You get some fancy boots
and now you're too good for me?
- That is not true.
- We weren't born here. We're orphans...
- and all we got is each other. You understand?
- We are better than this.
- But we're partners.
- We are brothers!
But I am not stealing anymore.
But Humpty would not give up so easily.
I'm in trouble, Puss!
It's boy blue and his gang
I owe him some money.
They're coming for me,
just get me over this wall!
We got to go!
Help me up the wall! Hurry!
Okay, I got everything!
We did it! Come on, let's go!
- How could you do this to me?
- I did you a favor!
- We can finally get out of here.
- This is the money of the people.
This is all they have!
- You disgrace those boots.
- Comandate, please! I can explain.
Arrest them!
Hurry up! Go to the bridge!
- You tricked me!
- I had too! You left me no choice!
Mama ...
Pequeno
Watch out!
Oh no ...
Puss, I can't get up.
Puss, help me I can't get up!
Freeze!
- Puss, save me!
- Save yourself!
I lost everything I cared about that day.
My brother, my honor, my home...
All I thought about was
the disappointment in my mama's eyes.
And I have been running ever since.
The egg betrayed me.
His lies cost me everything.
I'm awake!
You think I don't want to fix the past?
I can't get down.
Listen, a day...a day doesn't go by
when I don't think about what I lost.
I lost my best friend ...
my only friend.
And I get it now, I got greedy and
desperate and I let you down.
I let myself down.
All I'm asking for, Puss, is a second chance.
Give me that second chance
and I'll help repay you back San Ricardo.
Please, Puss. Let me show you
what our friendship mean to me.
- I will do it.
- Oh, that's great!
I will do this for my mother
and for San Ricardo.
Not for you.
We are not partners
and we're not friends.
Okay and I...I promise this time
I will not let you down.
Yes! I think we got our bean club back!
- This plan better work.
- Listen, you just need to worry about your part. .
Don't screw it up!
- What?
- Again with the mask?
I don't need style advice from Mr. Dusty Boots.
Come on, Puss! Now!
Our biological clocks are tickin', darlin'.
You gotta start lookin' at the big picture.
What's the problem?
Listen, I put a lot of work into my body.
I look good and I am not
just gonna throw it away.
- What?
- Look!
Excellent!
I have no time to be at home
with no diapers and veggie stocks.
You don't have to, Jill.
I will be the stay at home dad.
We have 10 hungry piggies there on the back.
You can practice on them.
Just pull over, feed them!
You've got to hurry!
- Why are you not using your claws?
- Would you please just shut up? I'm on it!
- Just use your claws!
- Be quiet!
- Your claws!
- I don't have any claws, right?
Was that 'em hog?
There, there, sleepy sleepy big fat piggy...
You babysit.
Soft paws.
Well ...
Hello beans of legend!
Let's go!
Look at what we have here, Jill.
- You mess with our baby!
- And you took my beans!
Soft paws bomb!
You'll gonna pay for this, cat!
Signal the egg!
Yes!
- Okay!
- Ready?
Set ... Go!
Well let's find out!
Alright, cat! Give me them beans!
Is it true, a cat always lands on its feet?
No! That is just a rumor spread by dogs!
See I told you I won't let you down!
You think this is over?
Hey, that was close!
Now!
We just gonna make it to that bridge!
Hang on!
Humpty, There is no bridge!
- Trust me.
Humpty!
We're going to die!
- I hate cats.
- This is war!
Giants Castle, here we come!
i must hand it to the egg.
This was a team effort.
Humpty's team had its claws ...
I mean flaws...
What i meant was...
Not claws, he's not a cat.
Not to say there is anything wrong ...
- I don't want to talk about it!
- Got it.
Okay, We should be close.
Keep your eyes up for
any strange cloud activity.
I am called Kitty Softpaws
because I'll steal you blind
and you'll never even know I was there.
Kitty,
you're not as good as they say.
You're better!
I will respect your privacy.
All right. I'll tell you.
I was just a stray, but I had beautiful claws.
One day a really nice couple took me in,
gave me milk every morning, loved me.
Maybe I scratched her curtains
or play too rough with the hamster.
I don't know why they did it,
but they took my claws.
Cat people are crazy.
Stop! Stop the cart!
I think this is it!
Can you believe it, Puss?
After all this years...
That is a strange cloud.
Here! I want you to plant them.
Okay, this is it! It's happening! Hurry!
This way!
Come on!
Right Here!
Now, place the beans.
Place beans carefully please
not on top of each other!
Magic is very delicate.
Ok, good! Very good.
Now, just stand back.
What's happening here?
- Maybe the magic rubbed off in your pocket.
- That's impossible!
Okay. Okay. Let's not panic.
You know I read somewhere that plants
have feelings, so ...
come on. Say something nice to it.
Okay. Let me just think for a second.
Hi, little plant!
Uh...guys
Humpty!
- I do not see him. Did you see him?
- I don't see him anywhere.
You sound...weird.
It's the thin air!
Come on in, it feels great!
The cloud, it tickles my nose.
It's because the upper vest.
Who knew?
Come on!
Gotcha!
Meow!
Hey Puss, what do you think?
Do I shave?
Let me show you something.
Somewhere down there, there are two little kids.
I don't know, maybe orphans,
and they're laying on a hill staring at the clouds
dreaming about the future.
That was me and you, Puss.
Me and you.
Boys, you might wanna take a look at this.
The giants castle!
- Okay, time to suit up.
- Humpty!
I'll fit right in with the golden eggs!
- Brilliant or what, huh?
- Humpty, you're not wearing underwear!
What? Are you embarrassed? I'm not.
Puss remember when everyone
was laughing at bean club?
And who is laughing now? We are!
That is our target.
- Hey, you don't sound like an elf anymore.
- It's because the air pressure in here is normal.
Let's go!
So here is the plan:
You two get the golden eggs
- I will fight the giant.
- There's no giant to fight.
- The giant's been dead for years.
- What? You didn't do the reading, did you? Oh, boy!
Jack and the Beanstalk.
Chapter 14,
Giant takes a big dirt nap.
Ah, ankle burn!
- What was that?
- They call it The Great Terror.
It's the monster that guards the golden goose.
Legend has it that if you look at it,
you'll turn to stone.
But nobody really knows,
because nobody's walked away from it alive.
Follow me and keep quite.
- Shh! Humpty!
- I can't...I can't help it!
Everything's rubbing and pinching!
I need powder!
How are we gonna got across?
Champagne!
Cheers!
Do not worry! I will protect you!
What you gonna do?
Hit it in the head with a guitar?
Please, stop bringing up the guitar.
Catch me!
Hurry!
Hide!
Don't look at it!
Be quiet!
You got to get it together!
- Come on!
- Okay.
Look at this! It's egg paradise!
Oh, it's so beautiful. I feel like I belong here!
Golden Eggs!
It'll be a lot of chicken!
I thought they were going to be like chicken size!
Can you imagine laying one of this?
Ouch!
Puss!
- How do you suppose to get these out of here?
- I do not know!
Oh my!
The Golden Goose!
Just look at her!
Isn't she beautiful?
My sweet darling!
I think she likes you!
Let's just take her.
Wait a minute! That's the goose of legend.
We do not know what happens if we take her.
I know what happen
if we don't take her.
We got nothing!
Guys! Guys! It's a gold pooper!
We're taking it!
Almost there!
Hang on!
It's coming!
Run!
Kitty!
What are you doing?
Hang on!
Come here you!
Gotcha!
She's mine now!
Hello!
No! Fly little gosling, fly!
Desn't meant to be this way!
- Puss?
- No.
I'm sorry!
Thanks, Ranger.
We should maybe cut that down.
Look at that! You finally got
that family you wanted, Jack.
You here that? I think it just called me daddy.
- Oh! He looks just like you, Jack.
- Thank you.
Well, what is it?
I do believe that's our cue.
To paying back San Ricardo!
To being rich!
You!
Me?
Yeah, yeah, baby!
One, two, cha-cha-cha!
Three, four, cha-cha-cha!
One, two ...
What?
There is one word for you, Kitty Softpaws.
Me-wow!
I know you have quite a reputation with the ladies,
Mr. Frisky Two Times.
I've also been knowns as The Fury Lover!
But that was before I met you.
You don't know me, Puss.
I'm not who you think I am.
I'm all about the score.
Come on! Look me in the eyes
and tell me all you care about is the gold?
- Puss ...
- Kitty ...
Oh my God!
New partners!
Do not fall for his animal magnetism!
Stay focused!
What?
So, I have been thinking, Miss Softpaws,
that when we go our separate ways
we can go our separate ways together.
Puss, you have to go now!
You do not have to push me away anymore.
You can trust me.
But ...
Give it up for the legend of San Ricardo!
Humpty and Puss, we did it!
- I'm calling it a night, guys.
- Kitty, stay up with us
No, I feel a... hairball coming on.
Okay, yeah! Have fun with that!
We should give her some privacy.
I never thought we would get here,
after all we went through.
To pull this off together.
It is good to have my brother back.
Yep, it sure is. Well, we have a big day tomorrow.
Really exciting stuff.
We should get some rest.
Good night, Humpty!
Que nesta!
I'm still alive!
Jack and Jill!
Kitty!
Humpty?
I will find you!
Get out of here!
Be gone!
What do you...what do you want?
Gold? I have gold!
Jack, egg's tryin' to bribe us.
- Hah, with our own gold.
- Come on now. All we want is a little breakfast.
- No! No! No! Please!
- How do you like your eggs, pumpkin?
Humpty! No!
- Hello, Puss!
- Surprise!
What is going on?
It's a surprise party and the surprise
is on you!
Looks like cat's out of the bag.
- You were in cahoots?
- Oh, yeah! They all work for me.
I spend a lot of time in the prison
preparing for this.
- You set me up?
- Oh, yeah! Set you up? Of course!
You think this was all about getting the gold
and clearing your name?
This little adventure was about one thing.
Revenge!
You never knew it, Puss. But I was always there.
You wanted to repay and old debt, Puss?
Well so did I.
Why would you do this?
You left me on that bridge! You abandoned me
when I needed you the most!
- What happened to brothers forever?
- I trusted you!
Well now you're finally gonna know
what it feels like.
You know? To trust someone
and have them stab you in the back!
Guards!
Puss in Boots, you are under arrest
for the robbery of the San Ricardo bank.
Consider this the final meeting of bean club.
I should scramble you with onions!
You should never have come back!
Pequeno! Wait!
- Do not fight them, please.
- Mom, listen to me! I can explain.
No! Puss, not more running!
Please stop breaking my heart
and face what you have done.
I'm sorry, Mama. I let you down.
Paws where we can see them!
Turn around... slow!
Guard!
Step into the carrier! Quietlike!
Attention, attention everyone,
If you could move a little closer!
Ladies and gentlemen, I present
legendary the golden goose of legend!
Kitty? Not you too.
Gold for everyone!
We got some fresh hot gold here,
folks!
Step right up!
Get it hot!
One hat. One belt. And two boots...
... Once a symbol of honor.
One bottle of catnap...
Uh...it is for my glaucoma.
This is where you belong, outlaw!
And this is where you will stay forever.
Don't stop on my account.
It looks like the egg got what he wanted.
- You talking about Humpty?
- Ublee..ublee...umm! Don't say his name!
I used to share this cell
with that smelly thing.
Happiest day of my life was when he left.
till I realized he stole my magic beans.
Wait! Wait! Wait! You had the beans?
Who are you?
Hey! What's your name?
Uuh! Andy Beanstalk,
my parents call me Jack.
I traded the family cow for them beans.
Of course it wasn't my family's cow,
some others family's family cow.
That's why I got eight to ten year.
Always know which cow's you're...
Crazy man! Wake up!
What else do you know?
We're all goners! Thanks to that little stinky.
I told him! I told him not to take the goose,
but all he wanted was his revenge.
Don't take the goose. Why?
The Great Terror! That's the golden goose's mom.
Oh, no.
And she will be out for blood
when she comes back for her baby!
Guard! San Ricardo is
in terrible danger!
- You must listen to me!
- Quiet you!
Shut up!
Open the door ...
Drop the weapon!
Very good!
Step aside!
No! Diablo gato!
Nice try!
I hope you can forgive me.
Apology accepted!
I don't really have time for you.
I have to save the town from The Great Terror.
Wait, Puss!
Don't you see, I'm here because...
I am here because you made me realize
that there is something I can care about more than gold.
- Some thing?
- Okay, someone.
He's about two feet tall, wears high heels.
- Handsome?
- He's very handsome!
A real beefcake?
- A stallion? Yes.
- Tiger? Oh, brother ...
But, this does not make us even.
Freeze!
- Yes it does!
- No, it doesn't!
I saved you!
You owed me one.
You didn't tell me about Humpty.
So now you owe me two.
- Oh, you are a lot of work.
- I know, but I am worth it!
You are not getting away, Puss in boots!
Oh boots!
- Kitty!
- Now we're even!
This is your San Ricardo weather report.
The chances of giant goose
destroying the town ...
100%
... 100%.
never alone. Always together.
- Humpty and Puss ...
- Brother forever
Come on, sweetie. Let's get out of here
come before Momma shows up.
I shall make you into an egg salad sandwich!
Aah! That is disgusting!
- Give me the goose, Humpty!
- No can do, I'm afraid.
See the mama's on her way and when she gets here,
it's bye bye San Ricardo and everything
you ever cared about.
Revenge on me is one thing;
but why Imelda?
Why the orphanage?
This is our home!
You mean your home!
I...I never belonged here.
We had a plan to get out of here,
but then you became a hero
and you picked this place over me.
You left me with nothing!
Humpty, I'm sorry I hurt you.
But do not take it out on these people.
You are better than this.
No, I'm not.
Oh, come on! I know the real Humpty.
The way you saw the world,
the inventor, the dreamer.
What happened to that guy?
I think it's too late!
It is never too late to do the right thing.
Together, we can save San Ricardo.
I can forgive you, Humpty, if you help me now.
I'll try!
- Really? After everything put you through?
- Prove to me there is still a good egg in you!
Run!
Googles ... check.
Get the baby over the bridge.
I'll get the mother to follow.
Give me a puuuu!
Mother Goose!
Wait! Just follow me and
I'll lead you to your baby!
No! Not that way!
Pequeno! Help!
Hang on!
I got you!
That's my boy!
Come with me, mamam goose!
I know where your baby is! Here!
- Humpty, Pick up the pace!
- I'm trying, Puss! I'm trying!
Sorry, Egghead.
We want more than just egg.
So how about give us that goose?
Humpty!
- Nice moves!
- What would you do without me?
Freeze!
Commandante! I can explain!
Gato, you are going back to jail,
if it's the last thing I do!
Humpty, hurry!
We're almost there!
- Puss! Help!
- Humpty! Hang on!
Here we are again. Right, Puss?
I will not leave you behind this time, Humpty.
I'm sorry, Puss.
I've made a mess out of everything.
I am a rotten egg!
I'm not...I'm not a person. I'm not a bird,
I'm not even a food.
I don't know what I am!
You are what you have always been, my brother!
Brothers forever!
- You can't save us both!
- Yes, I can. Just hang on!
Puss, you have to save the baby,
or the mama will destroy San Ricardo.
It's the right thing to do.
I will not let you go, Humpty!
I know you won't, so I won't make you choose.
Humpty!
I'm very sorry. She's okay!
Humpty,
I always knew that you were good inside.
Goodbye, Humpty.
It's him, Puss in boots!
- He saved us from the giant goose!
- His sword is like lightning!
They said he has ten lives!
His boots are made
of the finest leather!
He drinks whole milk.
Good legend!
He is no outlaw. He saved us!
Meow!
A gift for you, Mama.
I have to go,
the soldiers are coming for me.
I am so proud of you, my son.
Today you faced the past with bravery and honor.
You earned those boots and the people know
that you are San Ricardo's greatest hero.
I did it for you, Mom.
- You will always be in my heart!
- And you in mine.
Gato!
Here he is! I see him!
- I will see you again, Kitty Softpaws!
- Sooner than you think.
She is a bad kitty!
This is the story of a cat who became a hero,
An outlaw dedicated to justice
and a lover of beautiful women.
A great, great lover...
Really, it is crazy
I am Puss in Boots
And my name would become legend.
www.moviesubtitles.org