♪ Our glorious city
♪ Was built
by the divinities ♪
♪ By gods
who saw fit ♪
♪ To bestow
♪ The gift of a paradise
♪ Peaceful and harmonious
Upon ♪
♪ Us mere mortals
below ♪
♪ And made El Dorado
♪ The magnificent
and golden ♪
♪ One thousand years ago
♪ El Dorado
El Dorado ♪
♪ El Dora-a-a-a-do
Today, we sail...
to conquer
the new world...
for Spain, for glory,
for gold!
Viva Cortes!
Altivo, eyes forward.
Seven!
All right!
- Yes!
- Partner! Hee-hee!
♪ Tons of gold for you
Hey!
♪ Tons of gold for me
♪ Tons of gold for we
Hey!
One more roll!
Uh, guys,
you're broke!
- You got nothin' to bet with!
- Oh, yeah? I got this!
- A map!
- A map? - A map!
A map of the wonders
of the new world.
Wow!
Let's have a look.
Uh, Tulio!
- Excuse us, for one moment, please.
- Tulio, look!
El Dorado,
the city of gold.
This could be
our destiny, our fate.
Miguel, if I believed
in fate,
I wouldn't be playing
with loaded dice.
Hmm. Not with the face.
No, no, no, no, no.
No! No! No!
I said one more roll!
My map against your cash.
Hmm?
All right, peewee.
You're on! Not with those!
This time we use my dice.
Ehh, got a problem with that?
No.
I'm going to kill you.
Come on, baby.
Papa needs that crappy map.
Stop that!
Show me seven!
- Seven!
- All right!
Seven!
There it is! Well,
nice doing business with you.
I knew it!
Your dice are loaded!
What?
You gave me loaded dice?
He gave me loaded dice!
Guard, arrest him!
You dare to impugn my honor?
He was the one
who was cheating!
Arrest him!
He tricked these sailors and took their money!
Oh, now I'm the thief?
Yes.
Take a look
in the mirror, pal!
Oh, you better give them
that money back, or I'll...
- En garde!
- En garde, yourself.
I will give you the honor
of a quick and painless death.
But not with that. Ha!
I prefer to fight fairly. Aha!
Well, any last words?
I will
cut you to ribbons,
fool!
Such mediocrity.
Let your sword
do the talking.
I will. It will be loquacious to a fault!
Ha! Take that!
- You... mincing, fencing, twit.
- Ah, you fight like my sister.
I fought your sister.
That's a compliment.
Blackguard!
Heathen!
Kill him!
- Not the face. Not the face.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we've decided it's a draw.
Thank you all for coming.
- You've been great. See you soon.
- Adios!
Congratulations. You're very good.
No. That was good.
Very...
We should have kept our swords,
I think. Y-Yeah.
Yeah, I've got a plan.
What is it?
Uh, well... Uh, you...
pet him, and... I'll... Yeah.
Run!
Uh, well,
thanks a lot!
Whoa!
There they are!
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
Bye. Thank you!
♪ Ole
Uhh...
Ohh...
I'll bet
we can make that.
There they are!
- Two pesetas says we can't.
You're on!
You lose!
Ohhh! Whoa!
What's happening here?
We're both in barrels.
That's the extent of my knowledge.
Okay, Miguel,
we gotta move fast.
On three, we jump out and head for the dock.
Good. Good. Excellent.
One, two, three...
Th-Three!
Three! Ohh!
Three!
Uh, you ready? Ah, okay.
One more. Let's go.
One, two, three!
Excuse us. Okay.
We're outta here.
Who ordered
the, uh, pickles?
Cortes!
My crew was as carefully chosen
as the disciples of Christ.
And I will not
tolerate stowaways.
You will be flogged.
And when we put into Cuba to resupply,
God willing, you will
be flogged some more...
and then enslaved
on the sugar plantations...
for the rest
of your miserable lives.
To the brig.
All right!
Cuba!
Hey, Altivo!
Ah-ta-ta, not for you!
You're on half rations.
Orders from Cortes.
So, uh, how's the...
How's the escape plan coming?
All right.
All right. Wait!
I'm getting something.
Yeah.
Okay!
Here's the plan.
In the dead of night,
you and I grab some provisions, Mm-hm.
Hijack one
of those longboats,
and then we row back to Spain
like there's no manana!
Back to Spain, yeah?
Yeah.
In a rowboat.
You got it!
Great. Sensational.
And that-that's your plan, is it?
That's pretty much it.
Well, I like it.
So, how do we get on deck?
Umm.
In the dead of night,
you and I grab some provisions,
hijack one of those longboats... Uh, great.
Okay, what's
your idea, smart guy?
Wh-Wh-What do you mean? Don't ask me that!
You're the one with the plans.
Wait, I...
I have an idea.
Uh, come on. Give me...
Give me a boost.
Hey, Altivo.
Altivo.
You want a nice apple?
Come and get it.
You have to do
a trick for me first.
Huh?
All you have to do
is find a pry bar.
A long piece of iron with a hooky thing at the end.
Yeah?
Miguel, you're
talking to a horse!
That's it, Altivo,
find the pry bar.
Yes, find the pry bar.
He can't
understand "pry bar."
He's a dumb horse.
There's no way...
Well,
it's not a pry bar.
Oh, Altivo.
Oh, thank you, old boy.
Listen, if we can
ever return the favor...
For Pete's sake, Miguel,
he's a ruthless warhorse, not a poodle.
Come on,
before he licks you to death.
Adios.
Shh, shh. Shh.
Quiet, please.
What's the matter with him?
Oh, he wants his apple.
Well, give it to him
before he wakes the whole ship!
Fetch!
Huh?
Hmm?
Altivo! Huh?
Miguel!
Altivo, I'm coming!
Just hang on!
I'm right here, old boy!
Have you lost your mind?
Help is coming!
Ho-o-ly ship!
Whoa!
Loop the rope under the horse!
Yes!
On the count of three,
pull back on the rope.
What?
Three!
Pull!
Tulio!
Hey, it worked!
Did any
of the supplies make it?
Well, uh, yes and no.
Ohhh, great!
Look on the positive side.
At least things can't get...
Excuse me.
We're you going to say "worse"?
No. No. No?
You're sure?
Absolutely not. I've revised the whole thing.
Okay, because...
Yeah, we're at least in a rowboat.
We're in a rowboat, exactly.
You miss nothing.
Ahh!
Tulio, did you ever imagine
it would end like this?
The horse
is a surprise.
Any...
regrets?
Besides dying?
Yeah.
I never...
had enough... gold.
My regret,
besides dying, is...
our greatest adventure
is over before it began,
and no one
will even remember us.
Well, if it's
any consolation, Miguel,
you...
made my life...
an adventure.
And if it's
any consolation, Tulio,
you made my life... rich.
Is it?
Hmm.
It is!
It's... It's... It's... It's... It's...
It's land!
All in favor of getting back
in the boat, say "aye."
Aye!
Aye! Go!
Hey, Miguel!
I could use a little help!
Miguel!
Hello!
Tulio!
We've done it!
What's that? The map?
It's all right here!
You still have
the map?
The whistling rock!
The stream!
You kept the map,
but you couldn't grab a little more food?
Even those mountains.
You said so yourself:
It coul be possible.
And it is!
It really is...
the map to El Dorado!
You drank seawater,
didn't you? Oh, come on!
I'm not coming on!
I wouldn't set foot in that jungle for a million pesetas!
- How about a hundred million?
- What?
I just thought that, after all,
since El Dorado is the city of gold...
- What's your point?
- You know, dust, nuggets, bricks,
a temple of gold where you can
pluck gold from the very walls.
But you don't
want to go, so let's...
get back into the boat
and row back to Spain.
After all,
it worked so well last time. Wait!
Mmm. Wait a minute.
New plan.
We find the city of gold.
We take the gold,
and then we go back to Spain.
And buy Spain!
Yeah!
That's the spirit!
Come on, Tulio.
We'll follow that trail! What trail?
The trail that we blaze!
That trail
that we blaze!
Oh, no, you don't.
Yeow! Your horse
bit me in the butt!
♪ Look out new world
Here we come ♪
♪ Brave, intrepid
Charge!
♪ And then some
♪ Pioneers of maximum
audacity ♪
♪ Whose resumes show that we are just the team ♪
♪ To live where others merely
dream ♪ What are you looking at?
♪ Building up our head of steam ♪ Whoa!
♪ On the trail we blaze
♪ Changing legend
into fact ♪
♪ We shall
ride into history ♪
♪ Turning myth into truth
♪ We shall surely gaze
♪ On the sweet unfolding
♪ Of an antique mystery
♪ All will be revealed
♪ On the trail we blaze
Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
♪ On the trail
On the trail we blaze ♪
Dinner is served.
Hello.
♪ Paradise is close at hand
♪ Shangri-la
♪ The promised land
♪ Seventh heaven on demand
♪ Quite unusual nowadays
♪ Virgin vistas undefiled
♪ Minds and bodies
running wild ♪
♪ In the man
behold a child ♪
♪ On the trail we blaze
♪ The trail we blaze
♪ Is road uncharted
♪ Through terra incognita
to a golden shrine ♪
♪ No place for the traveler
♪ To be fainthearted
♪ We are part of a sumptuous
grand design ♪
♪ Changing legend into fact
♪ We shall ride into history
♪ Turning myth into truth
♪ We shall surely gaze
♪ On the sweet unfolding
♪ Of an antique mystery
♪ All will be revealed
♪ On the trail we blaze
Hmm.
Miguel. Miguel, wake up.
We're there. Oh, yeah.
We found it. We found it? Oh!
Fantastic!
Where is it? How far?
Right here! Here.
Where? Behind the rock?
No, no.
This is it.
Give me that!
This ca-What?
Apparently, "El Dorado"
is native for...
"great, big... rock"!
Hey, but I tell you what, I'm feeling generous,
so you can have my share!
You don't think Cortes could've
gotten here before us and...
And what? Taken all
the real big rocks?
The scoundrel!
Tulio, you...
We have to think about this.
We've come all this way,
and we-we-we should really,
you know... Get... on...
the horse!
No, no, no,
not with the face. Stop.
Looks like there's
a pass right over there.
Ohh!
Hyah!
I've...
Uh, hello.
Is this your rock?
Sorry. We were just looking.
We're, uh...
We're tourists!
Tourist.
We-We lost our group.
May we go now?
Spears.
Hey! Hey!
Oh, my...
It's... It's...
El Dorado.
Oh!
Mmm. Ah!
Well, it was nice working
with you, partner.
Tulio, I just
want you to know...
I'm sorry about
that girl in Barcelona.
So... You... You,
f... Behold!
As the prophesies foretold,
the time of judgment
is now!
Citizens, did I not predict
that the gods would come to us?
Hmm.
My lords,
I am Tzekel-Kan,
your devoted high priest
and speaker for the gods.
Hey.
I am Chief Tannabok.
What names may we call you?
Huh?
I am Miguel.
And I am Tulio.
And they call us
Miguel and Tulio!
Your arrival has been
greatly anticipated.
My lords,
how long will you be staying in El Dorado?
Aha! I see you've captured
this temple-robbing thief.
How would you have us punish her?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
My lord, I am not a thief.
See, the gods
sent me a vision...
to bring them tribute from the
temple to guide them here.
My only wish
is to serve the gods.
Release her,
don't ya think?
Then you will begin
by returning this...
to its rightful place.
My lords, why now
do you choose to visit us?
Enough! You do not question...
the gods!
That's right!
Do not question us,
or we shall have to unleash
our awesome and terrible power!
And you don't want that!
- Well, yes! We do!
- You do?
Of course we do!
Visit your wrath upon this nonbeliever!
Show us the truth
of your divinity!
Divinity!
One moment.
Miguel, you know that
little voice people have...
that tells them to quit
when they're ahead?
You don't have one!
Well, I'm sorry. I got carried away!
- Way away!
- Maybe we should tell the truth and beg for mercy.
Are you nuts?
We'd be butchered alive!
Yes, but they're
getting suspicious.
And if we don't come up
with some mega-cosmic event...
I'm trying! I'm trying!
I can't think with all these distractions!
You... Horse... Think horse.
Think, think, think.
I'm on the verge of... Stop!
Don't make me
start it up again,
'cause I will.
O mighty lords!
Come.
Let me show you to your temple.
All right!
Temple.
Step aside.
To commemorate your arrival,
I propose a reverent ceremony at dawn.
Ah, then perhaps I could prepare
a glorious feast for you tonight.
Which would
you prefer?
Both.
Both. Both.
Both is good.
My lords.
And so dawns
the Age of the Jaguar.
Happy new year.
Hey!
Hey. Hey.
Tulio. Tulio.
They actually think we're gods.
It's
an entire city of suckers.
We just have to keep
this up long enough...
to load up on the gold and then get the hell out of here!
Tulio, we'll be living
like kings!
- Miguel and Tulio!
- Tulio and Miguel!
Mighty and powerful gods.
Gods.
Hello.
Depart, mortal,
before we strike you with a lightning bolt.
Mmm. Mmmm!
Beware the wrath
of the gods! Begone!
Save it for the high priest,
honey. You're gonna need it.
Miguel,
it's not working.
Miguel!
We've been caught.
Oh, no. Don't worry
about me, boys.
"My only wish is to serve the gods."
Remember?
- How?
- Well, if you guys want the gold,
then you don't want
to get caught, right?
You're going to need my help.
- What makes you think we need your help?
"Ck-ck."
Are you serious?
I... What... We...
Okay. So, uh,
who are you?
Yeah, uh,
what's your angle? No angle.
- I want in.
- In?
On the scam.
There's no scam!
Why would you think there's a...
- Why?
- So I can get out.
I thought she just said
she wanted in?
She wants in
so she can get out.
Aha! Got it.
- W-Why?
- Think you're the only ones who dream of better things?
Of adventure?
You've got your reasons,
and I've got mine.
Let's not make it
personal, okay?
- It's just business.
- Oh.
So when you guys
are ready to go back to...
wherever you came from,
I'm going with you.
No!
Don't think so.
All right. Fine.
After all,
I'm sure you know...
the proper rituals for blessing a tribute,
the holiest days on the calendar...
Oh, and of course you know
all about Xibalba.
Okay? Good luck.
See you at the execution.
Wait! Ho... Would you...
Hold it.
Deal?
Hmm.
Deal. Not yet.
Let's just see how this works out.
Uh-huh.
Well, then I suppose that means you'll want these back?
How'd you get those?
Where was she keeping them?
Call me, Chel,
your new partner. Uh,
that's partner-in-training.
Now, put these on.
Your public's waiting.
Do you mind?
No.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Right. Uh, excuse me.
Bye.
Mm-mm-mmm!
Maybe they should call this place "Chel Dorado."
She's whoo...
Whoa, she's trouble!
Wait a minute! What?
The little voice...
Remember the little voice?
Ju-Ju-Just for a second
imagine that you have one.
What would it
be saying about Chel?
No. No. Listen.
We are partners.
We have a plan, remember?
Get the gold. Go back to Spain.
Yes! And we are
pretending to be gods.
Now, put Chel in the mix.
What is the voice saying?
Listen carefully.
Chel is off-limits, hmm?
Bravo! Chel is off-limits!
Shake on it.
Off-limits. Mm.
Mm. Mmmm.
Besides, we're supposed
to be gods.
We must avoid
giving in to temptation.
Gods. Oh. This is gonna to be tougher than I thought.
Tulio, relax!
All you have to do is smile,
act godly and follow my lead.
Big smile.
Like you mean it.
A-one, two, three.
♪ I hardly think
I'm qualified ♪
♪ To come across
all sanctified ♪
♪ I just don't cut it
with the cherubim ♪
Tulio, what are you
talking about?
♪ There again
they're on their knees ♪
♪ Being worshipped
is a breeze ♪
♪ Which rather
suits us in ♪
♪ The interim ♪ Interim,
interim It's me and him ♪
Oh, my God!
♪ It's tough to be a god
♪ Tread where mortals
have not trod ♪
♪ Be deified when really
you're a sham ♪
♪ Be an object
of devotion ♪
♪ Be the subject of psalms
♪ It's a rather
touching notion ♪
♪ All those prayers
and those salaams ♪
♪ And who am I to bridle
♪ If I'm forced
to be an idol ♪
♪ If they say that
I'm a god ♪
♪ That's what I am
♪ What's more
if we don't comply ♪
♪ With the locals' wishes
♪ I can see us
being sacrificed ♪
- ♪ Or stuffed
- You have a point there. Very good thinking.
♪ So let's be gods The perks are great ♪ Yeah!
♪ El Dorado on our plates
Thank you.
♪ Local feelings
should not ♪
♪ Be rebuffed
♪ Never rebuffed
♪ I never rebuff a local feeling No,
my friend ♪
♪ It's tough to be a god
♪ But if you get
the people's nod ♪
♪ Count your blessings
Yeah, keep 'em sweet ♪
♪ That's our advice
It's great advice!
♪ Be a symbol of perfection
♪ Be a legend
Be a cult ♪
♪ Take their praise
Take a collection ♪
♪ As the multitudes exalt
♪ Don a supernatural habit
♪ We'd be crazy not to grab it ♪ You got it!
♪ So sign on two new gods
♪ For paradise
♪ Par-a-dise
Good morning, my lords!
He's back!
Oh, no.
And now it's my turn!
The gods have awakened!
Whoa!
Mm-hmm.
- Hey, Chel, what's going on?
- It's not gonna be good.
Thank you.
This city has been
granted a great blessing.
And what have we done
to show our gratitude?
A meager celebration.
The god's deserve
a proper tribute!
Hmm.
The beginning of a new era,
the dawning of a new age...
demands...
sacrifice!
I don't like this.
Tulio, we've got to do something.
Stop!
Hmm?
This is not
a proper tribute!
You do not
want the tribute?
No. No, no.
W-We want tribute.
Uh, it's just that, uh...
Tulio, tell him.
The stars are not in position for this tribute!
Like he says,
the stars...
Can't do it.
Not today.
Ah.
Perhaps it is possible
I misread... the heavens.
Don't worry about it.
To err is human, to forgive... Hmm.
My lords,
may the people of El Dorado offer you our tribute.
does this please you?
Yes, very nice.
Certainly acceptable.
Yes, lovely. It'll do.
The gods have chosen!
To Xibalba?
No. No.
To Xibalba!
Oh, great.
Hey, Chel, um,
what are they doing?
They're sending it to Xibalba,
the spirit world.
The spirit world.
I'll take care of it.
Um, excuse me, Chief.
The gods have changed their minds about Xibalba.
They wish to bask in the reverence
that has been shown them.
Stop!
They wish to bask!
Take the tribute
to the gods' temple!
Nice going.
Smile while you can.
Well, well, well,
what have we here?
Ai-ai-ai.
♪ Tons of gold for you, hah
♪ And tons of gold for me, hoo
♪ Tons of gold for we, ah
Not bad for a day's work, eh?
Not bad at all.
We just became richer
than the king of Spain.
You know, speaking of kings,
the chief and high priest seem a bit, uh, tense.
Buenos Dias!
Listen, all we have to do...
is keep playing
the o against the other.
You know, do a little god dance,
chant some mystic mumbo jumbo,
dazzle 'em with some smoke and mirrors
and then get the hell back to Spain.
Um, Tulio, how are we gonna
get all this back to Spain?
Ummm...
A boat?
Yeah.
Um, we really hate
to be ascending so soon,
but, uh, some urgent
business has come up...
family matters...
and it's just a bit... Yeah, family.
Badda-bing, budda-boom,
you know what I mean.
Oh, we expected you
to be staying with us...
for the next...
thousand years.
Well, as we say
in the spirit world,
there's your plan and then...
there's the gods' plan. Mm-hmm.
And our plan, uh, calls for a boat,
'cause we're gonna ascend...
kind of in a horizontal
pattern at first.
And then we're gonna go vertical, uh,
as we get further out to sea.
Hmm. To build a boat
large and glorious enough...
would take... about a week.
A week? Hmm.
Um...
I wonder how long it would take Tzekel-Kan to do it.
But... But for the gods,
uh, three days.
Uh...
Well, if that's the best
you can do.
Oh, perhaps if you were not
burdened with so much tribute,
you could leave sooner.
Hmm? Hmm?
I like it here. Miguel?
Yep, yep.
Three days is just fine.
No, three days is not fine.
This is a real...
Mmm.
These... these are the ones... problem.
Oh. Thank you.
Miguel, how are we gonna
keep this up for three days?
You worry too much.
No, I worry exactly
the right amount.
You can never
worry too much.
We just have to lie low.
But, Tulio, this place is amazing!
I mean, I wonder what's...
No! Don't even move!
- Tulio...
- You're moving!
- A little, but... Come on.
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Stay!
- I gotta... I...
Just... stand there!
I just...
For three days?
Yes! Exactly.
For three days.
Don't even breathe. All right?
All right.
We lie low.
No, ah, ah, ah, ah.
Promise?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right, all right.
Great! Good. Okay.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to gloat over my gold.
Oh, yum, yum, yum.
It's beautiful,
isn't it? Yeah!
You know,
you really shouldn't miss it. I know.
But I-I couldn't.
Go ahead.
I'll cover for you.
Oh, good. Thanks.
So, what happened to Altivo?
I don't know.
♪ Tulio goes for paradise
Hey, what happened to Miguel?
I don't know.
Oh, my God! He's gone!
Miguel's gone!
He's loose!
What am I gonna do?
Oh, no, no!
Oh, Miguel is right.
You worry too much.
Oh. Ooh.
Oh, yeah. Oh, oh,
down, down, down, down.
No! No!
Big trouble.
Whoa!
Look, sweetheart,
we're in the middle of a con here,
walking
the razor's edge.
On the one hand, gold!
On the other hand,
painful, agonizing failure!
I can't afford any tempta...
uh, distractions.
So, I'm sorry.
So sorry.
But perhaps another time?
Another place, hmm?
Too bad.
I'm free now.
I'm... not really sure
I trust you.
Mmm, I'm not really
asking you to trust me.
Am I?
Whoo.
'Kay.
Ooh, yeah.
Excuse me. Excuse me?
Hey, where is everybody?
They've been cleared
from the streets, my lord,
so the city can be cleansed,
as you ordered.
Cleansed?
Yes.
So the Age of the Jaguar
can begin,
as you ordered, my lord.
Get back in!
- Where are you going?
- Hey, stop that!
- Move!
What are you doing?
Stop that!
But, my lord, anyone
who disobeys your orders...
must be punished,
as you ordered.
It seems I've been giving
a lot of orders, haven't I?
Tzekel-Kan has made
your commands clear, my lord.
Really?
Take the day off.
Huh?
Are you all right?
Here.
Oh, no!
It's all right. Please.
Hey, Altivo.
There you are.
Oh.
♪ The more I learn
♪ The more I see
♪ The less the world
impassions me ♪
♪ The hungry heart
♪ The roving eye
♪ Have come to rest
♪ Do not apply
♪ The frantic chase
♪ The crazy ride
♪ The thrill has gone
♪ I step aside
♪ I'd believe
♪ In anything
♪ Were it not for you
♪ Showing me by just existing
♪ Only this is true
♪ I love you
♪ Without question
♪ I'd believe in anything
♪ Were it not for you
♪ Showing me by just existing
Only this is true ♪
♪ Oh, I love you
Hmm. This is not
what I expected.
Perhaps Lord Tulio
will enlighten me.
How do I look?
Oh, uh... Well, you...
Oh, shut up.
Oh! Whoa!
My lord?
- Hello?
- The high priest. - Ow!
What's he gonna think if he finds
one of the gods like this with me?
Uh, lucky god?
J-Just-Just-Just...
Hello?
Whoa!
Oh, Tzekel-Kan!
What brings you here?
I-I-I-I-I humbly request an audience with you, my lord.
- Yes, what can I do for you? - My lord,
I have just seen Lord Miguel out among the people.
- Really?
- If I may be so bold as to offer some advice.
All right. Shoot.
My lord,
you are perfect.
Oh, well. Go on.
But in your perfection,
you cannot know how imperfect humans are.
Like snakes they are.
Spineless and slippery.
They are as untrustworthy as rats,
stealing and cheating with no remorse.
Spinning webs of lies,
like spiders!
Stop it!
That's disgusting.
They're beyond disgusting!
Yeah, yeah, way beyond.
Then we're in agreement.
I'll begin the necessary
preparations immediately.
Do you wish to have your victims bound to an altar,
or would you prefer them free-range?
And will you be devouring
their essence whole...
or piece by piece?
Tzekel, you've lost me.
My lord,
these people will not respect you if they do not fear you.
And, of course, we'll make them
fear us by...
A sacrifice,
as it is prophesied.
The history of the Age of the
Jaguar will be written in... Ink?
Blood!
Blood! Oh, right.
Of course.
I should probably consult with Lord Miguel.
This is fairly important stuff. I, um,
should discuss the entire, uh,
blood issue right away.
Excuse us, won't you?
Let's go.
Finally... we're connecting.
This way.
What do you think you're doing?
- Lying low.
Look, change of plans.
We have to grab what we can carry
and get out of here now! What? Why?
Because the high priest
is nuts! He wants...
- This is unacceptable!
- Yeah. Yeah. Like he said.
The gods should not
be playing ball like this!
- Well, exactly!
- This is how the gods should play ball!
Well, don't blame me.
I blame you.
What is the object
of this game, pray tell?
You've gotta knock the ball
through the hoop.
What hoop?
That hoop.
That's impossible.
- We're gonna lose.
- Gods don't lose.
Heep-ha!
My lords, Chief Tannabok's warriors
are the finest ballplayers in the city.
Fifteen mere mortals
against two gods.
I realize it's a bit uneven,
Heep-ha!
But I do hope they'll challenge you
enough to make the game... interesting.
Play ball!
Crush them into the dust.
Enjoy.
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
D'oh. D'oh.
My lords,
were you not supposed
to put the ball into play?
Ohh!
Well,
no, no, no, no, no...
We were merely demonstrating the, um, traditional, uh,
first avoidance maneuver.
Ah.
I've never heard
of such a thing.
Excuse me.
Who invented this game?
Why, the gods,
of course.
I'm warning you,
don't push your luck with this guy.
But, Tulio,
we're the gods.
Tulio!
The hip! The hip!
This is impossible.
Excuse me?
- Heep...
- Haaa!
Heep-ha! Heep-ha!
Foul! That was a foul!
New ball!
How long does this
go on anyway?
The game is over when the shadow touches this line.
We need a miracle.
No, we need to cheat.
Yes!
Huh?
Hey!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Ole!
Huh?
Hmm.
Yes!
Who's the god?
You de god.
No, you the god.
Fine. No, you de god.
Y-Yeah! Yeah!
Guys, it's here!
It's right here with me!
Mmm.
I love this game!
Yes!
Well done, partner.
- Yes! Yes!
- My lords, congratulations on your victory.
And now, you will, of course,
wish to have the losing team...
sacrificed to your glory.
Not again.
Look, Tzekel-Kan,
Uh, Miguel?
Forget the sacrifices.
Miguel.
We don't want any sacrifices.
But all of the sacred writings say that you
will devour the wicked and the unrighteous.
Well, I don't see anyone here
who fits that description.
Well, as speaker
for the gods,
it would be my privilege
to point them out.
The gods are speaking
for themselves now!
This city and these people...
have no need
for you anymore!
There will be no sacrifices!
Not now, not ever!
Get out!
Mmm. As the...
gods... command.
Whoa! Who-o-oa!
Hey, not bad for my
first commandment, huh?
Miguel, the little voice...
Yeah, fine.
Do you know why
the gods demand blood?
I don't know.
Because gods don't bleed.
It's time to take the future
into my own hands,
and this city
will be cleansed.
Even if I
have to do it myself.
Uh, how?
There are dark magics here...
and power... and...
Ooh. My, my, my,
my, my.
It's not called the Age of the Jaguar for nothing.
This'll be a delightful way to
bid the false gods... good-bye.
Hmm.
Audios, muchacho!
- Well, it's, um, uh, nice.
- Nice?
Yes, nice.
But?
Um, but, uh, is it
really fit for the gods?
My lord.
I have been around boats,
believe me,
and that, um...
the pointy, tall, um...
the-the-the-the long
up and down thing...
The mast? The mast, yes, yes.
The mast is good.
Well, look at it.
There's not nearly enough, uh,
um, rope.
- Rope?
- Yes, rope. Exactly my point.
Vertical ascension requires
a lot more, uh, rope.
- My lord.
- And look at this.
This doesn't look
at all secure.
Chief, I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
but all in all, it is a complete do-over.
Hmm.
You know, Lord Miguel,
if you wish to stay,
you only need to say so.
- You mean... forever?
- Of course.
Oh, no, I can't.
I have to go back with Tulio.
We're... We're partners.
Big plans
in the other world, huh?
Yep. Big plans.
Well, then, I better
go get some more rope, huh?
Oh, Chief, um,
forget about the rope.
Um, my mistake.
Hey, to err is human.
- Half?
- Mm-hmm.
I don't think so.
I-I'll tell you what.
Uh, I'll let you come back to Spain with us,
like you wanted, and, um, yeah,
I can see my way clear to throwing you,
mmm, ten percent?
You know, maybe I won't go to
Spain with you and take a third.
Ohh!
Like you don't
wanna go to Spain.
Oh, like you don't want me
to want to go to Spain.
I want you to want...
what you want. Mm-hmm?
Mm-hmm. Go on.
All right.
Cards on the table.
Uh, I want you to come to Spain with me and Miguel.
Mostly me.
Especially me.
Only me.
Forget Miguel.
Well, as long as that's
what you want.
Me too.
Okay.
Deal?
Deal. Mmm.
"Forget Miguel"?
Well, forget Tulio.
Well, is it ready yet?
Ooh.
Ah!
Ahh! Hmm.
It seems to be
missing something.
Ah, that's it.
It needs more... body.
Do... as I command!
The gods deserve
a proper tribute.
Stop! There will be
no sacrifices!
That kid does you
better than you do.
Some send-off, huh?
We're finally at the "go back to
Spain and live like kings" part.
Ooh-hoo-hoo.
Well, isn't king kind of a step down from god?
What? Wh-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Miguel, we can't stay here.
We have a plan, remember?
How about...
we forget the plan? Hmm?
What?
Now everyone will know
the truth of your divinity.
I'm okay!
I'm still okay!
Come on! Get on!
Altivo, hyah!
Whoa!
Tulio!
Hey, over here,
you big Tzekel-Kan cat creep!
Altivo, get Chel out of here.
Duck!
Who-o-o-oa!
Move! Move!
Jump!
Who-o-o-a!
I know what you are,
and I know what you are not!
And you are not gods!
Y... You're not a god?
You lied to me?
How dare you!
Hey, it was his stupid plan!
- What?
- Oh, oh, oh. My plan was that we should lie low!
But your plan was to run off and be all "Oh,
look at me. Look at me. I'm a god."
- That's not true!
- No? Who are you kidding?
You're buying your own con!
At least I'm not dating mine.
I... Ooh, low blow.
Listen, Mr. High and Mighty, we'd both be
sailing out of here with a mountain of gold...
if you had just
listened to me!
Well, now you've got all the precious gold and Chel.
So what do you need me for?
Well, maybe I don't
need you anymore.
Well, then, why don't you just go back to Spain,
and I'll stay here,
and we'll both
get what we want!
- That's... fine with me, pal!
- Fine with me too! - Ooh.
- Fine! - Ouch.
- Okay!
All right!
Tie him up!
What?
Whoa.
Jump!
Whoa!
No-o-o-o-o!
My lord.
Where did you get this?
That was good, huh?
Hey, a little help, please?
Chief Tanni! Chief Tanni!
- I've decided to stay.
- Oh, this is wonderful news.
What a glorious day
for El Dorado.
Lord Miguel has decided
to live among us!
Tulio!
Is everything okay?
Everything is... fine.
♪ There isn't much
♪ I haven't shared
♪ With you along the road
♪ And through it all
there'll always be ♪
♪ Tomorrow's episode
♪ Suddenly that isn't true
♪ There's another avenue
♪ Beckoning the great divide
♪ Ask no questions
♪ Take no side
♪ Who's to say
who's right or wrong ♪
♪ Who's course is braver run
♪ All I know is all we had
♪ Is over
♪ Said and done
♪ Friends never say good-bye
♪ Friends
♪ Never say good-bye
Ha!
Ahhh! Whew!
Mmm.
♪ Friends never say good-bye
Take care.
We'll miss you!
Thank you.
♪ Never say good-bye
♪ Friends never say
♪ Good-bye
♪ Friends
♪ Never say good-bye
Well, good luck.
Yeah. You too.
♪ Never
♪ Say good-bye
Whoa.
Whoa, boy, what is it?
- Cortes.
- My lord, what is it?
Chief Tanni!
Approaching the city...
is an army of strangers.
We are safe here.
They'll never find the gate to the city.
But, sire, they are being led
by Tzekel-Kan.
He survived! Warriors,
prepare yourselves for battle!
Chief, you cannot fight them!
Then how can we stop them?
We can't.
Hmm.
Uh, one moment, please.
Okay, here's the gate.
Here's the boat. Uh-huh. And?
Here's the gate.
Here's the boat. Okay.
Got that. And? Tulio! Well, here's the "goat,"
and here's the "bate."
That's it.
We'll crash the boat
into the pillars.
That's it?
I mean... But...
What about the gold?
Well...
Chief!
Chief.
I've got a plan.
Hold the line steady!
They're almost in place!
It better be there,
for your sake.
Okay, Chief, on my signal!
Ready! Hit the pillars!
Now!
- They're breaking too fast!
- Tulio, the sail!
It's stuck!
They're not gonna make it.
Altivo!
Are you crazy?
Get off the boat, Miguel,
or you'll never see the city again.
I know. You don't think I'm gonna
let you have all the fun, do you?
Come on.
We've got a wave to catch.
- Get out of the way!
- Huh?
Hold on!
Whoa!
We're gonna have to
hit it broadside!
That's your plan?
But the gold!
I know!
Just turn the boat!
On impact, everybody jump!
We made it.
It worked.
Wait. Get down!
Ouch. Ow.
There they are.
No.
You lying heathen.
There's nothing here at all.
No. Wait. Wait.
- Men, seize him!
- What?
There is no El Dorado here.
Onward, men.
Wait! No, wait!
Wait!
- Yes!
- Now, that was an adventure.
Yes. Yes, it was.
And, um,
it was so much gold!
I'm fine.
Good.
Let's go.
Partner.
Hey, guys, come on!
You don't wanna stay here
forever, do you?
But... we don't have a map.
We don't have a plan.
Well, that's what
makes it interesting.
You're right!
What are we waiting for?
Let's follow
that trail!
Hyah!
♪ Oh, the sweet unfolding
Come on, boys!
♪ Of an antique mystery
Hey, Altivo!
♪ All will be revealed Sit, boy! Sit!
Chel, we're not
on the horse!
♪ On the trail we blaze
Uh-Uhh.
Eh!
♪ Here comes the night
♪ Here come the memories
♪ Lost in your arms
♪ Down in the foreign fields
♪ Not so long ago
♪ Seems like eternity
♪ Those sweet afternoons
♪ Still capture me-e-e
♪ Someday out of the blue
♪ In a crowded street
♪ Or a deserted square
♪ I'll turn and I'll see you
♪ As if our love were new
♪ Someday we can start again
♪ Someday soon
♪ I still believe
♪ I still put faith in us
♪ We had it all
♪ And watched it slip away
♪ Where are we now
♪ Not where we want to be
♪ Those hot afternoons
♪ Still follow me-e-e
♪ Someday out of the blue
♪ Maybe years from now
♪ Or tomorrow night
♪ I'll turn and I'll see you
♪ As if we always knew
♪ Someday we would live again
♪ Someday soon
♪ I still believe I still put faith in us ♪ ♪ Believe
♪ I still believe
I still put faith in us ♪
♪ I still believe I still put faith in us ♪ ♪ Believe
♪ Here comes the night
♪ Here come the memories
♪ Lost in your arms
♪ Down in the foreign fields
♪ Not so long ago
♪ Seems like eternity
♪ Those sweet afternoons
♪ Still capture me-e-e
♪ Someday out of the blue
♪ Maybe years from now
♪ Or tomorrow night
♪ I'll turn and I'll see you
♪ As if we always knew
♪ Someday we would live again
♪ Someday soon
♪ The more I learn
♪ The more I see
♪ The less the world
impassions me ♪
♪ The hungry heart
♪ The roving eye
♪ Have come to rest
♪ Do not apply
♪ The frantic chase
♪ The crazy ride
♪ The thrill has gone
♪ I step aside
♪ And I'd believe
♪ In anything
♪ Were it not for you
♪ Showing me
♪ By just existing
♪ Only this is true
♪ I love you
♪ Without question
♪ The more I want
♪ The more I steal
♪ The more I hold
♪ The less is real
♪ All worldly things
♪ I follow blind
♪ In hope, not faith
♪ Was paid in kind
♪ The line is drawn
♪ The change is made
♪ I come to you
♪ I'm not afraid
♪ And I'd believe
♪ In anything
♪ Were it not for you
♪ Showing me
♪ By just existing
♪ Only this is true
♪ I love you