Ah!
Ho-ho!
Cracking job, Gromit.
Hang on, old chum.
- What's going on?
- Who is it?
Reel him in, lad.
To me. To me.
Gotcha! Thieving monster.
Ooh! Me prize pumpkin.
Me little baby.
Me pride and joy.
You've saved it,
Anti-Pesto.
It was nothing
at all, Mrs... Oh!
Ah! Oh, no!
Everything's under control.
- Don't worry, madam.
- Ah!
Thank you, Mr. Wallace.
All in a night's work,
Mrs. Mulch.
- Huh?
- Ah!
Cute little feller, isn't he?
You'd never believe
they'd cause so much damage.
Oh, he may
look innocent, sir.
But left to his own devices,
this is the ultimate
vegetable-destroying machine.
- Hee!
- Oh!
Reg, me teeth!
Job well done, lad.
Subject disarmed
and neutralized.
Bless you, Anti-Pesto.
With you out there
protecting our veg,
the most important event
of the year is safe.
Aye. And I hope they
give them pests what's
coming to 'em, and all.
Amen to that, Mrs. Mulch.
Whee!
Oh! Whee!
It was a long, hard night
last night, Gromit.
I'll need a good, hearty
breakfast under me belt.
Pile it up, lad.
I'm in the mood for food!
Oh, uh...
Gromit, old pal.
It's happened again.
I'll need assistance.
Ow! Oof!
Ah. Oh!
Well, thanks, chuck.
I'm sure that
hole's getting smaller.
Ah! Another successful night.
How are the inmates?
Must be getting
a bit full down there.
Talking of which.
Now, for a great big plate of...
vegetables.
A-ha!
Still got me on
the diet, eh, Gromit?
Watching me shape?
There's a good dog.
Oh, oh! Uh...
Gromit, lad?
How's that prize melon
of yours coming on?
Must be a while
since you measured it.
Mmm! Lovely food.
For rabbits, that is.
As for me, I need
something a bit more cheesy.
A-ha!
Ooh!
Oh!
Oh! Oh.
Caught red-handed, eh, lad?
I'm sorry, Gromit.
I know you're doing this
for my own good,
but the fact is
I'm just crackers about cheese.
Look, if I must change me ways,
at least let me do it my way.
With technology.
It's time we tried
my latest invention,
the Mind Manipulation-omatic.
Ha!
It extracts unwanted thoughts
and desires.
I haven't tested it yet,
but it should be perfectly safe.
Just a bit of harmless
brain alteration, that's all.
Uh-oh!
Anti-Pesto Humane Pest Control.
How might we be of assistance?
Ah, yes. Lady Tottington
here of Tottington Hall.
Your Ladyship.
This is an honor.
Oh! Ow!
It's a disaster. I have the
most terrible rabbit problem.
The competition's only
days away. You simply
have to do something.
Certainly, ma'am.
I think we're about
to go up in the world, lad.
Just stay right where
you are, your Ladyship,
and we'll be with you
in an... Ahh!
In an hour?
I can't wait an hour.
I have a major infestation.
Hmm? Hello? Hello?
Hmm.
Ah! That's more like it.
Thank goodness you've... Oh!
What ho! For you, my love.
Victor.
How lovely and...
unexpected.
Heard you had a spot of rabbit
bother and toodled on over
to sort the blighters out.
Gosh, that's... that's
awfully sweet of you.
But you really needn't bother.
It's no bother,
little boo-boo.
It's the least a chap
can do for his filly.
Don't want pests spoiling our
beautiful manor house, do we?
"Our" manor house?
No one's mentioned
marriage, Victor.
All in
good time, my dear.
Vermin first, though, what what.
Come on, Phillip.
Victor! We can deal
with this humanely.
Ho-ho!
Very classy.
Just the sort of client we
should be dealing with, eh, lad?
Oh!
Burrowing bounders!
They must be breeding like...
well, rabbits.
Only one thing for it, lad.
- Victor, hadn't we agreed?
- Hmm.
No more thoughtless killing.
Quite right, my dear.
So I've thought this one
through very carefully.
It's off to bunny heaven
for you, big ears.
Victor! No!
- Ah!
- What the...?
Champion
sucker, eh, Gromit?
The BunVac 6000.
Whee!
This'll impress her Ladyship.
I don't understand. It
should have been a bull's-eye.
Oh, Victor. I felt we'd
made a real breakthrough
with this hunting obsession
of yours. I really thought
you'd changed.
I'm sorry, Campanula,
but I am what I am.
There's no nonsense
with Victor Quartermaine.
What you see is what you get.
What the...?
Sounds like a really
big brute, this one.
Give it some more welly.
Gosh!
Maybe I should've
used a bigger nozzle.
Ah!
Anti-Pesto, you're here.
Oh!
Your Ladyship.
My darlings!
You're safe.
- Oh!
- My word!
What a fabulous job you've done.
And not a single one harmed.
Ah! The old
BV6000, ma'am.
Capable of 125 RPM.
That's rabbits per minute.
How inspired!
- Mr...?
- Oh, Wallace.
- Mr. Wallace.
- Mmm.
Is this all of them?
Oh, uh, just one left.
Hoist her up, Gromit.
Ah!
Victor, stop
fooling around in the dirt
and have a look at this.
The ingenious Anti-Pesto
have completely dealt
with my rabbit problem.
- Isn't it marvelous?
- Marvelous?
Marvelous?
This confounded contraption
virtually suffocated me!
Besides, the job's
only half done.
How do you intend
to finish these vermin off?
Crush 'em?
Liquidize 'em?
- They're humane.
- Humane?
Well, then perhaps
they'd be humane enough
to give me back my dignity.
I want...
Toupee, please.
Oh, grand.
Uh, we take check or cash.
Toupee, you idiot!
My hair is in your machine.
Oh, no, it's only
rabbits in there.
- The hare, I think you'll find,
is a much larger mammal.
Out of my way, fool.
I'm sorry, my dear,
but I refuse to suffer
any further humiliation
at the hands
of these blundering nitwits.
I therefore bid you good day.
Thank you for ridding me of a real problem, Mr.
Wallace.
Tell me, what exactly will
you do with all these rabbits?
Oh, um...
Trade secret.
Yes. I'd be happy
to let them roam free
if it wasn't
for the competition.
But they do so love their veg.
It's in their little
bunny natures, and you
can't change that, can you?
No.
Or can you?
Why didn't we
think of it before, lad?
The solution to all
our storage problems.
Simply by connecting the BunVac
to the Mind
Manipulation-omatic,
we can brainwash the bunnies.
Rabbit rehabilitation.
Once cured of their antisocial
veg-ravaging behavior,
the rabbits can
be safely released
without fear
of re-offending.
Just a little added lunar power
to enhance the mind waves...
and we can begin.
Veg, bad.
Say no to carrots,
cabbage and cauliflower.
Well, come on, lad,
what are you waiting for?
Turn on the BunVac.
Full suction.
Ah!
It's working, Gromit.
Oh! It's working!
Ho-ho!
Their tiny bunny brains
are being saturated
in my veg-free mind waves.
Ha!
Another 30 minutes
brainwashing should suffice.
Then we can move on
to the conditioning.
- Ooh!
- Ah!
Ah!
Ooh! Gromit!
Switch it off!
- Whee!
- Get it off!
Get it off me, lad!
Oh, thanks, lad.
Ah!
Quick.
Give us a carrot.
Ah! It worked, Gromit!
A reformed rabbit.
We'll call him Hutch.
Shall we?
Come on.
Let's get the kettle on.
We'll see to him in the morning.
Ho-ho! I feel
we're on the cusp
of a real breakthrough, lad.
Mankind freed from
rabbit problems forever.
Lady Tottington
will be impressed.
Good night.
Sleep tight.
And don't let the bed bugs bite.
Good night, Gromit.
Sweet dreams, old chum.
Protect and nourish
the frail and the weak, O Lord.
Let them grow big and strong
under Thy loving care.
In fact, let them grow bigger
and stronger than anyone else's,
so that the
first prize might be mine.
Amen.
The harvest offering
to bind the deal.
* We plow the fields and
scatter the good seed on... *
Huh?
Mmm. Ahem.
* He sends
the snow in winter... *
* All good gifts around us
* Are sent from...
Heavens above.
Hello?
Hello? Is anybody there?
Mrs. Mulch?
Please, come forward,
whoever you are.
There's no need to be afraid.
Ah! You're hungry.
Then please, take what you like.
It is for the needy,
after all.
No! No! No! No!
Mercy!
Ah!
Ow!
Morning, Gromit.
A pest-free night
per... chance?
Oh!
Lummy day.
- It's a disaster.
- Me garden's ruined.
- It's carnage out there.
- Where were Anti-Pesto?
Simmer down, now.
Right. One at a time,
if ya please.
We pay good money
for our crop protection.
If ya can't deliver
the goods, maybe you
should keep your traps shut.
I never saw such
cauliflower carnage.
Worse than the
Great Slug Blight of '32,
when there were slugs
the size of pigs.
Growbag's right.
The slugs are back!
That's enough!
Look, this flippin'
vegetable competition
- causes nothin'
but trouble every year.
- Here we go.
- If ya ask me...
- Get on with ya!
Know what? I'll tell ya.
If ya ask me, this was arson.
- Arson?
- Aye!
Someone arsin' around.
That's right.
One of you lot. A man.
- This was no man.
- What are you saying?
Does a man have teeth
the size of axe blades?
Or ears
like terrible tombstones?
By tampering with nature,
forcing vegetables to swell
far beyond their natural size,
we have brought a terrible
judgment upon ourselves.
Hey! Give over!
You're mental.
And for our sins,
a hideous creature
has been sent to punish us all!
Repent! Repent!
Lest you, too,
taste the wrath of...
the Were-Rabbit!
This is terrible!
What's going to happen to us?
- Doomed!
- Who's going to help us?
- What's to become of the show?
- We live for that competition.
- Get off me.
- We're simple folk.
It's all we have.
- Who will save us?
- Get... Hey!
A Were-Rabbit?
Oh, come, come, now.
I do believe the Vicar's been
to the communion wine again.
What we are dealing with here
is no supernatural rabbit.
It's a big fellow, perhaps.
- But a mortal creature
of flesh and blood.
- A matter easily dealt with
by a hunter.
Guns will not be necessary,
thank you, Victor.
Hasn't there been
enough destruction?
I believe the killing
of fluffy creatures
is never justified.
I say we give Anti-Pesto
a second chance.
What? How on earth would
those tiny-minded buffoons
ever catch such a big rabbit?
Mr. Wallace?
Oh! Oh...
Um...
Well...
With a big trap.
By Jove. He's...
He's got it!
- Genius!
- Brilliant.
- What a great idea!
Hmm. Clever.
You see, Victor,
there's hope
for the vegetables yet.
Not the ones I'm looking at.
That's me boys!
Ah! Love, Gromit.
That's the biggest trap of all.
The "tender trap," they call it.
And that's what we'll use
to catch this thing.
Yes, lad, a lovely lady rabbit.
How could any
hot-blooded rabbit-beast resist?
Ah!
Oh, come on, Gromit.
A bit more,
you know, alluring.
Ho-ho!
Very cheeky.
Ha-ha!
That's more like it, lad.
How can we possibly fail now?
You're a total knockout.
Oops!
Stick around, lad.
Should fix back on quite easily.
Nighty-night, me lovelies.
Think big now.
Ah!
No!
Don't worry. No. No.
Well, I'm very sorry,
Mrs. Mulch.
We'll get there as soon
as we can. Mr. Dibber. Oh, yes.
Uh, can I call you back?
Mrs. Girdling.
- A tunnel you say? Oh!
- What do you intend
to do about this?
I'll look into it.
So where did you get to, lad?
I thought I told
you to stay put.
It's gone mad around here.
I thought we were
supposed to be a team.
How are we ever
gonna catch this thing
if you go gallivanting off
on your own all the time?
You're doing it again!
Where are you going now?
Gromit!
Grommy!
Really, lad.
You do realize
I've made a personal promise
to Lady Tottington.
How is this sort of
behavior going to get us
any nearer to finding
a rabbit-mon... ster?
Hutch.
Oh, Gromit.
We've created a monster.
Hutch is the beast.
The lunar panels.
They must've over-stimulated
Hutch's primitive bunny nature.
And now, when the moon appears,
he undergoes
a hideous transformation.
Oh!
Oh, Gromit.
This is absolutely...
fantastic!
Don't you see, lad?
OK, so we've created
a veg-ravaging rabbit-monster.
But we've also captured it.
Just like I promised
Lady Tottington.
I'll go and tell
her the good news.
Make sure he doesn't escape.
Bye!
Mr. Wallace.
It's the beast, your Ladyship.
I bring great news.
Gosh, how exciting.
Please, do come in.
Well, this
is simply spiffing news.
With the beast in captivity,
the competition can
go ahead as planned.
- You saved the day,
Mr. Wallace.
- Oh...
It was nothing, your Ladyship.
So modest.
Oh, please, do help yourself.
Oh!
Thanks.
I so appreciate you
coming all this way
to let me know, Wallace.
Tell me, are you
a vegetable-lover yourself?
- They're... growing on me.
- Then come with me.
There's something very
special I want to show you.
Oh!
Hop in.
- It's very snug.
- It's my Jacob's ladder.
And it goes
all the way to heaven.
Welcome to my
inner sanctum, Wallace.
My secret garden. Oh!
It's a veritable
vegetable paradise.
I just knew you'd love it.
Unlike Victor.
He's never shown
any interest in my produce.
- His loss, Lady Tottington.
- Please, Wallace.
Call me Totty.
If anything
were to happen to my vegetables,
I don't know what I'd do.
I'm sure you understand,
Mr. Wallace.
I can see that you're
a true nature lover.
Oh, yes. Yes, I am.
At first,
I thought I could change Victor.
- Now I'm not so sure.
- Oh!
Do you think a man
can change, Wallace?
Change?
Oh, yes.
Really, Phillip. The things
one does for love.
Pesto.
- Mr. Wallace.
- Oh, Totty.
Totty?
I'd like
to show you one last thing.
Something no other man
has ever seen.
Oh!
My carrot de Chantenay.
Just smell it, Wallace.
- Feel its silken flesh.
- Oh, yes.
Isn't it the most
sumptuous, succulent
specimen you've ever seen?
- Yes!
- Doesn't it fill your heart
- with desire?
- Yes!
Just imagine
what it would taste like.
What on earth
were you thinkin' of, lad?
Ruined a perfectly
good piece of fashionable
knitwear, that did.
To say nothing of
a relationship with
an important client.
It's lucky for us her Ladyship
was so understanding.
Honestly, I don't know
what's got into you lately.
And slow down for pity's sake.
You'll buckle me trunnions.
Don't worry.
I'll see to this.
You stay here where you belong.
In the doghouse.
Right.
It's heavier than it looks.
Oh!
- I know your
little secret, Pesto.
- Oh!
- I know exactly
what's going on.
- Your Lordship...
Oh, yes. You think you can
pilfer my filly, don't you?
You think you can con a woman
- out of her fortune?
- Who, me?
Well, I got here first!
I've spent
a long time reeling in
that fluffy-headed
bunny-lover.
And I'm not about
to let some puddle-headed
peasant poach her from me.
- Comprenez?
- Oh, uh, right-o.
I'll be off then. Ta-ta.
You're not going
anywhere, Pesto.
Ow!
Not until I've taught you
a jolly good lesson.
Come on!
Queensberry rules!
Put 'em up, ya little pipsqueak.
You're shaking.
Don't tell me you're
a scaredy-cat as well
as a scoundrel.
And don't think acting
like a big girl's blouse
will get you out of it.
There's no mercy
with Victor Quartermaine.
- Oh!
- Huh?
Huh?
Ohhh!
What the dickens?
What on earth...?
Ooh!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Ahh!
Phillip! Attack!
Attack!
What the...?
Ahh!
Vicar!
Oh, where the devil is he?
Do you want to confess?
I want to talk to you about...
the beast.
Everything you need
to know is in this book.
- "Nun Wrestling."
- No, no, no! I meant this one.
Ew!
Ah!
Here. Here it is.
The hideous monster
plaguing our parish.
The Were-Rabbit.
So it's true.
The beast lurks
within all of us, my child.
The side that emerges at night
as the moon rises into the sky.
The side that
savagely rips the leaves
off any innocent cabbage.
Spare me the sermon, Vicar.
Just tell me how
I kill him. Um, I mean "it."
To kill such a creature
would require nerves of steel
and...
a bullet.
A bullet?
A bullet.
A bull... Oh!
What kind of bullet?
A bullet of pure gold.
Gold.
Yes.
Twenty-four karat.
Oh! Get out of my way.
Silly old fool.
Beware!
Beware of the beast within!
Hee-hee!
Ah! Ah.
Perfect re-entry, Gromit.
This veg diet's
doing the trick, eh, lad?
I feel smashing.
Mmm.
So how's our rabbit-monster?
Hmm?
Hope you're
keeping an eye on him.
Uh... What's up, dog?
Yow!
Well, fancy that.
Rabbit ears.
That is a bit odd.
And what
are you tryin' to say, lad?
What? What?
What? You think
that I'm the...?
Because of these?
Oh, no.
No. This is just a reaction
to that healthy veg diet
you've got me on.
It's the toxins coming out.
Silly old pooch.
Thinking I'm the beast.
Next thing you'll be saying
is that, oh, Hutch
is turning into me.
Hey.
What are you doing, lad?
Have you gone completely mad?
- Cheese!
- Ah!
Cheese? Ah!
Huh?
Oh, I do like
a bit of Gorgonzola.
Oh, dear.
- Perfect.
- Ma'am.
- Now, let's see.
- Coming through!
Mind your back.
The tombola's arrived.
And the bouncy Tottington Hall.
Splendid.
Oh, it's going to be such
a jolly competition tonight.
I just know it.
- Ya don't know nothin'.
- What?
The beast has struck again.
That's what.
That's right!
No, no, you're quite
mistaken, Mrs. Mulch.
- The beast is in captivity.
- Oh, yeah?
Then just take a look
at my wife's brassicas.
- Ravaged in the night.
- But I don't understand.
- Anti-Pesto told me...
- A pack of lies!
It's not safe to bring
our vegetables here.
The show's off.
But this is
simply dreadful news.
The Tottingtons have held
a giant vegetable competition
on this very night
for over 500 years.
That's right.
Not even the Great Duck Plague
of '53 stopped it.
Oh! If only there
were another way.
What ho!
It's Quartermaine.
Heard you had
a spot of rabbit bother.
Didn't
this bit used to...?
Now. Now, let's see.
Oh. Ow!
Oh, where does this part go?
Oh!
Oh, it's hopeless.
- I'll never fix
this flippin' machine.
- Oh!
Me mind's just
a rabbit-y mush.
Oh, Gromit.
I don't wanna be a giant rabbit!
Aw!
The bounce is gone
from his bungee.
Hey, presto!
Rabbit rehabilitation.
But if I can't fix it...
Cheddar.
Maybe the other me can!
I'm inventing, mostly.
Look at me go!
Ho-ho! I'm a genius.
Ah!
Awake! I can't answer
the door. Not like this.
Charming. I'm Wallace.
Ah! I already am!
Hutch!
Geronimo!
Huh? Wallace?
Uh, hang on a mo'.
Wallace?
Hello? I say.
Open this door at once.
Oh. Totty.
Uh, Lady Tottington,
if you don't mind.
- Oh.
- I'm afraid I have some
rather bad news, Wallace.
Thing is, well,
you've rather let
me down with this
beastly beast business.
- I suppose I have.
- Yes.
Well, it's obvious
to me that you have
absolutely no idea
where this poor creature is.
And I'm afraid
you've given me no option
but to let Victor
shoot the poor thing.
Shoot it?
Yes. Wasn't an easy choice,
but the veg competition
has to come first.
Besides, Victor's
promised me it won't suffer.
It will be quick and painless.
How thoughtful.
I cannot deny it was
a difficult decision for me.
Because I've
recently developed...
Hurry! Ah!
Feelings for you.
Uh, feelings?
Oh, well, never mind, eh?
- Ta-ra, then.
- Wait! Wallace.
I haven't finished. There's
more that needs to be said.
Well, I'll give you
a tinkle, shall I?
Can't we at least shake
hands? Part as friends?
It's not very convenient
at the moment.
Thanks for coming by.
Well, I... I...
Oh!
That's right, my lovely.
You can say goodbye
to your fluffy lover-boy.
You gotta help me, Gromit!
Hide me. Anything.
Before it's too late!
Lad!
Your Lordship.
Ahh!
Ooh!
Good night, Gromit.
'Tis done.
My poor sensitive child.
Allow us all to share
in your moment of sorrow.
Yeah!
On with the show!
Hmm? What the...?
Why you...
Of course.
The vegetable competition.
Your loyalty is moving.
Sadly, you won't be.
Come along, Phillip.
Everyone's been looking
forward to a good show.
Let's see they get one.
Hey!
- Hooray!
- Ah, Mr. Growbag.
I... I have a hunch
this'll be a night to remember.
I just have a hunch.
All right. All right. If we
must do this flipping veg show,
let's do it in an orderly
and law-abiding fashion.
Cucumbers, give way to marrows.
Carrots, wait your turn!
- Aubergines...
- A-ha! There's
our bait, Phillip.
All we have to do now is wait
for our fluffy friend to appear.
Look over here, everyone!
It's Victor!
- He's here!
- Our hero.
Please,
sir, kiss my baby.
- Another time, perhaps.
- Kiss my potato.
- Not now.
- Kiss my artichoke.
- Look, just...
- Victor.
Campanula!
Victor, I have to know.
Did it suffer?
Of course not, my dear.
Not yet, anyway.
- Victor?
- Oy, you.
- Constable.
- Careful with them capsicums.
Listen, I don't want
to cause panic,
but the beast
isn't actually dead yet.
- The beast
isn't actually dead yet?
- What?
Huh?
Oops.
To the competition stand!
Cracking toast, Gromit.
I'm just crackers about cheese.
Monterey Jack. Mmm.
Smashing Wensleydale.
Whoa!
Whee-hee!
Oh!
Job well done, lad.
Quiet!
Now, listen carefully.
I've only got two...
I've only got
one gold bullet left.
So leave this to me.
Yes, all right, I admit
the beast is still at large.
But the good news
is your prize vegetables
are the perfect bait...
- Bait?
- and will draw
the creature like a magnet.
- Keep still.
- My baby.
There, there.
It'll be all... Huh?
- Mrs. Mulch! No!
- Huh?
It's not getting my baby!
Lovely food.
For rabbits, that is.
- Come back!
Ooh! Ahh!
Yes. Right on cue.
Come back!
Go away!
That's right.
Come to Uncle Victor.
It's coming for us!
Bingo.
What the...?
Hurrah for Anti-Pesto!
- It's getting away!
- Get off, you stupid...
No!
Vicar, I need more gold bullets.
They don't come cheap, you know.
Victor? What are you doing?
I need it, my sweet.
Emergency.
Victor, no! Please!
Come, now,
Campanula, let go.
It's my
Golden Carrot Award.
This is hardly the time,
my darling.
- Give it to me!
- But Victor!
Cheese, Gromit.
The Golden Carrot
belongs in the show!
No, the Golden Carrot
belongs in the Were-Rabbit.
Huh?
Every man for himself!
- Help! Help! Help me!
- Ahh!
Put me down at once,
you great big hairy thing, you!
Stop! Stop!
Mob supplies!
Get your
angry mob supplies here.
Put her down,
you great ugly brute!
I'll bagsy
the lucky rabbit's foot.
Help me, someone! Help me!
Yes.
Huh?
No. No, no, no!
No!
Huh?
- Grrr.
- Ah!
Put me down!
Put me down, you...
Whatever you are! Help!
What is it?
What are you staring at
with those beastly eyes?
Huh?
Wallace.
Oh, Wallace.
What ever have
you done to yourself?
Well, don't you worry.
I'll protect you.
Get your hairy mitts
off my future wife,
you big brute.
No! Victor!
You don't understand.
The hunt is off.
It's... We made
a terrible mistake.
Oh, no. You commissioned
me to rid you of Pesto,
and that's just
what I intend to do. Oop!
- Huh?
- Pesto?
Why, you... you knew
it was Wallace all along.
Oh, all right.
So what if it is
that blithering idiot.
No one will ever believe you.
And if I can't have your money,
I can still bag your bunny.
Oh! My eyes!
Run, rabbit, run!
Hmm. I rather like
your hair pinned back.
No, Victor, no! Stop! Please!
- Victor!
- Ha!
You can hop,
but you can't hide, Pesto.
Beware the moon!
Stupid interfering mutt.
Ha!
Huh?
Stand back!
There may be
a large rabbit dropping!
Looks like the buck stops here.
Ah!
Eat karat, bunny boy!
Potty poo!
Huh?
No one beats
Victor Quartermaine!
Is that so?
Consider yourself dumped.
Humph!
He's in there!
- There he is!
- Surround him!
There he is! Over there!
Phillip, help me! Phillip!
Do something.
Ah!
Destroy!
Drive out the monstrosity!
Well, let's see how he likes it.
Wallace?
Oh, Gromit.
Well, at least
now he's at peace.
The rabbit's gone.
If only there were a way
to bring back Wallace.
Lovely cheese,
Gromit.
Gromit?
Don't forget the crackers.
Cheese?
Oh! Cheese!
It's me again. I'm back!
Gromit!
You clever mutt.
Well done, old pal!
- Totty!
- Wallace! You're...
Oh, whoops!
Thanks, lad.
Oh, look!
Well, I think
you deserve this, Gromit.
For a brave and splendid marrow.
We've all got a lot
to thank you for.
Ah!
Every dog has his day.
And thank you, Wallace.
You've saved me
from a terrible marriage.
All the same,
it is going to be rather lonely
at Tottington Hall now.
Unless...
I have a little proposal
for you, Wallace.
I'm so thrilled you agreed
to go through with this.
My pleasure, Totty.
One for the album, Gromit.
I declare this bunny
sanctuary officially open.
When you're ready, lad.
Fire up the old BV6000.
Oh, it's simply marvelous.
My home, a safe haven
for all things fluffy.
I do hope you'll still
come visit, Wallace.
I'd rather got used
to having you around.
Oh! There'll
always be a part of me
here at Tottington Hall.
Give it some more welly, lad.
Cheese!
Ah!