It's funny
how you wake up each day
and never really know if it will be one
that will change your life forever.
But that's what this day was.
The day I left the city to spend a week
in the house where my mother grew up.
A day I'll never forget.
So many years have passed
Almost there. Feeling all right?
I'm okay.
I left my childhood
In a garden green
Come in the garden
And look at the trees
I used to play there when I was a child
Oh, Hara.
How many times have I told her?
Wait here. All right? I won't be a minute.
Okay.
Hara! Your car's blocking
the driveway again.
So many years have passed
The dew is still on the roses
I left my childhood
In a garden green
Shawn? Where are you?
Shawn?
I'm here, Aunt Jessica.
Come meet Hara!
Supper is done and night has come
Let's have tea together
near the fireplace
Nice try.
My house, my home
ls so small, so pretty
My mom, my dad We are family
Joy everywhere
Hey, back off!
Hey! Go get your own!
Arrietty!
What?
You went outside again, didn't you?
How many times have I...
What happened to your room?
It's my own little garden.
If you ask me
it looks more like your own little jungle.
Is that a bay leaf?
Where did you get that?
I wanted to wait and give it to you
on your birthday, but...
Happy birthday!
This will last me all year.
But the bay tree is so far away.
If a bean saw you it would...
Beans don't scare me.
The beans should scare you.
That's what worries me.
The world is a dangerous place
for a Borrower.
Your Aunt Eggletina
wasn't scared either and she...
Was eaten by a toad. I know, I know.
If you don't like your gift
I can put it in my room.
No, no, I should keep it.
I have just the recipe for these.
I'll have your father borrow some sugar.
Oh, you don't have to.
Because tonight I'll borrow some for you.
What?
Don't tell me you forgot!
Tonight's my first borrowing!
Look, Papa's home.
Papa. Papa, I made it all the way
to the bay tree today.
And I used the leaves over my head
just like you said.
And I didn't even get seen by the cat.
So, what I'm trying to say,
- if there was any doubt...
- There's a new bean in the house.
What?
- I know. I saw him.
- Arrietty, I told you to be...
Yes, Mama, I was careful
and he didn't see me.
And he's much smaller
than other beans.
Papa, you just have to let me come
borrowing tonight.
We know nothing
about this new bean.
But you promised
this would be my night.
And I've seen him.
Papa, please, I am telling you,
he's just a child.
And the children are more vicious
than the grownups.
I'll be fine.
Well, the young beans
do go to bed early.
Oh, thank you, Papa!
Pod!
The boy is very sickly and weak.
She'll be fine.
But...
Oh, and don't worry, Mother.
I'll get Papa back safely.
Arrietty will be turning 14 soon.
She'll need to know
how to take care of herself out there.
Without our help.
Sometimes I worry
that we are the only Borrowers left.
What'll become of us?
Remember what the doctor said, Shawn.
Your heart needs rest. No excitement.
- Is that clear, Hara?
- Yes, ma'am, I'll see to it.
Whatever you need, Shawn,
you ask Hara,
- and she'll get it for you, all right?
- Yes, Aunt Jessica.
Make him feel at home, Hara.
Yes, ma'am.
We'll start by keeping the bugs out.
Don't you think you should wear
something a little darker and longer?
No, I think this one's perfect.
So, I need you to get me
some tissue paper and some sugar.
Oh, and promise, dear husband,
you won't let our daughter get eaten
or squashed like a bug.
Oh, please God. Please help them.
Don't worry about me. Everything's fine.
Okay, bye, Mom. I love you.
Oh, goodbye. Love you, too.
Stay close to your father.
I will
Do I get one of those?
Nope? Okay.
Arrietty!
Did you see that?
That's my girl.
Don't look down.
One step at a time.
All right. You need to hold this for me.
Okay.
Arrietty, make sure you hold on tight.
Arrietty!
- Let's go.
- Right.
It's so big.
Papa, what is this place?
This is where beans store all their food.
The sugar is over there.
When you get down there, wait for me.
Yeah!
Papa, you are great!
Yay!
There. That wasn't so hard.
- Where to now?
- Tissue paper. Then home.
Papa, look what I found.
Looks like someone
got their first borrowing.
Careful with it, it's sharp.
Okay.
Papa, borrowing is so much fun!
Look down there.
Filthy rats.
You want to stay away from those things.
I'm not afraid.
I will cut them down to size
with my sword.
Sometimes it's best not to go looking
for danger.
What is this place?
I've heard human beans
call it a dollhouse.
Dolls are toys for beans.
And we are not toys.
These things are not for borrowing.
Oh, but it's so perfect for us.
Don't you think Mother would
absolutely love that dresser over there?
If anything went missing,
they'd know right away.
Borrowers take only what they need.
Don't be afraid, okay?
Hey.
I know it was you in the garden.
I knew I saw you.
My mother used to tell me stories
about the little people
who lived under the floors.
Was it you?
Was it?
Please don't go.
I'm sorry. I should have told you.
He might have seen me
out in the garden today.
We all make mistakes.
So we'll just have to be
extra careful now.
Best not to tell your mother about this.
You know how she worries.
Right.
I'm very proud of you.
A lesser Borrower would've panicked
and run away.
Well, we're home.
Safe and sound.
Is everything okay?
Not quite the adventure we'd hoped for.
This old light gave out
halfway to the kitchen.
No.
Well, I'm afraid we had to give up
on the sugar.
That's okay.
I'm just happy you made it home.
It wasn't a total loss.
Arrietty, why don't you show
your mother your first borrowing?
What a beautiful pin.
Okay. Off to bed.
Night, Mama, Papa.
She looks so worn-out.
Should I make us some tea?
Shawn, come inside.
You'll catch your death of cold.
What did you say?
Why would he do that?
I think he was just being nice.
It's the same cube of sugar
I dropped in his room last night.
Pod,
what does she mean, she dropped it?
Do not touch it. Do you understand me?
It's a trap.
I just know it. They're going to trap us
like cockroaches.
Homily, let's try
not to get hysterical, okay?
Don't tell me to not get hysterical!
We'll probably have to move now.
Goodbye, old table.
We had so many fun times together.
Let's not say goodbye
to anything just yet.
Eat your soup before it gets cold.
I told you that young bean
would be trouble!
But no one ever listens to me.
Thank you, Arrietty.
Smart girl, doing this
when the sun came out.
Or maybe I have a smart mama
who taught me.
You're a good girl.
If you've got this,
I think I'll go lie down a bit.
Okay.
Is that you from last night?
No, wait. Don't go.
I'm sorry if I frightened you.
Please leave us alone.
We don't need your help.
But can I please just talk to you?
No! Human beans are dangerous.
Whenever we're seen, we have to move.
My parents said so.
So you have a family. That must be nice.
You don't have a family?
Yeah, I have one.
But they sent me here
to get the care and attention I need.
Because they're both very busy
with their work.
Sorry to hear that.
Anyway, my name is Shawn.
What's your name?
What do they call you?
Not that it's any of your business,
but it's Arrietty.
Arrietty. Arrietty.
That's a beautiful name.
Maybe we could be friends?
Could you at least come out
so I can see you?
I want to make sure I'm not dreaming.
I won't hurt you, I promise.
Help me! Help me!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What in the world? A crow!
Oh! Attack! OW!
You get out right now!
What got into that bird?
Don't think I've ever seen one
behave like that.
Maybe it's nesting season or something.
I don't know.
Looks me to like it was after something.
Oh, look at the holes in the screen.
Which I'll have to replace, of course.
Oh, my goodness. Are you all right?
Your aunt said for you
not to get too excited!
Should I get your medicine?
No, that's okay, Miss Hara.
I'm actually feeling pretty good.
Nesting season?
Well, Shawn, you have a nice,
long rest now.
Papa!
I hear you visited the young bean.
I'm sorry.
I went to ask him to leave us alone.
But I really don't think
he intends to hurt us.
Many Borrowers have lost their lives
thinking the same.
It must never happen again.
- Do you understand me?
- Yeah.
We'd better start looking
for a new home.
The boy knows that we're here.
Are we safe?
Delivery. Package for you, ma'am.
Thanks for the drink, Hara.
It's pretty hot today.
Do you happen to know
of any good pest control companies?
Pest problem?
Here's one.
"Squeaky Klean Pest Extermination."
1-800... Oh, hang on.
So you got yourself a mouse problem?
Maybe it's mice,
maybe it's little tiny people.
Strange things have been
happening here
and I know why.
That's just
the craziest thing I've ever heard.
I mean, when Hara told me,
I just couldn't believe it.
Why on earth would a crow
try to fly into your room?
Were you frightened?
No, I wasn't scared.
Hara came and chased it away
And it's a good thing I came in
when I did.
That bird had huge wings and claws...
Let's not relive the excitement, Hara,
considering Shawn came here
for a little peace and quiet
and tranquility before his operation.
Yes, ma'am. Forgive me.
I'm sorry, Hara.
I don't mean to be short with you.
But why his mother chose this time
to go away on business is just beyond...
It must be terribly hard for you without
your mother here to look after you.
You know, not so much lately.
I suppose the divorce
couldn't be helped,
but honestly, why couldn't she be here
when her son needs her so?
It's the last thing his poor heart needs.
Aunt Jessica, I was noticing
that miniature house in my room.
And the detail's amazing.
Oh, you mean the dollhouse.
That beautiful little house
belonged to your mother.
She had to leave it here
when she moved away to go to college.
It was Mother's?
Your grandfather had it specially made
because he was hoping it would be
a lovely home for the little people.
What?
That's right.
Little people who lived in the walls.
He was quite obsessed with them.
People laughed, of course,
and called him mad.
But your mother, she believed him.
They worked on that house together
for hours.
And he told her they would come,
but of course, they never did.
Tell me, Shawn, have you ever seen any
tiny little people in your room?
Can't say that I have.
I think it's why your mother
doesn't like to come here any more.
Too many memories of wishes
that never came true.
Can we look inside it?
Yes!
You know, I haven't looked inside it
in quite a long time.
Hara, could you be a dear
and turn off the lights?
Ma'am.
So many years have passed
This is the living room.
Your grandfather had
all of this handmade
by a real furniture maker in England.
Isn't that just insane?
Look at the attention to detail.
They really were preparing it
for someone to live in.
And just in case you don't believe
what I'm saying is absolutely true,
have a look at that room right there.
Come in the garden
What a kitchen!
And look at the trees
Everything in it
a miniature of the real thing.
That oven actually works.
You could bake real cookies.
Some really little cookies.
What a pity their dream never came true.
It really would've made a lovely home.
Settled down there long ago
So many years have passed
The dew is still on the roses
I left my childhood
In a garden green
Come in the garden
And sit on the grass
I used to sit there when I was a child
Ivy and moss
Little daisies
Covered the lane long ago
You know, Mother,
we've had these same pictures for years.
Wouldn't you like some new ones?
Well, Arrietty, I like those pictures.
And I've always dreamed
I'd see the real ocean someday.
Besides, there's no point
in changing them now.
I wonder what's taking Papa so long.
Why is my first thought always
that he got eaten by the cat?
What's wrong with me?
There he is!
Does he look eaten?
Hey, Papa, how was it out there?
I slipped and twisted my leg.
I'm lucky that Spiller here found me.
Well, what is going on down...
Pod, you're hurt!
It was the cat, wasn't it?
See, I'm not crazy.
Get up here!
Does it hurt, Papa?
It's just a sprain. Go calm your mother.
I'll get some cold water. I'll be right back.
Everyone relax!
Here's a towel. Dry yourself.
Who's that?
I wonder if he has news about
any of the other Borrowers.
Okay, I leave now.
Can't you at least stay
and have some tea?
Arrietty, I'll take care of your father.
Why don't you see
if Spiller would like a cup of tea?
Won't you please stay, Spiller?
I've never met another Borrower before.
We can't thank you enough
for your help.
Tell us, have you seen other Borrowers?
We're all alone here
and we're starting to believe
we're the only ones left. Are we?
This many.
Oh! Then cousin Lupy
could still be alive.
Oh, that's a bow, isn't it? Can I see it?
You use this for your borrowing?
Give that back, Arrietty,
before you shoot someone's eye out.
Okay. Go now.
Oh, but couldn't you stay
a little bit longer?
I'll cook dinner.
Already got this.
A cricket leg!
Want some?
- Very fresh.
- No, thanks.
Bye.
Thank you, my friend.
I'll go with him. To see him out.
What were you doing out there
in that storm?
I was looking for a safe route
for our journey.
And now I know which route not to take.
Oh, Pod.
Spiller knows of more Borrowers
a few days journey away.
There's a small river past the forest.
He's offered to take us on it.
That's great.
I'm sure we'll find a new place in no time.
And I'm sure
it will almost be as nice as this.
I'm really glad I met you, Spiller.
Or that I met anyone.
Hey, maybe next time you could bring
your whole family with you.
No family. Only Spiller.
Well, we... We could be a family.
And when you come back
you could stay for a family dinner.
Hara?
Arrietty, your stitches need to be
closer together.
You'll have to start over.
Why do we need
such a big bag anyway?
Are we putting the whole house in here?
I think I'm gonna go check on Papa.
Papa, can I come in?
- How's your leg?
- Well, better than that cricket's.
I'm serious.
Papa, why do we have to move?
Once a Borrower has been seen,
the beans' curiosity can't be stopped.
Well, isn't it possible that
not every human bean is dangerous?
Arrietty, before you were born
there were two other families
who were living in this house.
One family went missing,
they just disappeared.
The other one moved away.
They were seen by humans.
And so, we have to do
whatever it takes to survive.
But, Papa...
Oh! Oh, no!
Pod, what is it? An earthquake?
Mother!
It won't open!
Frame is buckled!
The wall!
Homily!
Homily, are you all right?
Pod, remember how I always said
I wanted a new kitchen?
More bills.
Remember,
take only the things we need.
We can't possibly carry all of this.
And, Homily,
don't take anything from the dollhouse.
I'm gonna go make sure that it's safe.
- You stay with your mother.
- Okay.
So you finally came.
Did you like your new kitchen?
Well, our house looks like a train wreck.
But it doesn't matter.
Because I came to tell you goodbye.
Can I turn around?
You're beautiful.
My papa said we have to move now.
We've been seen,
and Borrowers
aren't supposed to be seen.
What are Borrowers?
My mother, father,
and I are all Borrowers.
We borrow things that beans
won't miss if they are gone.
Just little things,
soap, cookies, and sugar.
All things that we need to survive.
Even my great-grandfather
was a Borrower.
I think my grandfather saw
one of you once.
It's possible.
And it's my fault that you're leaving.
Niya! Niya!
Don't be like that. Be nice to her.
So, in my aunt's house,
how many other Borrowers
are there who are living with you?
It's just my father and my mother
and me.
What about in other houses?
I'm sure there are some.
But I've only met one other so far.
You must be afraid you'll be
the only ones of your kind who are left.
What?
Every year there's
fewer and fewer of you, right?
Aren't you scared
that soon you'll all be gone?
What a horrible thing to say!
I know that there's more of us
because Spiller said so!
Who's Spiller?
He's one of us. He lives out in the forest,
and he said that
there are hundreds more of us.
That might be true.
But, you know,
none of us can live forever, can we?
We all have to die sometime.
Why would you say something like that?
Because it's true.
I guess so.
Believe me,
I know what I'm talking about.
Sometimes things happen to us
that are just beyond our control.
And when these things happen,
there's really nothing
you can do about it.
You just accept it
and prepare for the worst.
I wish it wasn't that way.
But you can't live a life
that's built on nothing but wishes.
It isn't practical.
Sometimes you just have to
accept the hand of fate.
Oh, no, you don't.
Sometimes you have to stand up
and fight
for the things that are worth fighting for.
You have to survive.
That's what my papa says.
And so we're leaving
even though it's dangerous.
And we are going to survive.
We are Borrowers and we'll make do.
We always have.
As long as we have each other to live for,
we'll keep on living.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to upset you.
I'm actually the one who's going to die.
What?
There's something wrong with my heart.
They're gonna operate next week
but it probably won't help.
That's terrible.
I've always been sick
and I've had someone looking after me.
And that's why when I saw you,
I just wanted to find a way to protect you.
But I guess I messed up.
I made it worse. I'm sorry.
And I'm sorry to hear about your heart.
Now what on earth is this doing here?
Now how did you get in there?
There you are!
Mom!
What? What's wrong?
My mother, I think she's in danger.
No!
Give me that, you little thief!
Now we'll see who they call crazy.
And I bet there's more of you,
aren't there?
Wait, no! Wait, wait! Wait!
I have to go help her.
But...
Oh, no! Help! No, no, please! Help!
Pod! Arrietty!
Let me out of here!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Let me out of here!
Arrietty! Help!
Watch it!
Let's see.
Now to find the others.
Let me out! No! No!
Something terrible has happened.
- Squeaky Klean.
- Yes, hello.
I'm calling from 833 Elm Lane.
Could you get out here right away?
I have a very unique pest problem.
- Is it mice?
- Oh, much worse than mice.
Do you want them exterminated?
No, I need you to trap them.
Shawn! Shawn! Shawn!
Shawn! Shawn!
Arrietty!
My mother is missing.
Someone took the roof off!
I think a human bean got her.
Oh, Mama.
We will find her.
What?
Someone's locked us in.
There's a room next door. Hold on tight.
One step at a time.
Right.
It's stuck!
Wait.
I can get us in.
Oh, no, no!
Keep going.
What do you mean you're lost?
How can you possibly be lost?
It's the only road!
- Is it before the bridge?
- What bridge? There's no bridge!
Hara must have found it
and opened it.
This is what I was afraid of.
Mother's been taken.
Are you okay?
Be careful. Shawn, please.
Where are those idiots?
Mother! Where are you?
Be wise.
They're supposed to catch pests.
But... HOW did you...
Hara.
Could I have some warm milk?
Okay! Wait just a minute.
Thank you, Hara.
I'm a little hungry.
Are there any cookies?
Cookies? Now he wants cookies.
Mother!
Arrietty!
Over here!
Arrietty! Here I am! Here I am!
Oh, Mother!
Oh, Arrietty.
Oh, good. There they are.
They finally found the road.
The only road.
Another bean!
It's okay, Mother. He's a friend.
Ma'am, we'd like to take a look around.
See what we see.
Yes, of course.
Squeaky Klean Exterminators?
Hara? Hara!
Oh!
What's going on here?
It's finally happened.
I found the little people.
Little people?
Yes! And what little robbers they are.
I wouldn't have believed it either
unless I'd seen it with my own eyes.
It's remarkable!
It's the eighth wonder of the world.
And they're so teeny!
And they have a whole house
full of things they've stolen.
Are you sure
you didn't find the sherry again?
All these years
you thought I was losing things.
But it wasn't me. It was them!
You didn't mention little people
to the exterminators, did you?
No. I didn't want to scare them off.
Because I'm sure
the house is just full of them.
You'll see when I show you.
This is their nest.
Nest?
Looks like a pile of old junk to me.
What?
It was here! It was here!
Where's that little teapot?
Okay, Hara,
I'm sending the exterminators away.
No! No, no! Wait just a minute.
Oh. Oh! I'll clean that up later.
Oh, please!
Hello, Shawn.
Can we come in for a minute?
It's open.
You'll see.
Those little thieves stole the tiny kitchen.
I don't know how they did it,
but the whole thing is gone.
Not gone.
Perhaps you need a little time off, Hara.
Yeah.
Wait! Wait! I can prove it!
I've got one of them in a jar!
Poor Hara.
I think she's finally gone bonkers.
Do I smell fresh herbs?
Someone's been making tea.
It's just as my father told us.
There really are little people living here.
Yes, there are.
Your mother really
should be here to see this.
She waited so long
for some proof of them.
But they're not thieves like Hara said.
They're just Borrowers.
What?
I mean, they must be very frightened.
I just hope they're still here.
I hope so, too.
Excuse me. Ma'am!
Where would you like us
to start looking?
Oh, are you all right?
Where did she go?
Who took my lady?
There are little people! There are!
Easy, 68$)'
And, no, I'm not losing my mind!
If I collapse, leave me behind.
With my tea kettle.
You're doing great. It's just
a little further until we break for food.
Can't we just head back?
We can live with the rats
in the compost heap.
Oh, no!
Let's hurry.
I can't do it.
Arrietty, you really
should eat something.
We're gonna be walking
at least until morning.
What?
I'm so sorry.
I feel like maybe it's all my fault
that we had to leave
such a wonderful house.
That's in the past.
We'll make another wonderful house,
the three of us, together.
I'm going outside for a bit.
Arrietty, don't go too far.
Niya.
Just a little further.
Spiller!
That's the last of it.
Come on, we should keep moving.
Okay.
Mother, are you all right?
Arrietty!
Shawn.
Arrietty.
We have to leave.
But Spiller says there's more of us
not too far from here.
A two-day's journey, at most.
He thinks it might be my mother's family.
You won't be the last of your kind.
But how did you find me?
Niya here showed me the way.
Thank you, Niya. Take care of him.
I brought you something.
Now think of it as a gift
from one friend to another.
Thank you, Shawn.
I have to go.
When is your operation?
Tomorrow. But I'm not scared.
Because someone taught me
how to be brave.
So you'll remember me.
How can I forget you?
You protected me after all.
Arrietty.
I hope you have a happy life.
Goodbye, Shawn.
Arrietty, my heart is strong now
because you're in it.
And you always will be.
Forever.
I never saw her again.
But the following summer I returned
and was happy to hear
the people in the house down the road
talking about how many things
in their home had gone
missing.
I'm 14 years old, I am pretty
I'm a teeny tiny girl, a little lady
I live under the kitchen floor
Right here, not so far from you
Sometimes I feel happy,
sometimes I feel blue
In my dreams, oh, I wish I could
Feel my hair blowing in the wind
See the sky and the summer rain
Pick a flower from the garden for you
Now I know there's another world
Butterﬂies floating in the air
There is someone out there for me
Walking down, picket fence
Run my hands along the edge
And music plays in my head
Hear the song before I go to bed
When stars are bright
outside my window
Wake up to tree boughs
filled up with snow
And I remember Oh, I remember
I remember my summer with you
Cherry popsicles, sand in my toes
Rolled down windows
Hold my hand, hold me close
Pick up your phone
Wanna hear your voice again
Like a fresh air, like a windblown hair
I like you, I don't care
Why did it have to end?
Summer love with my best friend
I'd fly to you
All the way across the states
Hear me, the winter day
Oh, I'd follow the sun
and come right to your door
I remember my summer with you
Cherry popsicles, sand in my toes
Rolled down windows
Hold my hand, hold me close
Pick up your phone
Wanna hear your voice again
Like a fresh air, like a windblown hair
I like you, I don't care
Why did it have to end?
Summer love with my best friend
I will miss you in summer again when