PONYO ON THE CLIFF
Sosuke, come right back up, OK?
OK!
It's a goldfish!
I can't get it out.
That was weird.
It looks kind of dead.
It licked me! It's alive!
Sosuke, we have to go!
- Lisa, a goldfish!
- Sosuke!
This wind is crazy.
Sosuke, I'm starting the car now!
Have you found her?
What? She was captured by a human?
This is bad. This is very bad.
Is it already dead?
It's alive!
Sosuke.
- We're gonna be late!
- Lisa, the goldfish is alive!
- A goldfish?
- It was right down by the rocks.
Yeah?
I don't know who you are, but please
don't spray pesticide around here!
Oh, no. This is not pesticide.
I brought this water from deep sea
to prevent extreme dry skin...
Whatever.
As long as it's not pesticide.
Excuse us.
This is bad. This is very bad.
That guy was a freak show. Just kidding.
Never say such a thing, Sosuke.
- We never judge others by their looks.
- I don't say such things.
- Are you taking that to pre-school?
- Yeah.
- Your teachers don't tell you not to?
- Don't worry, I'll take care of you.
She's cute.
A ship must be coming in today.
Sosuke, eat your breakfast.
I wonder if she would eat this.
Want some?
Hey! My cut is all gone!
Lisa, I think I'll call her Ponyo.
She came to me.
Besides, she might be magic.
Ponyo licked my cut
and it healed right away.
Do you wanna eat ham?
Lisa, Ponyo really likes to eat ham.
Just like me.
- Oh, dear... Oh, dear...
- Come on, Lisa, hurry!
Filthy. It's so filthy!
Good morning!
Ponyo, look.
You can see our house.
- We'll park here. OK?
- Yeah.
- Have a nice day.
- See you later.
Morning! Sorry for being late!
- Get Noriko's wheelchair?
- Sure.
Good morning, Sosuke.
I'm busy right now, Yoshie.
I'll talk to you later.
- Oh, my...
- Sosuke, dear.
- Toki, I'll catch you later.
- My goodness...
I wonder if my teacher will say no.
I got it.
You'll wait here. I'll be back soon.
I hope cats won't come around here.
Stay put. I'll be right back.
See you later. Hello there, Toshi.
She has a little fever,
but she's active. She should be OK.
- Right, sweetie?
- Oh, thank you. Bye-bye.
- Good morning, Teacher.
- Good morning, Sosuke.
How are you, Sosuke?
- Sosuke!
- Kumiko!
Look! Isn't this dress pretty?
My mom bought it for me.
Is that so?
- Hey, Sosuke, wanna go play?
- I can't. I'm busy right now.
- What are you doing here?
- Like I said, I'm busy.
- You're acting weird, Sosuke.
- Yeah, weird.
Ponyo!
Sosuke!
- Oh, Kumiko.
- What is that?
You're not supposed to
bring stuff to school.
These brushes are not school's.
They're on the senior center property,
so it's OK.
Let me see!
Oh, a goldfish!
She's not just a goldfish.
She's Ponyo.
Ponyo? I wanna see!
If I show her, you won't tell anyone?
No, I won't.
Look. Isn't she cute?
She's weird. She's fat, too.
My goldfish is cuter.
That one was Kumiko's fault. You should
Never judge others by their looks.
Let's get you some more water.
Ponyo!
I'm relieved.
That's strange... I hear Sosuke's voice.
But he's supposed to be
in school right now.
- So it must be only in my head.
- Look, Yoshie. I'm right over here.
Oh, my... Sosuke is here.
Do I have something nice?
- Yes, you do.
- Bingo!
All right then, what color is it?
- Red!
That's right!
- How did you both guess that?
- Come on, show us!
OK.
- Pretty!
- Cute.
Her name is Ponyo.
She likes to eat ham.
And she can do magic!
A cut on my thumb disappeared
because Ponyo licked it.
Maybe she could lick our legs.
I wish I could run fast, once again,
like you, Sosuke.
Well, I'd have to ask Ponyo.
I can't speak for her.
- Let me take a look, too.
- Sure, Toki.
Oh, no! It's a fish with a human face!
Hurry up! Put it back in the ocean.
Don't you realize it'll cause a tsunami?
Here you go again, Toki,
worrying about a tsunami.
When fish with faces come out to
the beach, tsunamis will come.
That's what they always say.
Tsunami! Tsunami is here!
Tsunami is here!
Tsunami...
- Toki, what's the matter?
- My clothes are all ruined!
Sosuke!
Sosuke! Come back here
and apologize to Toki!
Don't worry, Ponyo.
No matter what, I will protect you.
Sosuke!
Ponyo!
Ponyo. Sosuke.
Ponyo loves Sosuke!
- I will love you, too.
- Ponyo loves Sosuke!
Ponyo!
Ponyo! Ponyo!
Sosuke!
Ponyo!
Listen, Sosuke,
there's such a thing as destiny.
You can't change one's destiny
no matter how tough it is.
I think Ponyo went back to the ocean
because she was meant to live there.
Anyway, hopefully
that pesticide guy is gone.
Can I have a lick?
Hurry, it's starting to melt.
It's yummy!
Come on. Cheer up!
Koichi is finally coming home today.
He'll be disappointed
if you are all bummed out.
Don't go down to the water
anymore today.
OK.
Sosuke.
Time to come in now.
If I leave the pail here, Ponyo will
know where we live when she comes back.
That's true.
Do that if you want to, Sosuke.
Yeah.
Sosuke, can you get that?
It must be Koichi.
Hello? Yep. It's me.
Yeah. I'm doing fine.
I can't come home tonight. Help me
with the signal when I pass offshore.
OK. I'll let you talk to Lisa.
Koichi? Yeah.
What?! That's not fair...
Just say no!
Go ahead, abandon your wife and child
up here on a cliff all alone.
I give up! Whatever!
Come on, Sosuke.
Let's eat out tonight.
I wanna eat at home.
That's Koichi. Lisa, it's Koichi's ship!
Turn off the lights!
That's Sosuke, what a genius!
He's only five years old!
Your wife must be pretty mad.
S... O... R... R... Y.
Lisa, he's saying he's sorry.
B... U... G... O... F... F...
B-U-G O-F-F. B-U-G O-F-F.
Lisa, he says he loves you.
He says, "Lots and lots."
BUG OFF BUG OFF BUG OFF BUG OFF
Wow! Isn't that pretty?
PRAYING FOR SAFE SAILING
THANKS
GOOD NIGHT
Don't cry, Lisa.
I won't cry, either. So...
I promised Ponyo I'd protect her.
I wonder if she's crying now.
All right. I'm gonna cheer up!
Happy as can be
Don't you worry, Sosuke.
You did your best
and Ponyo will be just fine.
OK.
Now, let's eat dinner!
We'll finish Koichi's portion, too!
What have I done?
It was my fault that I had brought you
to show you the work at the farm.
Have I not taught you over and over
how the humans dirty up water and air?
Come on, now. Eat.
Can't you hear me, Brunhilde?
I want ham!
Ham? Where did you learn
of such a horrifying thing!
Tell me, Brunhilde.
My name is not Brunhilde. It's Ponyo.
P... P... Ponyo?
Ponyo! Ponyo loves Sosuke!
I will be a human, too!
Human? What's good about
such a foolish, horrid species?
All they do is to take life
out of the ocean.
I was once, long ago, a human myself.
You have no idea
what it took to give up being human...
I want hands!
I don't want these flippers anymore!
- I want feet, like Sosuke!
- That's enough!
I made hands! I made feet, too!
Yes! Hooray!
Don't tell me you have
licked human blood!
- I'm going to Sosuke!
- No!
The DNA contamination activated
a congenital inferior factor!
Revert. Revert. Revert!
Revert! Revert! Revert!
There. There. There. There. Here we go!
Oh, no. I don't have enough power!
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!
Evil blood, calm down.
Be still, be still,
be still, be still, be still.
She's already so powerful.
Just like her mother.
If you could only remain
innocent and pure forever.
I don't have the power
to hold her for very long.
I need to ask for her mother's help now.
I... What?
Oh, no! They're headed for my elixirs.
Shoo! Shoo! Get out of here!
That was too close.
The anti-crab barrier was loose.
I must be careful
not to upset the balance of nature.
Calm. I must remain calm.
When I think of meeting her again,
my heart won't stop pounding.
Focus on work.
This batch is already ready.
The barrier is not loose in here, is it?
PANGEA
This door still doesn't fit right.
I'll fix that next.
If even one living creature
got in here...
Yes. I can feel the power of the ocean
in the furthest reaches of my DNA.
When this well is full, then the age
of the ocean will begin again.
An explosion of life
to match the Cambrian Age.
An end to the era
of those abominable humans.
This cursed door!
Teeth!
Let's find Sosuke!
I'm free!
- Waterspout!
- Captain, look over there!
- It's a tsunami!
- Turn the ship into the wave!
Look! What is that?
Captain, the radio
and radar are both dead!
It's a little girl.
Looks like she's about Sosuke's age.
- Thanks again.
- Sure. Take care.
Why don't you wait here, Sosuke?
I'll stay with you.
I'll take the shortcut, so I'll be OK.
Goodbye, Teacher.
Goodbye.
Be careful!
Sosuke, I'm sorry.
The door didn't open, right?
The power just went out.
- Everything OK at school?
- Yeah.
Lisa, we'll be fine.
So why don't you go home?
But Ms. Kaneko is not here yet.
It'll be fine. She must be
running a little late.
We'll have to spend the night anyway.
If I were you,
I'd get out of here while you still can.
- Sosuke, wait here for a while.
- OK.
Hi, Yoshie.
Oh, Sosuke. Is that you?
- It's so dark I could barely see.
- Here. This is for you.
- Let's see... What is it?
- There's one for you, too, Noriko.
Thank you.
It's pitch dark. I can't see a thing.
I can't believe the power is down
from such little rain.
That's why I didn't want a sleepover.
The power's back on! Good!
Nice and bright. It's a goldfish!
I bet the lights came back on
because Sosuke's here.
The very powerful, micro-typhoon
is still maintaining the power, and...
This stupid TV.
Nobody understands weather anymore.
Their forecasts are never right.
You should take your mother home now.
With our lucky goldfish to
keep us company, we won't be scared.
OK.
This is for you, Toki.
- It's wrinkled. What is it?
- It goes like this.
- I got it. It's a grasshopper.
- No, it's the Koganei Maru.
That's the name of your father's ship,
isn't it, Sosuke?
- Right.
- It does look like a grasshopper.
Sosuke, we've gotta get on the road.
Let's hurry now and say goodbye.
- OK. Ladies, good evening.
- Good evening.
Be careful the wind
doesn't blow you away.
Get in from this side.
They said the phones are out, too.
The ocean looks all puffed up.
You think the storm
could sink the ships?
No. Ships can handle a storm. I'm sure
that's what Koichi is doing right now.
I saw a fish!
Did you see that, Lisa?
Put your seatbelt on!
Lisa! You can't cross here!
We just got word.
They're gonna evacuate this side.
Evacuate? There are some people
up at the senior center.
They're on the leeward side, and the
levees are high. They should be fine.
OK. But right now, I need to get home.
- You can't cross here.
- Take the mountain road.
- Here we go, Sosuke.
- Sure.
- No! Don't do it!
- A big wave is coming!
- Lisa, you gotta get out of here!
- Back up!
- The fish are following us now!
- Buckle up!
I'm gonna go real fast!
What a persistent wave!
- Lisa, the little girl just fell in!
- What?
She was on a fish!
Where?
The sea level is raised!
Sosuke,
where did you see a little girl?
She was out there,
running on top of a huge fish!
A fish?
Sosuke, we have to go!
Hang in there, Sosuke.
We're almost home.
There is a little girl.
It's dangerous out here!
Come over here!
Stay there, Sosuke.
Sosuke, do you know her?
Ponyo?
- Right! It's me, Ponyo!
- It is you!
Lisa! Ponyo came back,
and she's a little girl now!
I found Sosuke!
Listen, Sosuke, Ponyo.
All right.
Life is mysterious and amazing.
But we need to be calm right now.
- All right?
- Yes.
Very good.
You can take off
your raincoat now, Sosuke.
You are... barefoot, Ponyo.
Hold this for a sec.
Stay here, and I'll go get a towel.
Here, this way!
It smells like you in here!
Ponyo!
There, got ya.
Now, let's rub you down and dry you off.
Ponyo, you have beautiful red hair.
- And your clothes are dry.
- That's because Ponyo was a fish.
- Being wet doesn't bother her, right?
- Right.
I really like this thing.
All right then.
Why don't we have some tea?
Ponyo, will you
hold the light for me?
- Coming!
- Let's see if the water is working.
- It's working!
- It worked!
It's because we have
our own water tank up on the hill.
And who thinks the stove will light?
And light! All right.
- All right!
- We have our own propane tank.
- Please have a seat at the table.
- OK!
Ponyo, over here.
This is what you do.
Now, put your stuff down.
- You need to use your hands.
- No, I'll use feet!
Look at that!
What is it?
Look at her feet.
They're just like hands.
Here you go.
Here.
Thank you for the tea!
Ah, that was delicious.
So, what shall we do next?
- Ponyo wants ham!
- All she thinks about is ham, Lisa.
I better make some dinner then.
But, first,
we should start the generator.
We generate power
to talk to Koichi on the radio.
Koichi is my dad.
- Is he an evil wizard?
- No, of course not.
He's the captain of the ship
called Koganei Maru.
What about your dad, Ponyo?
His name is Fujimoto.
He keeps me in a bubble!
- What?
- So I ran away.
What about your mom, then?
I love my mom very much!
- But she can be very scary.
- Just like my mom.
Ponyo, over here, please.
I wonder if the fuel has gone bad.
- Maybe it's clogged.
- It's clogged.
It's clogged over there.
- It's on!
- It's light now!
Ponyo, you're amazing.
- Antenna, antenna!
- Hey, Lisa.
Did all the ships out there sink?
I don't see any lights out there.
- Too loud!
- We can't get through?
I can't get any reception.
Transmitting from JA4LL. JA4LL.
Come in, Koichi.
This is Lisa, Sosuke and Ponyo.
We're all doing fine.
- We're about to have dinner.
- Ham!
Put the noodles in your bowl?
Be careful. It's really hot.
- You have to wait a little bit.
- It takes three minutes.
OK, close your eyes.
Not yet...
Ponyo... No peeking!
OK. You can look now.
Abracadabra!
- It's ham!
- Careful, it's hot.
Hot, hot, hot!
Lisa, Ponyo fell asleep.
Do you think Ponyo
came from far, far away?
Yeah, I do.
Look outside. It looks like
the waves have calmed down.
- Maybe because Ponyo fell asleep.
- Do you see that light?
It's moving.
There must be somebody still over there.
I wonder if that's Yoshie
and the others.
- The lights are out.
- It's the mountain road.
Sosuke, stay with Ponyo, OK?
I've gotta go help them.
I can get there
if I take the mountain road.
Sosuke,
I should go to the senior center.
I'm coming, too.
I'd feel better if you'd
stay up here with Ponyo.
I'm coming with you!
We just need to bring Ponyo with us.
I wanna go with you, Lisa!
Sosuke, right now,
our house is a beacon in the storm.
The people in the dark feel hopeful
when they see our lights.
That's why someone has to be here.
Many mysterious things
have been happening.
We don't know why right now,
but we'll find out before long.
For now, I'm worried about
the people at the senior center.
If you stay and guard the house,
that would be very helpful.
Don't worry. I promise I'll be back.
Promise?
- I promise.
- You promised.
I love you, Sosuke.
The moon is out! I can see
the lights of a city up ahead.
Thank goodness!
We can get our bearings again.
We're someplace
I've never seen before.
Have we arrived in America or what?
That's not a mountain.
And that's no harbor, either.
Those lights are ships.
The water of the ocean has
come together to create a mountain.
That's probably a graveyard for ships.
The gate to the world beyond
must have opened!
- The engine stopped!
- Try to hold her steady.
- Drop the sea anchor.
- Yes, sir.
Something's coming from behind us.
I just saw the Goddess of Mercy!
- The engine's working.
- We're saved!
She saved us!
She must've appeared for us!
Thank you for protecting us...
Higher, higher.
There is a powerful holy barrier
around the house.
How has she learned
to do something like that?
I don't believe this!
She's turned into a human!
Hold still! You... What are you doing?
Girls! Oh, no!
Stop, now!
Listen, girls.
I'm concerned about your sister.
At last, she has finally come.
- Fujimoto.
- You've come for me, my love.
What a wonderful ocean.
It's full of magic and power.
It's like my ancient Devonian Sea.
Ponyo has tasted human blood.
She also drank all of my elixirs
that I've collected.
Ponyo? What a lovely name.
Of course, it's all my fault, really.
She can use magic freely, and she's
opened a hole in the fabric of reality.
She has no idea what she's doing.
She's now a little girl.
And she loves a little boy.
If we don't do anything about this,
the planet is doomed.
Already the Earth
is pulling satellites from the sky.
And the moon pulls the sea closer...
Be calm, dear.
Sosuke. The boy's name is Sosuke.
You all love your older sister,
don't you?
Listen, my darling, why don't
we let Ponyo become human for good?
- What?
- It's the old magic, you know.
If Sosuke's love remains unchanged,
Ponyo'll become human
and lose her magical power.
But, if anything goes wrong,
Ponyo will turn into sea foam.
Well, we all originated in sea foam.
But he is only five years old.
That's impossible...
Children, sleep peacefully for now.
Sosuke!
Ponyo, you OK?
- Ponyo, good morning.
- Good morning, Sosuke.
Look at that.
The ocean is at our door.
- How come your Lisa's not here?
- Because the road is under the water.
Too bad we don't have a boat.
There's a boat, right there!
- You can't ride it.
- Yes, you can.
Thank you!
Wow! You even made the candle bigger.
- We can ride it!
- Yeah! This is fantastic.
- Fantastic!
- You take that end, please.
OK!
- Ready?
- I'm ready!
It actually floats!
Doesn't look like it has any leaks.
Now we have to fill the boiler.
The water goes in through this pipe...
...then it gets heated up here,
in this round thing.
It's like a rocket.
Ponyo, everything's shipshape.
- Shipshape!
- Yep.
- Shipshape.
Shipshape! Shipshape!
Shipshape!
Is it hot? It's hot!
Hot!
- Look at that!
- It's burning.
It's hot! It's hot! It's hot! It's hot!
It's hot, right?
It's working!
Sosuke, we're shipshape, right?
- Yep.
- This is fantastic.
- Sosuke! We're happy, right?
- Yep.
- Sosuke, it's burning, right?
Sosuke, that thing is hot, right?
Ponyo, you be the boat's lookout.
And I'll do the steering, OK?
OK! I'm the lookout!
There's the road.
That's the mountain road
Lisa took last night.
- I don't see her anywhere.
- We'll see her.
She promised me she'd come back.
Those are ancient fish.
They lived during the Devonian Age.
I know that one.
It's Bothriocephalus.
- And that one is...
- Dipnorhynchus.
- Dipnorhynchus!
- Wow! That one's really huge!
- That's Devonynchus!
- Devonynchus!
Ahoy!
- Ahoy...
- Whoa, there's a boat!
Ahoy!
They said, "Ahoy."
That's fast!
I'm getting the hang of this.
Get ready to stop, Ponyo.
- Hello, you two.
- Hello.
Hey, that is quite
a boat you got there.
I've seen you before.
You're Lisa's little boy, aren't you?
- He's not a little boy. He's Sosuke!
- She's Ponyo.
And I used to be a fish.
A fish?
Your name is lovely, Ponyo.
By the way, have you seen my mother?
Your mother?
Why isn't your mother with you?
- She went to the senior center.
- Wow, way up there?
This is our baby.
Oh, dear. I wonder what's wrong.
Oh, is that for us?
Let me have it.
Thank you.
I'm looking forward to tasting it.
Wow, that's good soup.
- My mom made it.
- The soup's for the baby!
Oh, I'm sorry.
He's too young to have soup.
But I could eat the soup instead,
and it would help me make milk for him.
Yeah, my mom made milk for me, too.
Ponyo, is it all right
if I eat the soup?
- That's fine.
- Thank you.
Heave-ho!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
People from the town!
It's just like a parade!
Ahoy! Are any of you in need
of assistance at this time?
Thank you! We're fine for now!
We are taking everyone
to the Mountain Peak Hotel!
For your safety,
we request that you follow us!
Aye, aye! Will do!
- Looks like the whole town is here.
- I'm glad.
- I hope everyone's OK.
- Ponyo, time to light the candle.
Hold on a second. Let's see...
Here, have some milk.
Wow.
It's for milk.
She already ate all the ham
off those sandwiches.
Thank you. It'll help me make good milk.
Sosuke.
- I have a used candle. Do you want it?
- Thanks. Ponyo will make it bigger.
Thank you!
- Be careful.
- Thank you.
What's the matter?
There. There.
Ponyo!
- Sosuke!
- Hey, that's Sosuke.
- Where is Lisa?
- What's going on with Lisa?
She went to the senior center last
night! We're on our way to find her!
That means Lisa beat that wave!
- That's Lisa.
- Sosuke, can I ride with you?
Kumiko, I'm busy right now. Maybe later.
Check the park.
The seniors should be there by now.
- Good luck, kid!
- You'll find her!
We'll send a boat for the seniors
as soon as we drop this group off!
Good luck, captain!
Ponyo, we need to replace the candle.
We'll be OK.
The fisherman gave me another one.
Hot!
It's still pretty hot.
Bye-bye.
Here, Ponyo.
Can you make this bigger?
All right.
Ponyo, are you sleepy?
Ponyo.
Ponyo. Ponyo!
Oh, good. I can walk from here.
There's the road.
Oh, no! The boat!
Ponyo!
Ponyo, wake up!
Sosuke.
You scared me.
I thought you might
turn back into a goldfish.
Lisa's car!
Ponyo, I found Lisa's car!
Lisa! Lisa!
Lisa!
Lisa...
Lisa.
Lisa!
Sosuke, I've got your boat.
There's water coming from your eyes.
- Let's go find your mom.
- Yeah.
HIMAWARI HOUSE
- My lap blanket!
- Forget about it!
Look, here comes a whale again!
I think he sees us.
The other side is nice, isn't it?
- And my knees don't hurt.
- We didn't have to be afraid.
This is the other side?
I thought it was the undersea palace!
Ladies, can we gather around, please?
- Coming!
- Let's go!
- It's so nice to run.
- Beat you there!
Winner!
Everyone, quiet, please.
The time has come for you to bear
witness to a sacred test of love.
- Oh, how exciting!
- Test of love!
My heart is beating fast!
Please, ladies! You're the witnesses
to this sacred test.
We ask everyone to be patient
for a little while longer.
Fujimoto, you won't let any harm
come to Sosuke or Ponyo, will you?
- Right.
- Of course not! He's the father...
Of course I wouldn't.
My hope is Ponyo will stay asleep.
Excuse me.
- I'm sure he's nice at heart.
- I wonder how Lisa's doing?
She's with Ponyo's mother, and
they've been talking all night and day.
Poor Lisa. Must be hard on her.
I wish we could hear
what they're talking about.
Oh, why don't we just ask. Lisa!
Lisa!
Please know that we are all
cheering for Sosuke and Ponyo!
- Lisa!
- You must be anxious.
Sosuke'll do just fine.
He's a determined, young boy.
Absolutely!
He's such an upstanding boy.
Thank you.
Please be there for him.
It's going to be fine.
Ponyo, there's a tunnel.
MOUNTAIN PEAK PARK AHEAD
STOP
I think I've been here before.
- Ponyo?
- Don't like this place.
- Don't let go of my hand.
- OK.
Ponyo!
Ponyo! Please don't die! Ponyo!
Ponyo! Wake up, Ponyo!
Be careful not to wake her.
It's good to meet you, Sosuke.
We've all been waiting for you.
- The old ladies, your mother...
- My mother?
Won't you come with me
and join them, Sosuke? Ponyo, too.
Let Ponyo keep sleeping
and we'll just sneak away.
Sosuke! Sosuke,
don't listen to that wacko!
He tricked all the others
into going with him!
- Toki!
- Nobody fools me!
Like I said, there is so little time!
Can't you see that?
If the moon comes any closer,
there will be no going back!
If you're gonna lie,
come up with a better one!
- Sosuke, come to me!
- Humans!
Listen, Sosuke, please come with me!
You're the only one
who can save the planet.
I don't want to use force.
Ponyo!
What a horrible thing to do
to your father!
- Ponyo!
- Sosuke, come on!
Bring them to me!
You can do it!
Jump for it!
Girls!
- Lisa!
- Sosuke.
Ponyo!
Where am I?
- So this is Sosuke.
- How do you do?
- Are you Ponyo's mother?
- Yes.
You brought my daughter
safely here. Thank you.
Sosuke.
Ponyo opened a magic well because
she wants very much to be human.
For her to become human,
she needs you to accept
and love her as she truly is.
You know that Ponyo was a fish,
don't you?
She became half human
when she licked your blood.
Oh, I see... I cut my thumb,
then Ponyo licked it and made it better.
So that's how she changed into a human.
Do you care if Ponyo
is half fish and half human?
I love Ponyo as a fish,
half-fish and fully human.
I love her in all forms.
Ponyo, come here, please.
Ponyo, Sosuke will be your guardian.
To become human,
you must choose to abandon magic.
Can you do that?
Yes!
Kiss the bubble,
when you return to land,
and Ponyo will become a girl.
Five years old, just like you.
I'm happy for you, Ponyo.
Thank you very much, Ponyo's mother.
Everyone,
the balance of nature is restored.
Way to go!
My Sosuke.
Thank you, Lisa.
Thank you. I'll take care of her.
Everyone! Are you all right?
- Wait, let me get your wheelchairs!
- Don't bother. We like to walk.
Life begins again.
This is your ship, I believe.
- Thank you.
- Sorry for everything.
If you will. May I?
Take care of Ponyo.
It's Koichi's ship!
Koichi! Hi! Over here!
It's Lisa! And Sosuke's there, too!
Ahoy!
Look, Ponyo, there's Koichi's ship!
THE END