Tokuma Shoten Presents
Visit bird-hd.info for more m720p Movies Encoded By BiRD
My Neighbor Totoro
Executive Producer
Yasuyoshi Tokuma
Produced by
Tatsumi Yamashita and Hideo Ogata
Supervising Animator
Yoshiharu Sato
Art Director
Kazuo Oga
Music by
Joe Hisaishi
Producer
Toru Hara
Written and Directed by
Hayao Miyazaki
Dad, do you want a caramel?
Thanks. Aren't you tired?
All right.
We're almost there.
Mei, hide!
It wasn't a policeman.
Hello. Are your parents around?
Thanks.
I'm Kusakabe! We've just arrived!
A pleasure to meet you!
Welcome!
Thank you.
Here we are!
Wait!
Mei, there's a bridge!
A bridge?
See that flash? Fish too!
So, you like it here?
Dad, it's terrific!
Look, a tunnel of trees!
Is that our house?
Come on!
It's a wreck!
Wreck!
Looks like a haunted house!
Haunted?
And it's all rotten!
It's gonna fall down!
Fall down!
Look, Mei!
See?
It's huge.
Dad, there's a huge tree!
It's a camphor tree.
Camphor tree...
Oops!
An acorn!
Show me.
Another one!
One for me!
Out of the way.
I can't open the screens.
Acorns!
There's acorns in the house.
They dropped from up there!
Maybe there are squirrels in here.
Squirrels, really?
Or rats that like acorns.
I'd rather have squirrels!
Where shall I put this?
Here, I'll get the door for you.
Satsuki, open up the kitchen.
It's just round the back.
Mei, come on!
Wait for me!
Hurry!
Ready?
Bathtubs.
There's nothing here.
That's the bathroom.
Dad, there's something in here.
A squirrel?
Dunno. A bunch of black things
but not roaches or mice.
Really?
Can you see 'em?
I think they were...dustbunnies.
'Dustbunnies'?
Like in my picture book?
That's right. Ghosts don't come out
on days like this.
When you walk into a dark room
from outside,
your eyes dim and
so the dustbunnies come out.
I see.
Come here, dustbunnies.
Come out, come out, wherever you are!
Let's get to work! See if you can find
how to get upstairs.
Get up there and
open all the windows.
Sure!
I'm coming, too!
Toilet!
Not here!
Nothing here!
Nothing!
Mei, it's here!
It's pitch black!
Dustbunnies...
Another acorn.
Come out, dustbunnies!
Are you there, Mr. Dustbunny?
Dad, there's definitely
something here!
That's exciting! I've always
wanted to live in a haunted house.
I'm coming!
I got it. Satsuki!
Mei.
You're full of energy!
This is 'Nanny'. She looks after
the house and came to help.
I'm Satsuki and
this is my sister, Mei.
Nice to meet you both.
I'd have cleaned up
if I'd known you'd be this quick.
No, you've done plenty.
Lately I've been so busy in the rice
paddies, I only did a bit of dusting...
What have you done to your hands?
The dustbunny got away...
Your feet, too!
Mine are black, too!
That must be the 'soot spreaders'.
Those little, black,
fuzzy things that fly?
That's right.
They breed in empty old houses,
and cover them with soot and dust.
I could see them when I was little.
Now you can too, huh?
Are they like goblins or something?
Naah, nothing so scary.
If you keep smiling,
they'll soon leave the house.
They're probably deciding
where to go next, right now.
Mei, they're going away.
That's no fun.
What happens if a huge one
comes out, like this?
I wouldn't be scared.
Okay then, I won't walk you to
the bathroom at night.
Okay, cleaning time. Could you get
some water from the stream?
From the stream?
I'm coming, too!
Mei, wait there.
Did you get a fish?
Nanny, it's coming out!
Good, keep pumping 'til the water
gets cold.
Okay!
May I help you?
Huh... my Mom... for Granny.
Yes?
Wait, what is it?
Is that you, Kanta?
You live in a haunted house!
Kanta, stop it!
I did the same when I was his age.
I hate boys.
But I really love Nanny's rice cakes!
Eat as much as you want.
Thank you!
Thank you very much for your help.
Good bye!
Dad, the house is going to fall down.
I hope not; we've only just moved in.
Come on, let's laugh to keep
the bogeymen away!
I'm not scared.
I mean it. I'm not scared!
One-two, one-two...
Come on, keep up the good work...
Okay! Washing...finished!
Here we go!
Nanny!
Hello!
Hard at work?
Where're you all heading?
To visit Mommy in the hospital!
That's nice.
Give her my regards!
This way.
Hello.
Hello there.
Mommy!
So glad you came, my dear.
Daddy took the wrong road.
Really? Hello, Satsuki.
It's a school holiday, today.
How nice.
Daddy is talking to the doctor.
It's so good to see you all.
Have you settled into the new house?
A haunted house?
Mom, do you like ghosts?
Of course I do!
I can't wait to see them.
See, I told you Mei.
Mei was worried that
you wouldn't like ghosts.
What about you two?
I love them!
I'm not scared of them!
Are you fixing Mei's hair, Satsuki?
It's really good. Lucky girl, Mei.
But she always gets mad at me.
That's 'cuz you won't stay still.
Come here, Satsuki.
Isn't yours too short?
No, I like it like this.
Do mine, Mommy! Mine, too!
Wait your turn!
Wavy hair, just like mine
when I was your age.
Will it be like yours when I grow up?
Probably. You take after your Mom.
Mom looked really well.
You're right. The doctor says
she'll be home soon.
Soon? Like tomorrow?
You always say this.
Tomorrow is a little too soon.
Mom said she'll sleep with me
in my bed.
Weren't you saying
you're big enough to sleep alone?
Mom is special!
Dad, time to get up!
Wake up!
Sorry, I overslept again...
I've got to bring a box lunch today.
I totally forgot about it.
It's all right.
I've made something for all of us.
It's burning!
I'm coming.
Here, this is yours, Mei.
It's for me?
Mei, sit down and eat!
Here, wrap yours.
Satsuki!
- oh.
I'm coming!
You made a friend already?
She's calling you!
Yup, that's Michiko.
Gotta go!
See ya!
See you later!
Morning!
Hi, let's go.
Daddy!
Do I look all grown up?
Yes dear.
And where might you be going?
I'm just going out.
Daddy, is it lunch yet?
Already?
You be the flower shop, Daddy.
Pole-tads!
Got no bottom.
Gotcha!
Who are you? A big Dustbunny?
To-to-ro? You're Totoro!
I bet you're Totoro.
See you!
Okay, catch you later!
I'm home!
Hey there. Is it that late already?
Where's Mei? I'm off to Michiko's.
We haven't eaten yet.
ls Mei in the garden?
Mei!
Dad, I found her hat!
Wake up, Mei!
You shouldn't sleep here!
Where's Totoro?
Totoro?
Where?
Were you dreaming?
Totoro was here.
You mean that troll
in your picture book?
Yeah. He was all hairy with
a big mouth like this.
There's a tiny one and a little one
and a huge one like this.
There you are.
Wow, this is amazing.
A great hiding place!
Dad, Mei said she met a Totoro here.
A Totoro?
It's this way.
Hey, wait for me!
Huh?!
Here?
No.
It went to a big tree.
But there wasn't any other path.
Mei! Come back!
But it's true! Totoro was here.
I'm not lying.
I know, Mei.
I didn't lie.
Neither of us think you're lying.
You probably met the king of this forest.
You were very lucky.
He doesn't come out very often.
We should pay our respects
at the shrine.
Pay our respects?
To this forest.
Mei, you're getting heavy.
Daddy, look! That camphor tree!
What a big tree.
It's here!
Is that the tree?
Dad, hurry up.
The hole has gone.
Are you sure it was here?
The hole disappeared.
I told you he doesn't come
to see us often.
But will he come again?
I want to meet him, too.
If you're lucky, sure.
What a beautiful tree.
This tree must have stood here
for years and years.
Trees and people
used to be good friends.
I saw that tree and fell in love with
the house. Hope Mom likes it, too.
Okay, let's pay our respects
then get home for lunch.
Yes, I promised to go see Michiko.
I want to go, too!
Attention!
Thank you for looking after Mei.
Please take care of us.
Let's race home!
That's not fair! Dad!
Wait!
Hurry UP!
Wait for me!
Dear Mother, something amazing
happened today.
Mei met a giant Totoro.
And I'm hoping to see him
myself soon, too.
Kanta, hurry up! You'll be late!
Coming...
Mei?
Excuse me!
Yes, Satsuki?
It's my sister...
What happened, Nanny?
I'm sorry. She insisted that
she be with you.
It's Dad's day at the university.
You promised to be
a good girl at Nanny's.
I still have two more classes
and Nanny's too busy for this...
She was good up 'til now,
weren't you?
I'll go talk to my teacher.
Since Satsuki's mother is in the hospital,
I want you all to be nice to her.
What's that?
It's Totoro.
Mei, you should keep quiet.
okay.
Bye bye, Mei!
I can't stay after class today.
We'll let teacher know.
See you!
Hurry up, it's going to rain!
okay
Here it comes!
Here.
I won't cry. Aren't I good?
It's getting worse...
Dear Guardian Spirit,
let us stay until the rain stops.
But...
That was lucky.
It's got holes in it.
Daddy forgot his umbrella.
I'm going, too.
I said I forgot it!
What idiot forgets his umbrella
on a rainy day?
Ouch!
You broke it playing, I bet.
I did not!
Excuse me.
Hello Satsuki. Hi, Mei. Grandma!
I'm sorry about Mei today.
Not at all.
Sorry we couldn't do more.
Kanta lent us this umbrella.
He did?
A broken old thing like that!
Mei was with me, so I was glad.
But I'm so sorry that Kanta got wet.
Not at all. It probably
cleaned him up a little.
Are you off to meet your father?
YES.
What good girls you are.
Bye bye, Mei.
Who was that?
I don't know.
Just in time!
Getting on?
All right, drive on.
Daddy wasn't on it.
He'll be on the next one.
Why don't you wait at Nanny's?
Are you okay?
Sleepy?
I told you. Wanna go to Nanny's?
It won't be much longer.
Hang in there.
It's late...
Come on.
Are you Totoro?
Wait a minute.
You can use this.
Take it, Mei's slipping off.
Hold it like this.
Here's the bus!
He took Daddy's umbrella...
I'm sorry.
All right, drive on.
The train was late
and I missed the bus.
Were you worried?
We met him, Dad! He was here!
And the cat bus!
What?
It was huge!
With big eyes like these!
We met him! We met Totoro!
How wonderful!
Come on, Daddy.
Dear /I//other, I can '2' tell you
how excited I was today.
it was the scariest, funniest day
I've ever had.
Totoro gave us a lovely present...
wrapped in bamboo /eaves and
tied with dragon whiskers.
when we opened it,
it was full of magic nuts and seeds!
'We decided to plant them in the garden
to make a lovely forest.'
But they haven 't sprouted yet.
Mei sits there all day, waiting for them.
She looks like a little crab
It's nearly summer vacation.
Dearest, dear Mom, get well soon.
Love, Satsuki.
Come on. Bed time.
Lights off!
Wait, Dad.
Daddy, do you think they will
sprout tomorrow?
Well, I'm sure Totoro would know.
Night night.
Mei!
That's where we planted the seeds.
Wow, we did it!
We're the wind!
There are no trees!
yes
It was a dream.
But it wasn't a dream.
We did it!
Mr. Kusakabe! Telegram!
Anyone home?
Nanny.
I'm here.
This one is ripe.
What about this one?
That's good, too.
Your garden's a treasure house.
Let's take a little break.
These should be cold now.
Looks delicious.
So good.
The sun blessed these so
they're really good for you.
Would they help my Mom, too?
Of course. If she eats my vegetables,
she'll get better right away.
She's supposed to be back next Saturday.
She'll sleep in my bed!
At last. That's wonderful.
But it's only for a couple of days.
To get used to the new house.
I see. We'll feed her lots of
vegetables, then.
I'll give her this corn I picked.
I'm sure she'll be very pleased.
Yes!
There was a telegram for you.
For us?
Dad won't be back till late,
what shall I do?
Open it, it might be important.
PLEASE CONTACT, HOSPITAL...
It's from Mom's hospital!
Something's happened to her!
Nanny! What shall I do?
Calm down. Do you know
where your Dad is?
I know his office number,
but we don't have a telephone.
Kanta, take her to use the phone
in the main house!
Mei, stay here with me!
Stay with Nanny, Mei!
Hello, I'd like to make a
long-distance call, please.
It's Tokyo 31 '1382.
A cute girl, Kanta.
Hello? Yes?
Hello, may I speak to
Dad... er... Mr. Kusakabe?
It's his daughter, Satsuki.
Daddy? It's me, Satsuki!
Hello, what's up? From the hospital?
Okay, /'// ca// them right away.
Is there anything wrong with Mom?
Don 't' worry.
/'// check and call you right back.
I'm hanging up now, stay there.
May I stay here until he calls back?
Stay as long as you like.
Satsuki!
No, this corn is for my Mommy!
No, it's my Mom's!
Listen Mei. Mom's not well
so she's not coming home this time.
No!
There's nothing we can do.
You don't want her to get worse, do you?
No!
It's just for a few more days.
So you don't care
if she dies, do you?
Stop being silly! I'm going.
Let's go, Mei.
I hate you, Satsuki!
We should bring the washing in...
Don't worry too much, Satsuki.
Nanny's here to help, so cheer up.
Your Dad said he'll stop by the hospital
to check on her.
Besides, it's just a cold;
she'll be back next week.
They said it was just a cold...
when she went into hospital.
But what if she dies!
Don't be silly, Satsuki.
Maybe Mom will...
Stop it. Nobody would leave
two pretty little girls like you.
There, there. Don't cry.
I'll be here
until Daddy comes back, okay?
Mei!
Did she come back?
Wasn't she at the bus stop?
That's strange.
Where has she gone?
I was nasty to her,
'cause she was being silly...
Maybe she's heading for
the hospital!
The hospital? It would take
a grown-up three hours!
I'll go look!
Kanta, hurry! Tell your dad
that Mei is missing!
Stupid Mei. Always getting lost.
Excuse me.
Have you seen a little girl pass by?
She's my sister.
No, I don't think so.
I'm sure I would've noticed...
Maybe she wasn't here.
Are you sure she came this way?
I don't know.
Please, stop!
Jerk! What are you doing?!
I'm looking for my sister.
Have you seen a little girl?
Your little sister?
She's four.
I think she's heading to the hospital.
Did you see anyone?
No. We just came from there...
but we didn't see anyone.
Thanks anyway.
Where have you come from?
From Matsugo.
Really?
Good luck.
Satsuki!
Kanta!
Find her?
No. And you?
Dad and the others are looking
for her. I'll go to the hospital,
you go back home.
I guess she got lost
on the way to the hospital.
They found a sandal by the pond.
We're not sure if it's hers or not!
Did you find her?
Dear Lord, please protect her and...
It's too deep here,
better search further away!
Hey, are there any poles left?
Grandma, Satsuki's here!
Nanny!
Look, is it hers?
No, it isn't.
Thank heavens,
I was sure it was hers.
Hey, Nanny was
jumping to conclusions.
It's not hers!
Where's she gone then?
Let's start from scratch.
We better hurry,
it'll be dark soon.
I really appreciate
your help, everyone.
Don't worry.
Could have been any of us.
Please, help me Totoro!
Mei is lost. It'll be dark soon.
I'm sure she's scared somewhere...
Totoro!
Mei is lost
and we can't find her!
She must be scared,
please help me find her.
I don't know what to do...
They can't see the bus.
FOREST-SWAMP
CEMETERY-SHRINE
MEI
Mei!
The trees are
moving out of the way!
Satsuki!
Mei!
You silly girl.
I'm sorry.
You wanted to take the corn to Mom?
HOSPITAL
Will you take us to the hospital?
Thank you so much.
I'm sorry. They didn't need to send
a telegram just for a cold.
The girls must be worried.
I'm sorry to upset them.
They'll be fine.
As long as you're okay.
We've all learned to cope.
This'll just postpone the enjoyment.
They've put up with it so well.
I'm especially sorry for Satsuki,
she's been so patient.
You're right.
I'm going to spoil them
for a while when I come home.
No!
She's laughing!
Looks like she's fine.
I can't wait to get back on my feet.
look
Where did that come from?
What?
I could swear I just saw Satsuki
and Mei laughing up in that tree.
Maybe they were too. Look.
'For Mother'
VOICES Satsuki Noriko
Hidaka Mei Chika Sakamoto
Dad Shigesato ltoi Mom Sumi
Shimamoto Nanny Tanie Kitabayashi
'Sampo'
Lyrics by Rieko Nakagawa
'Tonari no Totoro'
Lyrics by Hayao Miyazaki
Music Composed and Arranged by Joe
Hisaishi Performed by Azumi lnoue
English Translation by Aya Futami,
Kennedy Taylor & Stephen Alpert
English Subtitles by AURA
A Studio Ghibli Film
The End