You are so beautiful.
You look like a rose blooming
in a secret flower garden.
You, bastard! This is private garden.
I really want you to look at this.
Oh, this is from Hollywood.
About the production
of the scenario and casting you sent.
We are in the middle of preliminary trials
The title is "A bouquet of the Adriatic Sea".
That's nice.
Really? That means O.K., doesn't it?
Gina, come to Hollywood with me.
I was air pirates' guardsman
to obtain a fame and fortune.
Next I want to be a Hollywood star.
And, then?
The President!
I'm serious.
I promise to make you the first lady.
Gina.
I like your for such stupidity.
Really?
But I say no...
... because I already have a gamble going.
If he comes over here
when I'm in this garden, I will love him.
But he comes only to the
restaurant at night.
And never emerges in the daylight.
That guy is coming back.
Fool...
He left without getting off the plane.
I lost the gamble again.
You're kidding!
The gamble is about that guy?
Is that a problem?
Life is more complicated here
than in your country.
Here I can fall in love anytime I want.
Kid, go to Hollywood by yourself, OK?
Kid...
I hit my head because you did an acrobatic
maneuver all of a sudden.
I just said hello to my friend.
To Gina of the hotel Adriano?
She wore a white dress and
was at the terrace of the hotel, wasn't she?
My grandpa told me that all pilots of
the Adriatic Sea fall in love with Gina.
You speculate a lot.
So, how is the lady?
You fell in love with her too,
didn't you?
We are going down to refuel.
Close your mouth,
or you'll bite your tongue off.
Wa! Wait! Uwaa...
A girl on a fighter?
Where's Porco?
He is talking with my dad.
Not only the temporary government...
... but guys in the King's faction have
tried to get along with the air pirates.
Here you are.
Thanks.
No thanks for such a bad news.
You'd better present yourself to either side.
They will pay a fortune for your skill.
You got a cigarette?
Curtis is will go back to
America sooner or later.
It's us who should to go to America.
Goodbye to freedom in the Adriatic Sea.
Is it Byron's?
No, it's mine.
See you later.
Porco, this is bad news.
The gas price is three times
as much as in ltaly.
Don't be like a businessman,
make it cheaper.
This gas is genuine.
That's why I hate women.
Hey, Mr. Would you tell her...
Pay him, Fio.
After that, put your big butt and your looks
in the space between the machine guns.
We're going to fly to my home.
I'll add the gas bill to the other bills.
Nobody can live alone.
We rely on each other.
Nobody lives around here,
even though the landscape is beautiful.
Here we are.
That island is my home.
It's a wonderful place.
An excellent co-ordinator.
Ohh... my butt is stiff from the long flight.
The pig!
Don't move!
They stink, again.
Boss, we caught him! Boss!
Shit! Don't step on me... Back off!
I was waiting for you, pig!
I knew you'd coming here.
You gave us a lot of trouble.
It's a girl.
The pig is with a girl.
She is pretty.
Shut up! What's that about a girl?
About a half of the worlds
population are women!
Hey, that girl is not an ordinary one.
She is a chief engineer
at the Piccolo company.
But, she is very young and pretty.
That girl?
She made my plane much better than before.
She may be young, but she's really something.
Is that true?
You are good with airplanes in general.
Be polite, boys.
She came with me to collect my debts.
You are deeply in debt after all.
It serves you right!
C'mon men, let's do some damage
around here.
Damage?
Are you going to break the plane I made?
Are you going to break
such beautiful airplane with axes?
Miss,
there is a complicated reason behind this.
You are going to break, aren't you?
But, what I want to say is...
Are you guys really fighter pilots?
Would you back off? My shoes.
I have grown up with a lot of stories
about the pilots since I was a small child.
My grandpa always told me that
no one is as nice as the pilots.
It's because sea and
sky purify their hearts.
Hence, the pilots are much
braver than the sailors...
... and more proud
than the ordinary pilots.
Don't tell me.
I know that.
What they want the most, he said,
is neither money nor women...
... but honor.
Yes. Yes.
You're right!
A toast to the pilots!
She's really something.
I understand.
I'll give up on breaking the plane,
you made, with axes.
But we'll be mortified
if we don't do anything.
Let's lynch the pig!
Lynch the pig!
What the hell you talking about!
You guys don't understand anything.
I asked whether you feel ashamed or not.
Aren't you ashamed of being helped by Curtis,
the American?
If your mother heard of that,
she would cry.
And you don't even take a shower.
Porco came back to fight against Curtis...
... for pride and honor of the
pilots of the Adriatic.
You guys are lowest of the low!
I told you not to hire Curtis, eh!
Just like a girl.
Don't try to excuse yourself.
Boss, what are we supposed to do?
She convinced us.
How about asking Curtis to fight the pig?
Do we ask him to fight the pig, again?
The contract is already over.
I'm ashamed of it...
That's Curtis!
I got it.
I'm not going to run away!
You made your passage through there?
Hey, hold this.
You want a return match, don't you.
But I won once, already.
Besides, I am not a bounty hunter
for these guys.
What's your proposition?
Beautiful!
Will you marry me if I win?
I'm serious.
O.K.
Instead, if Porco wins,
you pay these bills.
Wait, Fio!
You back off!
Miss, you still have time
to think about that.
Ask him, not me.
This is very expensive.
It's very cheap.
Are you going to fight or not?
I'm willing to fight...
... for love.
O.K.
Listen up everybody.
I'm really impressed
with Miss Fio's decision.
We, "Mamma Aiuto",
are going to back up this fight up!
Yes.
Let the air pirates union do this, too!
Miss Fio! See you soon!
This sucks!
Hey pig, don't run away!
Shut up, get lost!
Bye-bye!
This is ridiculous. Well, you are...
Don't tell me. I know, I am foolish.
Fio...
... I think I have to say thank you.
You gave me a chance to fight Curtis.
Thanks.
We share the same luck.
We are partners, aren't we?
We are going to have a hard time.
I trust you.
Trust me, eh?
I haven't heard that in a long time...
... but I'm glad you said that.
What's wrong? You feel sick?
Fio?
I'm fine.
It's just that my heart is pounding.
To be honest, I was really scared.
Hey?
I want to swim.
Porco! I made a mistake!
Are you O.K?
I should have padded the deal.
We have a bad bargain.
You're right.
Porco...
Hmm?
You can't sleep, can you?
Now, I just saw...
It may have been a dream...
Everything is all right.
It's too early in the morning to get up.
Porco?
Why did you become a pig?
I don't know.
I know a lot about Captain Marco Pabatto.
My father used to be in the same unit.
I've heard many stories,
in which the captain...
... saved the lives of enemy pilots.
I liked it.
Porco! How about if I kiss you?
You know a fairy tale
where a princess takes off...
... a curse on a prince,
who was changed to a frog.
You, silly. Save it for your man!
Won't my kiss work?
Huh, you are a nice girl.
You make me feel comfortable...
... and make me wish
to be a human being again.
Be a nice girl and go to sleep.
Tell me your story and I will.
My story?
Well...
It was the last summer of the war.
We were fly over the Adriatic Sea
on our usual patrol.
Belneldi was flying on my right side.
He was an old friend of mine.
He got married just two days before.
I was the matchmaker.
He didn't have enough leave
to be with his wife for long.
So, he returned to duty.
Everyone was falling down like flies,
whether a friend or a foe.
I was chased by three planes...
... and had no time to worry about my friend.
At the end I was the only one
remaining of my unit.
But, they never gave up chasing me.
I made desperate efforts to run away.
My hands and feet went numb...
... and I grew dizzy.
I thought I was going to die.
It was at that time that
I saw the white sky.
White?
Yeah, it was like a flash.
Because of the brightness,
it took me a while to realize that I was in a cloud.
I was worn out, and
didn't have any power left to control my plane.
In spite of that my plane continued to fly.
And what happened then?
It was calm...
... and the sky was very clear, too clear.
There was a line of clouds far above me.
Belneldi, you are alive, aren't you!
Belneldi, wait, where are you going!
Belneldi, don't go!
Are you going to leave Gina alone?!
I'll go instead of you!
When I recovered my senses, I was flying
over the sea, almost touching it, alone.
God said it wasn't your time yet,
didn't he?
In my mind I thought he might
let me fly like that forever.
That would not have been right,
because your are a good guy!
The good guys are all dead already.
Besides, there might have been
Hell inside that cloud.
Well, my story is over.
Go to sleep.
Shit, they gave me crap.
I'm glad you came back to live
because I like you.
Goodnight!
Hey, hey, which one's gonna win,
a pig or...
Icecream? Telescope?
Fools. They make a festival of our fight.
Are they all air pirates?
Trash of the Mediterranean Sea.
Gangs, pirates, smugglers,
spies and even some ordinary people.
This makes my fame rise more and more.
Ten minutes till start!
This is the fight between Porco Rosso
and Donald Curtis!
There are no special rules...
... but an unfair fight will a
disgrace to their fans.
Shut up and start right now. Back off!
You shut up, or I kill you!
He'd be better off throwing a 10 ton bomb.
This is the fight which will determine
the future of Miss Fio Piccolo.
Shut up!
Do you understand?
If you do, clap your hands.
Clap!
Shut up, that's the routine.
Well, both of you present your bids.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Put it on the chair properly!
None of you have anything to say, do you.
Well shake hands or something before you start!
No way. I'm fond of cleanliness.
He's hard to please.
Fio, as soon as this fight is over,
we will go to the church.
Don't worry.
My mom told me your going to like me soon.
You...
May I take a picture with you?
I took a shower already.
Everybody, smile!
SMILE!
If the flight is over in 3 minutes,
the black plane has the advantage...
This is great.
I want them to do this event every month.
15 seconds to go.
They are so cool.
5 seconds to go.
4, 3, 2, 1, 0!
Curtis took off first!
This is going to be a one-sided fight.
Give me that.
Porco, what are you doing! Fly over!
He would be shot if the took off now.
It's very difficult for Curtis
to shoot Porco in this situation.
I know you want me to waste the bullet's.
I know it.
Looping! The pig took Curtis' back!
Looping?
His skill made the pig
an ace of the Adriatic Sea.
Shit!
He's gonna shoot!
He doesn't open fire.
Is his machine-gun broken!?
I got it, I got it!
The pig won't shoot until the end.
The pig doesn't kill anybody.
Now, the American should be fine.
You got it! Go and shoot!
Oh, he didn't shoot yet.... See,
I told you...
If the pig opened fire, it would kill
the American, so it's going to hit...
... Curtis' engine a few bullets
after Curtis gets tired.
He said this is not war, but...
Porco...
Are you teasing me or what?
Come on!
Is your gun broken, huh! You,
poor bastard!
They are coming this way!
Come on, pig!
Go away from here and fight over there!
Great! The pig is leaving a cloud trail.
Come on!
Shoot the other side!
It's cool! It's the first time
I saw the plance leaving a cloud trail!
I've never seen such an air fight before.
I'm really impressed.
I'm ready for the flight.
She'd better hurry,
or the fight will be over.
She's in her room, and doesn't come out.
Does she want to go or not?
I want to see that fight.
To G of Heart, for the pig.
The air force found out about the fight.
Stop the silly fight.
Oh, this must be from Fierrali.
I must hurry.
First of all,
both of them are very tough.
The show isn't over!
Porco, fight!
I'm not going to give Fio to a man
like you.
O.K. the pig took Curtis' tail.
It's over!
Jammed.
This is the end.
Whoops... Jammed, too.
You, idiot! You are out of ammo!
Whoops.
This is broken because of Fio's butt...
I'm not going to finish this fight with a draw.
This is not a western. You can't hit me.
You...
You really think it will reach here?
You, stinking pig!
Can't throw it!
Bastard!
Throw it finally!
For love!
Shut up! You piggy!
Looks like something is wrong.
Ah... they are coming.
They are coming back!
Wait! Bids don't leave from here.
O.K. Wait, you guys.
You, fat pig!
You, chicken cowboy!
Come on with your bare hands!
Go back to cows!
Porco, hold on!
Stand up, pig.
Go, go!
Finish him!
Come on Porco!
Bets still stand!
Where's the betting table?
- Can't you fly much faster?
- It's impossible. Engine would blow.
Pilots are all stupid, aren't they?
Hey, Fio. Did you see my punch?
I'm gonna take him down next round.
I'll take you down this time.
Porco, hang on!
I'll make prosciutto out of you!
Come on, you chicken!
You are the chicken!
That was my word.
You seduce all women around you.
Choose Gina or Fio, either one!
What?
Don't choose both.
Gina is...
Don't say, Gina, Gina.
Gina loves you, pig.
She is...
... waiting for you...
... at the garden!
Porco!
Drumroll!
It's over! Look at that!
I can see it.
The Italian Air Force hasn't arrived, yet.
You are unfair... You're a dirty liar.
Don't you understand, you idiot.
I am not telling a lie...
I don't give Fio to you.
That's Gina's plane.
It's an emergency signal.
1, 2...
The winner is the one who stand up first.
Everybody, let me through.
6, 7, Gina, don't.
8!
Marco, Marco, can you hear me?
Do you want another girl to be unhappy?
9!
Porco!
Porco, thank you!
Well...
This party is over.
The Air Force will be here soon.
Everybody run away quickly, please.
Then stop by my restaurant.
I will serve you all.
Everybody, let's go!
It's over, Mr.
Hey, boss, hurry up!
Shut up! I'm coming.
I don't like the pig, but I like you.
Goodbye!
Thank you.
Take a shower sometimes, will you?
Thank you, too, Mr. Curtis.
Next time I'll propose you formally,
not as a bet.
O.K. But I've made up my mind already.
You, get on Gina's plane.
No! No!
I'm going on Porco's plane.
You said I'm your partner, didn't you.
Gina. Take her home, please.
You always do this.
I'm sorry. Please leave.
Let's go.
The Italian Air Force is finally coming.
Do you want to help me?
I'm going to lead them astray.
Wait, your face!
Let me see your face!
Your plane is over there, eh?
Let me see it a little bit!
After the flight from the Air Force,
I returned to Milan.
I haven't seen Porco since.
Instead, I have found
a very good friend in Miss Gina.
Since the fight,
there have been many wars.
But I still keep in touch with Gina.
After I took over the "Piccolo" factory,
I made it a rule to spend summer vacations
at the Hotel Adriano.
Miss Gina has become even more beautiful since.
Old friends still stop
by the Hotel all the time.
Mr. Curtis, now I recall...
...writes to me sometimes.
Though he is not the president of the USA, yet...
... he says he longs for the summer
of Adriatic Sea.
It's only our secret that Gina...
... won her gamble.
The End