This motion picture is set over the
Mediterranean Sea in an age when...
... seaplanes ruled the waves. It
tells the story of a valiant pig, who...
... fought against flying pirates, for
his pride, for his lover, and for his...
... fortune. The name of the hero of our
story is "Porco Rosso".
PORCO ROSSO
Yeah?!
Porco Rosso, get going.
"Mamma Aiuto" is on the move.
"Mamma Aiuto"?
I don't need a cheap job.
A charter ship from Venice was attacked.
They are stealing fuel from the ship.
Is that it?
Ah... Well...
Girl students on vacation were on board.
It's going to be more costly then you think.
I'm going to apply part three
of the contract 14 to this case.
And part four, too.
Stop...
Or I'm going to sink you! Stop!
I'm going to be kidnapped, yeah!
- They're pirates, sea pirates!
- It's not "sea pirates", it's "air pirates".
It needs 'overhaul', huh...
- Are you bad guys?
- Yeah.
- Are we hostages?
- You guys are called air pirates, not?
- You know a lot.
It's a skull.
Neat, isn't it?
Hurry up kids! I'm busy.
Do you want all 15 of them?
It's not nice for a girl
to be left behind, don't you think.
I'm late
The girls were kidnapped
by air pirates!
Bring the girls back!
They went that way!
No! Not that way!
I know what they are thinking.
Because they're poor and stingy...
... and want to save on gasoline...
... they will change their course
to the nearest island...
... as soon as they're out of sight.
Shit!
Damn it!
This is no good.
Here we are.
What the heck is this?
A sightseeing plane around the islands.
A pig!
It's a pig!
It's a pig. What a cute pig...
You girls could be kidnapped here.
Watch out babes!
Cool! He's cool!!
What a nuisance!
We are flying! Let me see, let me see!
Hey, kids. Don't.
Shut up, shut up, please.
Hey, do something, will you?
That's why I asked
if we wanted to take all of them.
Ok, just for a little bit.
Coz you are too naughty...
Wow! Wonderful!
Hey, look at that!
It's a red plane.
Where, where!
He is over there, isn't he?
Yes!
I'm not going to let you go any further.
See, he is coming.
That's Porco Rosso!
Hey, I can't see.
Holly cow!
It stopped.
We are gonna fall.
Not yet!
We have one more engine!
Damn it. What the heck are you doing!
Shoot, shoot him, shoot him down!
Wow! That red plane is cool isn't it?
- You can't hit him, can you?
- You're in my way.
The morse code!
You loose. Listen to me.
Shut up!
There, he is coming! Here!
Get your heads down!
Where, where is he?
He must be hiding.
Wow. We are sinking.
Let's go, let's go! Come!
We are not sinking.
This is a plane!
Sinking!
Don't! It's dangerous!
Stop them.
They are very valuable hostages to us!
Don't worry, mister.
We are students at the swimming school.
- Oh, no.
- Me too.
Contact from the pig again.
I'm going to allow you
to take half of the gold coins.
But leave the rest of the coins
and the hostages, behind!
If you don't,
I'm going to kill you all!
Says the pig. But...
A half of the coins!?
Keep your mouth shut!
Come on, Pig.
Let's fight!
Go to hell!
What?!
It's broken.
It's over! We surrender!
We surrender!
Bye bye, play with us again, will you?
Bye bye.
Everything is fine, isn't it?
Since we have enough money for repairs
You, idiot. Be greedy!
Calm down, calm down, will you.
Don't touch that,
it will get broken.
Don't go close to the propeller.
Uhm? Pee? Do it around there, will you?
A new triumph for Porco Rosso.
Mamma Aiuto's guys
said they couldn't come to see us.
Shit! Such a pig became a hero.
But, the young fella is an American,
isn't he?
If he is...
... that's a shame for the pilots
of the Adriatic.
Oh, not at all.
His grandmother is quarter ltalian.
Anyway, we should do something
about the pig.
- We have a great deal of trouble.
- But, 10%? That's not fair.
Shhh...
Here he comes.
He sucks. He is a fake.
Shhh...
Mr. Porco Rosso!
I'm a reporter for
the Neptune newspaper.
You did another great job,
again.
I think "Mamma Aiuto" is not
going to appear again for a while.
People say your estimated amount of bounty
must be over that of the last year...
Ouch! Wait. Let me go.
Listen to a song in silence.
She is a wonderful lady.
Madam Gina of the hotel Adriano...
... is very famous among the pilots
through out this country.
During her song, even air pirates
and bounty hunters become good guys.
Is that plane up front yours?
Yeah, it's the plane with the rattle snake
bringing me fame and fortune.
The plane beat an ltalian
at the Schneider cup, twice.
Not only is it fast,
but it is also and excellent fighter.
I heard that a small pig named Porco Rosso
is famous around here.
If you make a deal with the air pirates,
watch your tail "cowboy".
They are misers and are poor, too.
They stink,
for they don't take a shower.
Uh uh... I know that.
What!
Come on, you little chicken shit!
What's going on tonight?
You're up to no good, aren't you?
He, he, he, he...
Yes ma'am.
I'm glad you came,
but don't play war games.
We know, Gina.
We don't work within 50km
from this establishment.
We are getting along with even that pig.
You're good boys.
See you later.
Whaa, whaa, what are you doing!
Hi, Porco, tell me your story.
Next time two of us are alone.
That Mr. America is funny.
As soon as he sees me...
"Will you marry me?"
So I told him:
I married three pilots...
the first died in the war,
the second died over the Atlantic Ocean...
... and the last one died in Asia.
You got the news?
I got it today.
It said the remains were found
in the forest of Bengal.
I have been waiting for three years.
My tears dried up long ago.
Good guys always die.
For my friend.
Marco, thank you for staying with me
all those years.
You are my best friend.
The only thing I don't like...
is that you don't want
to take that picture off.
Don't break it, you promised me.
That's only picture left
of Marco as a human.
How can we break your curse?
That American is very talented.
I envy you.
I wish I would make money like you.
This is the payment for this month.
You've payed off the entire loan
for the airplane.
Let's see, how about buying some patriots bond
in devotion to our country?
I'll let the humans do that.
Welcome, Mr. Porco Rosso.
This one is ready.
- Give me 60 rounds of ammo as well.
- O.K.
This country is busy, isn't it?
Oh, yeah.
The government is probably going to change.
If so, people like you will be outlaws.
Country and law
don't mean anything to a pig.
You're right, Mr.
So goes for a mole.
Is it ok like usual?
We have a new supply of an incendiary bomb.
Hey, kid. I'm not going to war.
See you.
Later...
Excuse me, boss.
Could you tell me the difference
between a soldier and a bounty hunter?
Uhm... You're a scum
if you can't win in war.
You're useless and stupid
if you can't make a fortune.
I've never heard of an air pirate
who was deeply in debt.
We had nothing to barter with, Captain.
We couldn't even pay for the paint.
There's ships up ahead!
Why do I have to stay
with such pathetic looking group?
It's due to the pig, Porco Rosso.
What's that?
The guys of "Aiuto" don't even
have money for paint.
Poor looking boys.
Well, we are finally complete.
Hey, is Mr. America around?
Yes, he is in the sun.
Just like we told.
I sighted the target!
It's the Queen of the Mediterranean!
Are we going to take on such a big ship?
That's why we prepared well.
Don't be afraid!
My engine is in trouble.
I'm going to back you up. You go first.
You are cunning!
Do as we agreed!
We share cost of repairs
and expenses when we loose, don't we?
You, stingy...
Of course we share them!
We need to share the bullets too?
Altak is the only right candidate
to speak out here!
We've just discussed this issue.
- You cunning bitch!
- If we can't share that, I will quit...
Shut up! Calm down!
Attention please, attention please.
Air pirates are attacking this ship...
... but there is nothing to worry about.
This ship has excellent fighters.
Let me introduce them.
No. 1 is the black stallion,
signore Bulkar...
... and No.2 is the seawolf, Visconti.
I didn't know they had fighter protection.
How can it be?
It's totally a mess.
Come over here, Curtis!
Curtis
Pass it to me!
This engine finally had it.
Looks like I'll have to take it to Milan.
... they were shot down...
... but they succeeded in escaping
by parachute.
The air pirates, who took all the money
and gold away from the ship...
... left the following message,
"You are next, pig!"
"Come and get it, pig!"
I repeat
You are next, pig!
Come and get it, pig!
This crime...
You guys are special kind of trash.
I'm sorry, but I'm going on vacation.
White sheets...
... beautiful ladies.
Don't give out on me yet, Mr. Engine.
I don't like this weather.
Well, guess I'll have
to go under the clouds.
Oh, good boy, hang in there.
Yes, you are a good boy, engine.
Rosso!
Fight me man to man.
I don't have time to play with you.
Don't run away...
... or I'm going to tell everybody about it.
See you later, Mr. America, ha ha ha...
Shit, I'm out of the clouds.
Damn it.
Gotcha!
No, you didn't.
It's broken.
I did it!
Now, I'm a celebrity.
They are not going to believe me...
... if I don't bring back any proof.
Let's see...
Yes!
This cheap, red colored piece.
This is it.
This will be a nice gift
for my mom in Alabama.
Please hurry up.
Madam...
... madam. Telephone, please.
He is alive after all.
Please get the phone at the front desk.
Marco, is this you?
Did you get hurt?
I was about to leave to pick you up.
Ok, that's fine.
I lost some weight, because I was stranded
on a deserted island.
I'm going to Milan to repair my plane.
If that Mr. America stops by your hotel...
...tell him this, please,
"See you again, next time."
What? You think of me as a
bulletin board or something?!
However I'm worried about you guys,
and pilots like you regard women...
... as nails in a landing pier
or something insignificant.
Marco, you're going to end up
as roast pork someday.
I'd hate to witness such a miserable funeral.
A pig that doesn't fly is just an ordinary pig.
Marco, you fool!
Red broken wings.
Porco Rosso, dead or alive?
I guessed you would come tonight.
I come to disturb you again!
You lost too much this time.
Why don't you just build another one?
I want to keep this one.
I know how you feel.
Step aside, please.
I need drive into the factory.
Who is that cute girl?
My granddaughter,
who was living in America.
Alright, alright, alright.
Nice plane.
It's neat grandpa.
Good design.
There is almost no workers to do the job
like this these days.
She doesn't resemble you.
Is she really your granddaughter?
Don't touch her!
Fio, I leave this to you.
Ok. I'll do it.
The opponent is Curtis.
I need 15 knots more.
Curtis? I've heard of him.
Look at this.
This is a Hallvolley, isn't it.
Don't ask how I got this.
An Italian plane
which had this engine lost a race...
... against Curtis
at the Schneider's cup in 1927.
But it lost due to poor engineering...
... not due to this engine.
This is exciting.
Don't tune it up too delicately.
My plane is not for such racing.
An Asian proverb calls this "Preaching
a sermon to Buddha". Did you know that?
Are you going to take all of my money?
These days,
rolls of bills aren't worth a damn.
Give me the money in your pocket,
for the propeller, the paint and...
That's is for living expenses,
such as a hotel and meals.
You can stay here. I'm not going to
charge you much. Meals included.
I don't see your sons.
Are they alright?
All three left looking for work.
Then... Who is going to design my plane?
Fio is.
Fio! That's a girl, isn't she.
She is young,
but she's got something my sons lack.
Hey, old man.
We've known each other for a long time...
... but I think I'll look
for another repairman this time.
Wait.
You are nervous because
I'm a woman, aren't you?
Or, am I too young to do it?
Both, Miss.
Ok. I agree with you.
Well, can you tell me the first priority
of being a good pilot?
Experience?
No, inspiration, I think.
Oh, I'm glad you didn't say experience.
Anyway, I heard from grandpa
that you flew at an early age...
... and have been an excellent pilot since then.
That was 1910, when I was 17.
17! That's the same age I am now.
I can't quit being a woman...
... but let me do the job, will you?
If I can't do it well, don't pay me.
Is it ok, grandpa?
She is my granddaughter, she'll do well.
In my case, I was able
to fix engines at the age of 12.
Could you sleep here tonight?
I'll make your bed tomorrow.
The breakfast is at 7:00am.
You can take a hot shower.
I've left a towel already.
Have a good night.
You don't have enough money.
But we know each other well...
... so will make the rest a loan.
Goodmorning. Did you sleep well?
Did you stay up all night?
This is the rough plan.
What do you think?
I want to redesign this wing section,
leaving the plane shape as it is.
This will make your plane fly faster.
I'm surprised at the original plan.
The wing was also made of wood.
This plane is great.
The designer who designed
this wing must have know the wood very well.
I'm really impressed.
This is the only plane of its kind made...
... nobody used it...
... just put in the store room.
No wonder!
I'm surprised that this radical design...
... allows you to take off from water surface.
Only take offs and
landings give me some difficulty.
It behaves strange during the flight.
Add 0.5 degrees to the angle
of the wings, right?
Everything should be fine then.
You'll let me continue with this,
won't you?
Thank you, Mr.! I'll do my best!
But let me tell you something, Miss.
Don't stay up all night.
Insomnia prevents
you from doing an excellent job.
And it is not good for your beauty.
Thank you for your advice.
Well...
... to be honest,
I couldn't sleep well last night.
I was worried that
you won't let me do this job.
Well, I'm very sleepy now.
I'll make coffee for you.
Is she going to build this plane alone?
Next is my niece, Monica.
She is will be in charge of general construction.
This is a wife of my nephew, Silvana.
She is going to do finishing construction.
These are daughters of my relatives.
Sophia, Laura, Constance, Valentina.
This is Fio's elder sister, Giliora.
This is Sandra, my cousin.
You look so pretty Marietta.
Wives of my sons,
Maria, Tina, Anna
and her younger sister Birreta.
Angelino!
Grandma!
Are you still alive?
You've grown up to be a nice boy!
Are you ladies going to work?
Yes, I'd like to have some money
for my great-grandchildren.
There are no men here, right?
Ah...
All these are your relatives?
Yes, they don't have any jobs these days.
All the men went to other places to work.
Because of the "Great Depression"?
Don't worry.
Girls are nice, they work very well
and are also gutsy.
Making an airplane is in no way
like baking a cake, I think...
Dear God.
You gave my company,
which was about to go bankrupt...
... a piece of bread and a job.
Please forgive us,
who make a fighter plane with ladies.
Amen.
Well, let's eat well and work hard!
Sounds good!
This engine is quite something!
What do you say, it's nice, isn't it?
Don't over do it
or this factory will be gone.
Huh, you think Curtis is not worth it?
Uh-hm, sure, this is a good idea.
So, let me do it.
But, this is going to cost a fortune.
I got a lot of bills already.
I'm not sure what our sponsor thinks.
Porco...
Ok, ok. Don't look at me like that.
Do it your way.
Yes! I've already talked to the manufacturers.
I will order these immediately.
Porco, I love you!
Wait at least three months, will you?
I want to change my job
and become an air pirate.
She is a nice girl, isn't she.
Don't touch her.
If I would be henpecked,
I could not feel happy.
You're a major now?
You rose in the world, Fierrali.
You, fool. Why did you come back?
I make it a rule to go wherever I want to.
The government is not going
to let you go this time.
Did somebody follow you?
I gave them the slip.
A warrant for your arrest
is going to be issued.
Hey, this is no time to laugh.
They say they will confiscate your plane.
This movie is crap, don't you think.
Hey, Marco, come back to the air force.
I would make room for you.
I'd rather be a pig than a fascist.
The era of sky adventures is over.
It's the only thing left for us to do.
To fly for such ridiculous reasons
as the country or the nation?
You are a pig after all, huh?
Thanks for your advice, Fierrali.
Give my regards to the others.
This is a nice film, don't you think.
Watch your tail cowboy.
They don't sue a pigs, but...
Goodbye, my comrade.
Porco, need a ride?
Hey, you're a life saver.
I borrowed this because
I need to take your plane to the lake tomorrow.
It's for a test flight.
I don't need the test flight.
I need to fly as soon as possible.
Don't be such a fool.
I'm not going to give you the plane
without testing it.
Besides, it will take almost a day
to take it apart and transport it to the lake.
We don't have much time.
Take a look back, will you, slowly.
That's the fascists secret police.
They were following you, Fio.
Me? Why? For what?
Because I gave them the slip.
And, because you are working on my plane.
Porco, are you really a spy?
Ha, ha, ha, ha! l? A spy?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Look, a secret agent works much harder than l.
But, you were a hero during the war.
This is strange if you didn't do anything.
I think so, too.
This is not right way!
Looks like you're used to being in big trouble.
Well, we will be very busy.
You can fly anytime you want.
Two guys are hiding in the backyard,
and three in the front.
This excites me!
Hey, don't ramble.
See you later.
Take care of yourself.
Fio! What are you doing?
I'm going, too. Wait for five minutes, please!
I want to prepare my seat.
Give me a break!
Do you understand what you are saying?
Shh... Don't talk so loud.
Fio.
Look. You are the daughter of a decent man.
Besides, you are not married yet.
Would you hold this for a moment?
Thank you. I made this in a hurry, look!
This really fits.
Would you hold that?
Hey, Miss. I'm a wanted
bounty hunter by the government.
I'm not going to be playing with this plane.
I'm sorry
but I have responsibility for this plane.
But, I'm going to take off from the canal
in the back.
And I'm not even sure
if I can fly without any problems.
And, when you're going to fight Curtis
you'll need me as an excellent engineer.
Hey, I'm a man, you know.
We are going to be
camping alone on a deserted island.
I don't care,
I like camping very much.
I'm not talking about THAT.
Take her with you.
I want you to win and pay the debt.
You've got to beat Curtis.
My company may go bankrupt
if you don't pay it.
Are you really
this girl's grandfather?
You don't have to pay her any money.
I'm going to install this phone for you two.
You really want her to
be wanted by the police.
No. I'm going to be Porco's hostage.
That way they can excuse
their cooperation with you.
So, please, take me with you.
Take off the machine gun on the right side.
What?
There's almost no space
even if you got a small butt.
Take off one machine gun!
Whoa! Thanks!
My butt is bigger than it looks.
It will be just a minute
for me to take the gun off.
I want to take off as soon as possible.
Before someone else wants
to come with me as well.
You're too fat for someone else
to fit in your plane.
Grandma, hurry, hurry.
Fio. Bring me back a souvenir.
Contact.
Open the door!
Let it go!
Come back with money!
How is the steering, Porco?
This is kind of like a tomboy,
just like you.
Stop the plane at once!
We need to make adjustments!
We don't have the time to do it.
Just do your job!
It's wet with water.
There a ship up ahead!
Let's fly!
Easy, easy, tomboy!
The turning wing is shifting to the right.
Use the tab!
The tab?
The one I put on the stick!
Hurry!
Good. It became a nice boy all of a sudden.
Beautiful.
How beautiful the world is!
Is he attacking us?
No. He is not attacking.
That's a parade plane of the
Italian Air Force.
Looks like it's Fierrali...
Do you know him?
The Air Force waits up ahead.
He says he'll tell us how to escape them.
He also says that
we should fly low to the Adriatic Sea.
Thanks, comrade!
Thank you!
He said, "don't cast pearls before a swine",
looking at you, Fio.