© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous
Mr. Raccoon, Mr. Raccoon,
Come on out and play
Some other time
I'm having dinner now
What are you eating?
Pickled plums and radish
Can you give me some?
Don '2' be such a greedy bum
Gel' your own!
POM POKO
We used to live near a farmhouse.
But not to steal their food.
In the farms and fields...
there are always frogs,
grasshoppers, mice, moles...
persimmons and mulberries.
Much more food than
in the mountains.
Then suddenly last spring
the humans went away.
They didn't come back,
so we decided to move in.
That was such a wonderful year.
A house with a garden,
it was like a dream!
But then...
We usually don't have strict
rules about territory.
But this was different.
Wherever we went for food,
we came up against others.
There were fights
and our territory was invaded.
And finally...
Pom Poke Year 31, autumn.
In the clear-cut forest
of Taka near Suzu...
the raccoons of the Tama Hills
faced their final battle.
Gonta the Brave led the Taka forces.
Seizaemon the Elder
led the raccoons from Suzu.
It's a little-known fact,
but when humans aren't around...
raccoons stand and walk
on two legs, just like this.
The battle was fierce
but it didn't last long.
Fight, fight! Taka!
Fight, fight! Suzu!
Taka win! Suzu win!
Both of you lose.
Let the losers be killed.
Taka's forest is gone today.
Suzu's will be gone tomorrow.
Too many raccoons,
no place to live.
where will they go?
There's no place to go.
You're all finished.
Taka win! Suzu win!
Both of you lose.
Let the losers be killed.
Let the losers die
for the sake of all.
It will be a blessing!
The fewer the better.
You survivors, take care!
Have no more babies.
Or there won't be
enough forest to hold them.
Urged on by Granny Oroku...
the raccoons looked and
were stunned by what they saw.
The hills had vanished...
and the earth
had been stripped bare.
The land was empty and cold.
It's insane!
This is no time for fighting!
In the 1960s,
Japan's economy was booming.
Demand for housing
near Tokyo skyrocketed.
Construction spread to the hills
and farmland surrounding the city.
The biggest housing development
was called Tama New Town.
30,000 acres would be developed
for 300,000 people.
Mountains were deforested,
stripped and leveled.
Farms were bulldozed,
old houses were demolished.
The Tama Hills became a
residential development.
The forested hills became
a sprawling suburban community.
It was the largest urban
development project ever.
Those humans are truly amazing.
I always believed
they were animals just like us.
But now I think humans
must be as powerful as gods.
There was no time to lose.
The raccoons gathered
from all over the Tama Hills...
for a midnight meeting
in the abandoned temple of Manpukuji.
Tsurukame the priest was 105.
He was the chairman of the meeting.
Given this dire situation...
we must give up our
nocturnal habits...
and be ready for action
during the daytime.
Their plan was to try
to stop the development.
Then it's unanimous!
The meeting broke up at once.
All decisions would be
made by the council of elders.
They announced a 5-year plan
to study the humans...
and revive the ancient art
of transformation.
Messengers would be sent
to far-off Shikoku and Sade...
to seek help from
famous Transformation Masters.
But the journeys
would be perilous.
Nobody volunteered to go.
They all pretended to be asleep.
I suppose we'll just have to
leave it to the younger raccoons.
Agreed!
Getting down to business...
they proceeded to research
McDonald's hamburgers.
The meeting ended
with everyone well satisfied.
NO DUMPING
They decided that an old TV
would be the best way...
to collect in-depth
information on humans.
Good evening.
Good evening!
The TV aroused great interest.
Raccoons started to hang out
at headquarters...
just to watch the TV all day.
Transformation requires extreme
physical and mental discipline.
Truly, shape-shifting
is the greatest miracle.
Less-skilled animals like chameleons
use mimicry.
Only raccoons, foxes and
a few cats can transform themselves.
Gonta!
See how you did that?
You already have
the gift of transformation.
It's quite easy once
you get the hang of it.
At least in theory.
I'll give you a demonstration.
Don't you need a big leaf?
That's only for beginners.
It's been a while.
With Granny Oroku
as their teacher...
transformation training
proceeded rapidly.
All the youngsters were eager
to practice their new skill.
Excellent, Shokichi!
I've always been
interested in humans.
We're not supposed to get
too close to them...
but my dear departed father
never stopped me.
Detailed knowledge of humans
is the key to transformation.
Dad knew it would be
useful for my future.
Of course, some students
lagged behind.
In fact, many were just hopeless.
The key to transformation is
extreme discipline of mind and body.
Foxes work hard at it,
but raccoons are easily distracted.
Some of them played hooky.
Hey!
Ponkichi!
Ready, set,
let's all transform!
My friend Ponkichi never got
the hang of transformation.
He just wanted to be
an ordinary raccoon.
A human looked up
at the evening sky...
and saw the moon
rising over the mountains.
Then a tree branch
blocked the moon.
The human said, “That's strange.
There was no branch before.”
The branch disappeared and
stuck out on the other side.
The human saw this and said...
“Wait! There were
branches on both sides.”
So a branch stuck out
on the other side too.
Then boom, both branches fell.
What really fell?
A raccoon!
Yes! And why did he fall?
Gonta?
Because he was stupid.
I would never fall.
Good. That's the spirit.
Sasuke, why did he fall?
He lost hold of the tree.
Very good. And what
does this teach us? Shokichi?
That you shouldn't believe
everything humans say.
Right.
We raccoons are too trusting.
It's easy for humans to fool us.
Then we get into trouble.
Does everyone understand?
Yes, Tsurukame.
Now, what if I start singing?
Raccoon, raccoon
Come on out and play.
We're in the middle of a lesson!
See? You fell for it.
That's what I was afraid of.
The raccoons were still
hard at work when spring arrived.
Flowers were blooming.
It was the season for love.
Following Granny Oroku's warning...
many of the raccoons
abstained from mating...
to keep the population
under control.
Especially the females.
They controlled their maternal
instincts with firm willpower...
rejecting the lovesick
advances of the males.
Meanwhile, work continued
on the massive development.
More forest disappeared,
more land was cleared for housing.
The raccoons were sad and angry.
They called the site “the bald hills”.
Mr. Mailman, you dropped something.
The females, who were just
as independent as the males...
were also just as skilled
at transformation.
When males transformed into girls,
it sometimes looked unnatural...
so the females coached them.
Some females also
transformed into men.
Class is over, but I want
the boys to stay here.
One day Tsurukame
gave the males a special lecture.
Boys, there's something special
about the mat you're sitting on.
I won't beat around the bush.
It's my testicles!
150 square feet.
Here's your proof.
After basic training,
the students went into the field.
It's like learning to drive.
You need someone experienced
to come with you...
and back you up
if you get in a tight spot.
The art of transformation
requires a great deal of energy...
especially when transforming
into humans.
The dark circles around raccoons' eyes...
are from sheer fatigue.
Even experienced transformers...
...need an emergency energy boost
every now and then.
Too much fatigue might mean
changing back into a raccoon.
Recently, fast-acting energy drinks
have become very popular.
To graduate from field training...
each student had to work
as a human and earn 1,000 yen.
I'm beat!
Some raccoons pretended
to be one worker.
Others posed as monks
begging for alms.
A few females worked in bars
to earn money for energy drinks.
One even tried his
luck at pachinko.
One broke into
a temple donation box.
But all he got was a few coins.
Granny Oroku saw right through him.
I told you,
never turn leaves into money!
An urgent report interrupted
Gonta's training at headquarters.
He rushed to the Taka Forest
and was shocked by what he saw.
Developers had turned
his homeland into bald hills.
Furious, he rushed back
to headquarters.
He called a meeting
of the council...
and demanded total war
against the humans.
I'm against it.
Why?
It's too soon.
You need more experience.
We finished our training.
We can do great things.
What do you think, Granny?
Are they up to it?
They certainly have the basic skills.
But...?
They lack experience.
The humans might see through them.
We need to know, Gonta.
Why are you proposing this?
Is it because of what happened
to your home forest?
Is that it?
No, I swear. It's for the happiness
of all the raccoons in Tama.
What a lot of nonsense.
It was you who tried
to take over Suzu forest.
Shut up!
Even if you won't join me...
the Taka raccoons will fight.
If Gonta's going,
then I'm going too.
You Will, Shokichi?
Thanks!
All right men,
there's no turning back now!
Wait!
You can't stop us, Granny.
I'd better teach you
a special skill for emergencies.
If the humans see through you,
this disguise will last for five days.
Well, what is it?
A dead fox.
Pom Poke '(ear 32, summer.
Gonta and a band
of brave followers...
set out to test
their new transformation skills...
in a surprise attack
on the humans.
Their counterattack had finally started.
Here they come!
This way! This way!
We did it!
This afternoon, at the
Tama New Town site...
five more workers
were killed or injured...
in a landslide and accident
involving a trailer.
One building under construction
was completely destroyed.
Heavy rains and poor visibility
were blamed for the accident.
Because so many accidents
have occurred simultaneously...
questions are being asked
about the project's overall management.
Local residents are concerned...
and some are demanding that
the development be cancelled.
Hold on there!
The humans who died
were victims of this war.
First we should pay our respects
to the memories of those who died.
Tsurukame is right.
Let's have a minute
of silence for the victims.
Hurray!
Minute of silence!
Let us remember.
- We won! We won!
- Let's celebrate! A big party!
Gonta's back!
The heroes have returned.
You did great, Shokichi.
You young people
give us hope for the future.
And we're just getting started.
Listen up!
Everyone must join the fight.
We'll kill them! Destroy them!
Run them out of these hills forever!
Say something, Shokichi.
Then we'll plant lots of
our favorite persimmon trees.
Hurry, persimmon seed,
sprout' a free
If you don't, I'll chop you up
Out with the humans!
Kill them! Destroy them!
All right, that's enough war talk.
Let's just celebrate, shall we?
I'm a little worried about something.
What?
Do we have to drive out
every human?
Of course!
Can't we let a few stay?
Like before?
No! They're our sworn enemies!
They're monsters!
We have to exterminate them!
Are you sure?
Of course, I hate them too.
Some of them are all right.
No, I hate them all!
But...
But what?
If they all go away,
we'll never eat tempura again.
Or sardines...
Or corn...
Hamburgers! Donuts! Fried chicken!
Potato chips! Turkey!
I can almost taste them!
Well Gonta, what if we let
a few humans stay?
It can't be helped.
Let's hear it
for Gonta and his men!
In the garden of Manpukuji Temple
The moon shines bright.
Everyone come out. Come out.
Hurry, hurry, all our friends.
Tsurukame, come out!
Everybody look at Granny!
You gotta get a look!
Everyone's gotta get a look!
The government has declared that
the needs of a growing population...
are too urgent to even consider
cancelling the New Town project.
- Hey!
- What did he say?
It was an unfortunate accident.
Brave Gonta suffered compound
fractures and ruptured organs.
He would be sidelined
for at least a year.
The news report cast a pall
of gloom over the celebrations.
But the humans' fear
of divine retribution...
gave the raccoons a new idea.
Maybe it was a mistake
to tear down those shrines.
What do you mean?
Maybe the guardian spirits
are punishing us with these accidents.
I hear you had to relocate
many of the shrine statues.
Of course we made offerings
to the spirits...
...and held purification rites first.
What do you think, Professor?
Each locality has its own
guardian gods and spirits.
Altering the landscape
without their permission...
will naturally invite their anger.
I think there is a lo!
more bad luck f0 come.
I have an idea.
The raccoons promptly put
Shokichi's idea to the test.
When one of the land owners
checked his property before selling...
he found more guardian statues
than he was expecting.
He decided it might be better
to delay the contract.
The purification rite at a shrine
that was about to be relocated...
was interrupted by a raccoon
posing as the shrine guardian.
He appeared on the roof.
Terrified by the fox's wailing,
the humans panicked...
and the relocation was cancelled.
Instead, the residents requested
that the new road be diverted.
Now the raccoons were fired up.
They competed with each other
to use their transformation skills...
in this new guerrilla war.
Come this way.
Leave our forest alone.
Take it with you.
Let's pack the leftovers.
Wait!
Leave the food.
ls something wrong, miss?
What's the matter?
I have no face.
A goblin!
L...I just saw...
A murder?
No.
Not a murder? Oh, well.
It was a woman.
A vampire?
No, she was...
Did she look something like this?
Did she...
look something like this?
It was such fun
scaring the humans...
that they decided
to have another party.
But the hero of the first battles
was disappointed that his injuries...
were not healing quickly.
His wife nursed him well,
but he was not ready to fight.
He thought the others
were losing their aggressive spirit.
Last night's news was great!
“Goblins appear in New Town.”
That cop was on the show.
Everyone laughed at him.
He lost his temper.
I laughed myself sick.
Idiots! Do you think
this will stop the project?
If you're going to transform,
do what I did.
Kill the humans!
Just as Gonta predicted,
the construction didn't stop.
Rivers were lined
with concrete.
Roads were cut
through the bald hills.
Housing construction
was already under way.
However, the mysterious incidents
received so much media coverage...
that the New Town goblins
were famous all over the country.
The raccoons' spirits rose
higher and higher.
Pom Poke Year 32, autumn.
The raccoons competed
for the honor...
of going in search
of the Transformation Masters.
Tamasaburo was chosen
to journey to Shikoku.
Bunta would go to Sado.
At the next full moon...
the two young raccoons
set off on their long journeys...
after a tearful farewell.
The others settled down
to wait for the Masters...
while they continued
to haunt New Town.
Even if it didn't stop
the development...
it was their favorite sport.
Daddy!
Can we really chase the humans
away with these cheap tricks?
What if we slip up
and they see through us?
Should we fight like Gonta says?
No, killing one or two humans
won't make any difference.
To go on or not to go on.
That is the question.
KW o'?
What are you doing?
Does your neck hurt?
I was posing. I thought you
might say I was pretty.
Oh, sorry.
Now my neck really does hurt.
You looked pretty.
Too late.
But I mean it.
It's okay.
I'm out of practice anyway.
Everyone likes that song.
I guess I do too.
How about “Where Are You From?”
Nobody sings that now.
That song...
A raccoon was on Senba Mountain
Along came a hunter..
A hunter killed my grandpa.
Sorry, I didn't know.
It's okay.
But they didn't eat him,
like in the song.
They sold his pelt
for a lot of money.
Your pelt's pretty too.
I was hoping you'd say that.
What about that song?
My dad used to sing it.
He was a good ball bouncer too.
He must have been a character.
And when he finished singing,
he would always start preaching.
What did he say?
“Listen well, children.”
“Like the song says...”
“they kill us, cook us
and eat us.”
“Humans are cruel by nature.
That's what the song says.”
Hey, let's play ball.
Are you good?
Sure am.
Now it's my turn.
Where are you from?
From Higo... Where's Higo?
From Kumamoto... Where's Kumamoto?
From Senba... Where the mountains
are full of raccoons.
When are you going out
on that raid you talked about?
I'm getting tired of that stuff.
But I liked your idea.
Really?
Why don't we do it tonight?
Together?
Are you afraid?
No, it's not that, but...
Then let's do it.
It'll go just fine.
Okay, you're on.
With you, I'm sure it'll go great.
I'm so happy!
My, what adorable little children.
We just got back from the stars,
but now our house is gone.
The stars?
From the red-eyed Scorpion,
we crossed over the Eagle's wings.
We looped the coiled Snake,
to the top of the Bear Cub's brow.
We scatter dew and frost
as we travel through the stars.
Who are you two, anyway?
We're lost and we're cold!
Mister, do you know
the way home?
We don't know
what you're talking about.
We don't know.
Now go away!
Better call the cops.
They're not kids. They're gremlins!
Forgive us!
Forgive us, little gremlins.
Wait a minute.
We can work this out.
Come on,
I'll raise your pay.
I'm going home.
I can't take it any more.
This place gives me
the creeps.
Come on, don't say that.
I heard Tokyo
was a scary place...
but this is too much.
You better forget
this whole project.
Something doesn't want it to happen.
The raccoons cheered.
That night's party was
especially grand.
The heroes of the evening
were Kiyo and Shokichi.
The construction site
was quiet and deserted.
But next morning...
More humans showed up
to continue the work.
Despite the raccoons' hard work...
there seemed to be
an unlimited supply of humans.
Some say these strange events
are the work of foxes or raccoons.
If that were true, all we'd need
to do is kill a few animals.
This made the raccoons at
headquarters very nervous.
But it's just like the old folktales.
No wonder rumors are spreading.
Whoever is spreading them
must want the project to fail.
Rumors?
We saw it with our own eyes!
Very well. We'll just have to get rid
of these dangerous animals.
Just let us know when you catch them.
That is, if you can prove they did it.
It was starting to look as if
transformation wouldn't be enough.
Long ago, there was
a golden age of raccoons.
The art of metamorphosis
was at its peak.
Raccoons were a favorite subject
for artists and writers.
But we abused our powers.
The humans turned against us.
As Japan modernized,
we were trapped by the thousands.
Our pelts became
brushes and fur collars.
This was their revenge,
but we brought it on ourselves.
You must learn from this
terrible experience.
Remember that we have
been able to live in peace...
only because we stopped
using our powers recklessly.
Transformation is a great gift.
But if used carelessly...
it will only rekindle
the humans' desire for revenge.
I urge you all to be careful.
The young transforming raccoons
were not sure what to do next.
But now it was autumn,
the best season for raccoons.
It was time to
store up fat for the winter...
and grow their
thick winter coats.
They forgot about transforming and
stuck to the job of getting food.
One day, an exhausted raccoon
arrived at the construction site.
It's okay, we're raccoons.
Thank you.
You look exhausted.
Where did you come from?
From Fujino Mountain.
Is that in Shikoku or Sado?
It's in Kanagawa,
just beyond those mountains.
Kanagawa? You mean
you're not from Shikoku?
I'm sorry, I seem
to have disappointed you somehow.
It's just that we've been
waiting for some visitors.
Anyway, what is it
that brought you here?
I was looking for the source
of the landfill...
they're dumping on our mountain.
According to this raccoon
named Hayashi...
dirt and construction
waste was being dumped...
in Fujino's forest.
The dumping was hurting
the environment...
and making survival hard
for raccoons and other animals.
To find the source
of this trouble...
Hayashi hitched a ride
on one of the dump trucks.
But his transforming skills
were rusty, and he fell asleep.
Before he arrived in Tama,
he changed back into a raccoon.
It's not just Fujino,
it's other places too.
They keep building
dump sites and golf courses.
They destroy our hills
and cause us trouble.
Then they dump the waste in
Fujino, and cause you trouble.
How far will this insanity go?
When I arrived here
I couldn't believe it.
I thought for sure the waste
was coming from the big city.
But this isn't the city!
They level one mountain
and dump it on another.
What in the world for?
I don't understand it one bit.
Then if we stop the development...
the Fujino raccoons will be better off too.
I'm so grateful to hear you say that!
Please use all your power...
to help save our homeland
as well as your own.
We'd like to, but unfortunately
it's easier said than done.
What happened to Bunta
and Tamasaburo, anyway?
When in the world
are they coming back?
There was still no sign
of the Transformation Masters.
Now it was winter.
During the raccoons' winter rest...
the humans forgot the
“New Town Goblins”...
and people's attention
shifted elsewhere.
The media was busy with
the private lives of movie stars...
and political corruption scandals.
In the garden of Manpukuji Temple.
Raining, raining cotton candy,
ice cream, snow cones!
All our friends, Pom Poko, Pom!
Pom Poke '(ear 33.
New Year's morning brought a
fresh blanket of snow.
Most of the construction workers
had gone home for the holidays...
and were enjoying long-awaited
family reunions.
Our golden bells s Wing and s wing,
though there '.s not a breath of Wind.
Baby raccoon sees our swinging balls
and swings his too.
We really saw them.
A bunch of raccoons did it.
It's the truth!
Three workers at the
Tama New Town construction site...
were arrested
for destroying a bulldozer.
They maintain
that raccoons did it.
Investigations are under way,
but the snow has already melted.
Look what you've done now,
Shokichi.
It's no big deal.
The whole thing's pointless.
He was just trying to
help the others participate.
What do you think, Tsurukame?
I think it Will be okay.
Tsurukame was right.
The workers were released
for lack of evidence.
The raccoons weren't blamed.
The case remained a mystery.
Spring came at last.
Once again, the season for love.
The raccoons had been
chaste for over a year.
Now they couldn't resist.
Courtship rivalries and
sweet nothings filled the air.
Even the sky was rose-colored.
Wait up, Hanako!
Hanako, wait!
You can't catch me!
Everyone has spring fever.
We're just like trees and flowers.
When spring comes, the sun shines.
Our flowers blossom...
and we bear fruit.
But we must obey Granny's orders.
Until our battle is won,
we will be chaste.
Shokichi, you really are
a wonderful raccoon.
I'm so glad.
Our love is forever.
Shokichi!
That was their big mistake.
Their love grew passionate.
And sure enough,
they ended up like the others.
That spring, Shokichi and Kiyo
had four baby raccoons.
The previous autumn,
Tamasaburo had finally reached Shikoku.
He went to Kincho Shrine,
home of the Masters...
to explain the problem
and appeal for their help.
But then he fell ill.
Koharu, the Master's daughter,
cared for him...
and he recovered miraculously.
That spring the two fell in
love and had three babies.
In the shrine, the Masters
of Shikoku debated endlessly.
They agreed that it was
important for all of Japan...
to stop the New Town project.
They had to act quickly.
But who would go, and who
would stay to guard the shrine?
Hundreds of questions were raised
and discussed from every angle...
but no conclusions were reached.
Another summit meeting.
They never seem to end.
And on such a lovely day.
The year is half gone already.
When will they reach a decision?
I never want them to decide!
When I think of you leaving us
to go back to Tama...
I feel so lonely that
I'm sure my heart will break.
Koharu, I don't want
this happiness to end either.
Then why don't you stay?
I'm going to ask Father.
I want you to stay here
and become his successor.
While Tamasaburo was absorbed
in the trials of youth...
Bunta, who had journeyed to Sado,
roamed the fields and mountains...
searching for a Master
called Danzaburo.
He searched high and low...
but no one he met
had heard of the master.
From summer to autumn, the
raccoons faced a serious dilemma.
Not only was their
forest disappearing...
but the population multiplied
with a spring baby boom.
Bad weather caused
an extreme shortage of food.
Persimmons, nuts and other
autumn fruits were scarce.
Transforming raccoons managed to
get food from the humans...
but it wasn't enough to feed
all the babies.
Even the non-transforming
raccoons were forced...
to scavenge food from the humans.
Some of the careless ones
were hit by cars or caught in traps.
Many lives were lost.
I've had enough!
It's time to confront the humans.
Right, Shokichi?
Are you sure you're all right,
Gonta?
Of course! Watch this!
This calls for a celebration!
When's the party?
Granny, this is
no time for a party.
I think we should wait until
the Masters get here.
You too, Shokichi?
I'm sick of you wimps.
We mustn't underestimate the humans.
If we attack now,
we're sure to lose.
We've already waited too long!
Hold on.
Let's hear Shokichi's opinion.
Until the Masters arrive,
I have three proposals.
First, equal distribution of food
to raccoons who can't transform.
We should make it a system.
Second, a traffic safety training program.
Third, a rescue squad for
anyone who gets caught in a trap.
Shokichi, you sound
just like a human.
No, I'm a full-blooded raccoon.
Okay, we'll worry about details later.
For now, let's see who agrees.
Hands up!
Agreed!
What is this, Gonta?
Shut up! It's a coup.
Anyone who stands in our way
will be killed by my guards.
Those are dangerous words, Gonta.
That's “Gonta, Sir!”
Hear me out!
The humans are strong indeed.
But not invincible.
We can kill them!
As the saying goes,
“A cornered mouse will bite the cat.”
A mouse? How?
It's silly.
We'll stake everything on victory.
Right. If it fears nothing,
even a mouse can win.
We're not mice.
Biting a cat won't help us.
You know, a mouse would
taste good right about now.
Mouse tempura is the best.
No, fried mouse nuggets
are tops.
I like 'em breaded
and deep fried.
Those crispy fried tails!
What are you talking about?
All I can say is...
Mouse tempura is my favorite.
Listen, Gonta.
As you see, we're not ready.
We'd better just wait
for the Masters from Shikoku.
I'm sorry.
Just be careful
not to have any more babies.
But I guess that's too much
to expect from us raccoons.
No! Instead of fewer raccoons,
we need fewer humans!
All the places they've infested
used to be our homes.
They're intruders!
Drive them out.
Kill them!
Drive them out!
Meanwhile...
Hey, Taxi!
I'll tell them we're here.
Tamasaburo!
I've brought the
Masters from Shikoku.
Well done, Tamasaburo!
Friends! On the way here, we saw
your devastated mountains.
You have our deepest sympathy.
We would like to hold
a general meeting tonight.
Pom Poke Year 33, autumn.
That evening, the raccoons assembled
to listen to the Masters.
There's a good moon out tonight.
My name is Hage of Yashima.
Soon I will celebrate
my 999th birthday.
Why is Tama being developed
but Shikoku is not?
It is because we have protected
our homeland vigilantly.
In Shikoku, the humans know well
that if they anger us raccoons...
great misfortune will befall them.
The humans worship me
and my distinguished companions...
at every temple
and shrine in Shikoku.
They bow down before us.
Allow me to
introduce myself.
I am the Supreme Leader of Shikoku.
My name is lnugami Gyobu.
I am Kincho VI,
lord of Kincho Shrine.
We shall drive out the humans...
by uniting our powers
for a goblin attack.
This battle will require us...
to merge our spirits
into one powerful force.
We three may not even
survive this battle.
However, if you complete this
operation flawlessly...
you will regain the respect
the humans once had for you.
We must be fearless.
If we focus our combined strength...
we can stop this insane development.
Stop it in its tracks!
We have a full arsenal of tricks.
We have built a great boat.
An unsinkable boat!
A boat that will carry us far.
Board our boat
and find peace of mind.
What a beautiful summer moon.
We like full moons.
Let us pray to this moon
for success.
Shall we?
The raccoons began intense
training for Operation Goblin.
Congratulations on your 999th birthday!
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Master, please perform that scene
from the Battle of Yashima!
Of course, why not.
The time is ripe.
Pom Poke Year 33.
Year's end.
Operation Goblin was about to begin.
Slightly cloudy, no wind.
Cool but not cold, humidity 65%.
A perfect day for goblins.
From ancient times, raccoons
have been skilled at transformation.
But this time was different.
Not only their energy...
but the energy of the cosmos
itself had to be harnessed...
to guarantee the success
of Operation Goblin.
Accumulating and channeling
that energy was vital.
Under the direction
of the Three Masters...
the raccoons generated
an indescribable amount of power.
Males, females,
skilled and unskilled alike...
all contributed their energy.
That evening, the raccoons united...
to use their full strength as
it had never been seen before.
Hey look!
What's that?
Let the trees blossom
in the middle of winter!
Wow, a big parade of goblins!
I used to see those sorts of things.
Like a parade of foxes.
I know, I saw them too.
With little lanterns and everything.
And the lanterns
would go marching along.
I wonder what
that was all about?
Can foxes really do that?
It sure seems like they can.
I mean, you can see them.
It's just nerves.
All this talk about goblins.
All those old stories about
foxes and lanterns.
It's all in your head.
You just think
you saw them marching.
Your mind plays tricks.
Of course.
It's foolish to believe it.
The human mind
is a frightening thing.
You're sure they're real.
But they can't be real.
Those are real.
They're all in your mind.
Welcome home.
Sachiko!
I summon the six elements!
Form is emptiness!
Master Gyobu!
That was scary.
Aw, is it over already?
That was so cool!
It's time for bed.
All right.
And brush your teeth.
I feel like I was dreaming.
Me too.
What could that have been?
Maybe UFOs are real too.
Strange things really do happen.
Long ago, when the
Matsuyama Clan was at war...
Gyobu defected to the enemy,
causing the downfall of his clan.
He regretted it so deeply,
that he made a solemn vow...
to fight for justice.
His death must not be in vain.
Let us carry on his noble ideals.
We will fight to the end,
until the day of triumph.
Ga-te ga-te para-ga-te
Raccoons of the Sweetcake Hills
Victory is ours!
We drink lots of sake and transform.
Operation Goblin
was a big success!
But with all the excitement,
they forgot to monitor the news.
We're looking for video
of this mysterious parade.
No one has come forward yet.
Investigators are perplexed.
I shot all that video,
but none of it came out.
This is really weird.
The goblin slipped in through
here and it was terrifying!
Nobody could have faked that.
Something fishy
is going on in New Town.
I wish I could move, but...
At 12:20 tonight, we will bring
you a special program...
with in-depth coverage
of this mystery.
As the humans investigate
what happened...
they will realize that
this wasn't their imagination.
They'll be face to face
with reality.
Then, when they realize
that their science and logic...
are powerless to unlock the riddle...
They will be dumbfounded
by the mystery of the cosmos...
and realize how insignificant
humanity really is.
Good fortune awaits us,
but let's not wait for it.
Let's wake it up. Let's celebrate!
Drink up! Sing! Dance!
But the next day...
things took an unexpected turn.
Last night's unauthorized
parade in Tama New Town...
was a publicity stunt for Wonderland
theme park, now under construction.
The police investigation is ongoing.
Nonsense!
However, local residents confirm that
it didn't look like a publicity event.
Of course not!
The president of Wonderland
confessed to last night's stunt.
What?
I would like to apologize to the
public for this disturbance.
He's crazy!
We are still working on the
construction of Wonderland.
But to let everyone know what
a splendid park we're building...
we decided to provide
some free entertainment.
As president of the park,
I ordered the surprise parade.
- Liar!
- What's he talking about!
Fortunately, we've received
an enormous outpouring...
of enthusiastic praise
and support from the public.
We are overwhelmed
at the enormous response.
If they must lock me up for this...
I'm prepared to pay the price.
- What the...
- Why?
Something is very wrong here!
If they must lock me up for this...
That fool!
The news threw the raccoons
into a panic.
Meanwhile, Wonderland's boss searched
for the parade's organizers.
Just find them.
I want the organizers.
I don't care what it takes.
I'll pay them whatever they ask.
As much as it takes!
It was raccoons.
What? Then get me a raccoon!
Any raccoon.
Contact their manager!
Raccoons? What did you say?
I was only joking.
Who are you?
How did you get in here?
Your secretary. I phoned earlier.
My name's Ryutaro.
You seem to be in a tight spot.
But only I can contact the people
who staged that parade.
All right, I'll give you
a million dollars.
While this mysterious stranger
explained his proposal...
the raccoons were enraged that
their glory had been stolen.
They cried with resentment
and sank into helplessness.
And since there was no video
of the goblin parade...
media coverage tapered off.
You're a fox, aren't you?
Precisely. I'm Ryutaro,
transforming fox of Tama.
I've heard many tales of
the Great Kincho from Shikoku.
This is an honor.
My ancestors were far greater than I.
So tell me, why are you here?
I was deeply moved by
your fabulous parade.
You knew it was us?
Indeed. And I understand your
despair and discouragement.
I see, I suppose as a fox
you would understand.
And I knew things
would turn out this way.
You did?
Ryutaro invited Kincho
to join him in Ginza...
in a private room at a
certain well-known club.
Welcome!
Don't worry, all these
ladies are foxes.
Would you
prefer them as foxes?
Or shall I have them
change into raccoons?
Let's be frank.
Raccoons have no future in Tama.
The foxes already died out.
The foxes died out already?
Yes. It's a pity.
Now only a few of us...
survive as humans, like this.
Humans?
It's the key to survival
in the big city.
I invited you here to persuade
you raccoons to do likewise.
Just a moment!
I understand your shock.
But times like these...
call for drastic measures.
You must bear the unbearable.
Your only hope for survival
is to get jobs at Wonderland.
What, and go to work
for our enemy?
Let's think calmly. At this point
raccoons have no choice.
That much is given.
Living as a human fakes big money.
Ano' how do you earn a living?
You use the talents you have.
The question is which job
would pay the best money.
Unfortunately Wonderland
pays the best rates.
And the benefits are considerable.
This is the salary...
and these are the benefits.
Of course, only I will know
that you're raccoons.
Bon appétit.
Let's think about it over dinner.
Enjoy the food, Master Kincho.
You must be tired of scraps
from the garbage in Tama.
That's not important.
I have one question.
If we must live as humans, what
about those who can't transform?
They have to
fend for themselves.
At least the strongest
ones will survive.
We too had to abandon
our weaker members.
And they... perished.
Yes. It was a
heart-wrenching decision.
What a tragedy!
But you raccoons are lucky.
You can eat just about anything.
I wouldn't worry too much.
In Kincho's absence...
the Tama raccoons gathered
to decide what to do next.
But only a handful showed up.
They talked big
but they didn't deliver.
We never should have
waited for them.
I say, “Don't sell the pelt
until you've skinned the raccoon.”
Not even Buddha could help us.
We must not blame the Masters.
“Tricky like a raccoon.”
That's what humans call someone
like the president of Wonderland.
You talk about humans
too much, Shokichi!
I'm just trying to learn
more about them.
Shut up!
We must kill all the humans!
Control yourself, Gonta.
Our only choice
is to tell the humans...
that Operation Goblin
was the work of us raccoons.
Have you lost your mind?
That's just what we mustn't do.
She's right. If they find out,
they'll come after us.
But it's so tragic.
That parade was a work of art.
Why can't we take the credit?
I can't bear this.
I want to shout it out!
We are the ones who did it!
But Tsurukame...
how would we get them
to believe us?
We should make
a public declaration.
Call the TV stations
or send letters.
They'll probably think
it's just a prank.
Then we'll go on TV and show
them our transformations.
That's ridiculous.
They'll say it's just a trick
and we'll be humiliated.
This is a waste of time.
This much was true.
The debate went back and forth,
and on into the night.
This whole discussion
is a waste of time.
But if we turn terrorist,
the humans will kill us all.
That's why we shouldn't
reveal our secret.
Then there's not much
we can do.
Our only hope
is to stick together.
We've got to try again.
We've got to launch
Operation Goblin 2.
What's the point?
It'll fail the same way.
We'll perfect a new plan
and a new strategy.
You just don't want to do anything.
You're like some stinking girl.
Watch your language, Gonta.
Girls don't stink.
Well if they did,
he'd be one.
I'm going to get ready
for Operation Goblin 2.
And who will follow you?
Who's going to follow you?
You watch your mouth!
Knock it off.
Listen everyone!
There's only one way for us
to avoid conflict...
and it requires the use
of our special talents.
Our powers overwhelmed the
humans in Operation Goblin.
But unfortunately, they thought it was
the work of men with inhuman talents.
Then what should we do?
We have to be creative.
Like Columbus
and his famous boiled egg.
- Wow! That's great!
- Bravo!
Is your plan that creative?
From now on, we will live as
inhuman humans.
You must be joking.
No, this is no joke.
But what about the others?
Where did Tsurukame go?
APPEAL FROM THE RACCOONS
While Tsurukame was absent
from the meeting...
Kincho's plan was rejected.
Raccoon solidarity started to unravel.
Most of the raccoons
went back to gathering food.
Hard-line Gonta went around
recruiting troops for his battle.
Master Hage gathered the
non-transforming raccoons...
and gave them faith
with a new dancing religion.
These are chaotic times.
All we can do is dance.
Save us, merciful Buddha.
Look what has become of
venerable Hage.
Tokyo is such a frightening place.
In Shikoku, a parade like that
would have an instant impact.
Offerings at our shrine would
go up five... no, ten times!
Master Kincho, take me back
to Shikoku with you...
to continue my training.
I can't wait any longer.
Really, Tamasaburo?
Yes.
You're ready to be my successor?
Yes, Master Kincho.
I'm relieved to hear that.
But I have to ask you.
You're not the kind of raccoon...
who would abandon
your comrades, are you?
Of course not. But...
But what?
You've lost everyone's support.
What can we possibly do?
We're not finished yet.
I'll show you.
This is quite a fancy restaurant.
We spared no expense
to please you.
This is astounding.
We'll be bigger than Disneyland!
To get revenge on the president...
Kincho and the raccoons
ruined his deal with Ryutaro.
The president told the police...
that raccoons had stolen
a million dollars from him.
But they wouldn't listen.
That same day, Gonta's army
began their operations...
to stop the next phase
of development.
Attention eco-terrorists!
Stop interfering with development
and leave these woods at once.
You could be arrested for theft...
possession of dangerous weapons
and illegal trespassing.
If you fail to evacuate immediately,
we will use force to remove you.
Gonta's troops had the police
and workers completely blocked.
They refused to budge.
By nightfall, both sides
were still holding their positions.
If we can't stop Gonta, we have
no choice but to help him.
The riot police are already there.
It's too late.
I'll check it out.
- Stop! You'll be caught!
- We're going too!
Everyone ready?
In the spirit of honor,
if we are sacrificed in battle...
our brother raccoons
will continue to fight...
with undying determination
until our day of victory.
Our raccoon balls
Sway in the wind
Back and forth
To and fro
Amen.
Special orders! Stand aside!
Gonta, wait!
Let's go!
Gonta...
They used their balls
in a last-ditch attack.
Mr. Raccoon, Mr. Raccoon.
Just then, in another part
of the forest...
a TV crew was searching
for the raccoons.
Won't you please come out?
You can transform
or come as you are.
“World Telereporter” is on your side!
They seem quite reluctant.
Mr. Raccoon, Mr. Raccoon
Can we talk?
We have nothing to eat.
They answered!
The letter we received was genuine.
We want your side of the story.
Won't you come out?
Here they are!
It's the raccoons!
Are you really responsible
for the goblin parade?
Yes, we are.
We want our viewers
to believe you.
Won't you give us a demonstration
of your transforming talents?
Some of us raccoons
can't transform.
We need our forest to live.
Please, raccoons.
If you don't come out,
no one will believe you.
After all, you contacted us.
Please stand behind your words.
Tsurukame!
Please tell the humans
our side of things.
There's one! He transformed
into a raccoon statue!
Mr. Raccoon, a word
for our viewers.
We...We...
Yes?
Please go on.
We staged the parade!
This is our home!
Please don't take it away from us!
This is the wish
of all living things!
The people I saw yesterday
are gone today.
The people I see today
will be gone tomorrow.
Nobody knows
about the day after that.
But someday people will be sorry.
999 years ago, the Battle of Yashima...
was witnessed by Hage...
the venerable Master of raccoons.
He had seen enough.
He was ready to leave this world.
With a song of triumph,
they stretched his massive testicles...
into a treasure ship
adorned with lacquer and gold.
He filled it with treasure,
gold and jewels.
Buddha would carry them
from earth to heaven.
Singing and dancing,
the non-transforming raccoons...
boarded the ship for their journey
to the shores of bliss.
The treasure ship sailed
down the Tama River...
beneath the moon,
rocking and swaying.
The sail filled with wind
and they steered for the sea.
The river foamed beneath the prow.
The moon glinted off the water.
The treasure ship sailed on,
rocking under the moon.
It was like a dream,
with bells, flutes and drums.
Laden with raccoons,
gold, silver and coral...
the treasure ship
sailed away down the river.
Before it sank beneath the waves,
the others watched tearfully.
The ship entered the mist
like a dream on a night in spring.
As they looked up at the moon,
Buddha beckoned them to heaven.
And they crossed over
to the other world.
All the raccoons perished
on that journey of death.
A journey with no return,
a journey of death.
Poor raccoons,
on a journey of death.
We're no match
for the humans after all.
Bunta! Is that Bunta?
Tamasaburo!
- It's good to see you back!
- Sasuke! Shokichi!
What happened to the elder from
Sado? Master Danzaburo?
After searching all this time,
I found that 45 years ago...
he was shot by a hunter during
the famine after the war.
I see.
I was hoping to meet him.
Thanks for your hard work, Bunta.
Why is everything so different?
I've only been away three years.
We tried to stop them.
But nothing is the same.
Or have I gone crazy?
We know how you feel.
Was it the humans?
Yes, this is their work.
Impossible! Only raccoons could
be this tricky. Not humans.
Those humans cheated us.
They were raccoons after all.
Old, stinking raccoons!
Give us back our hills!
Give us back our fields!
Give us back our home!
Let's change it back.
Our final operation.
Make it the way it was.
Why not? We could hit
the humans with one last illusion.
Interesting. I can see
the old scenery already.
All right. One more try.
But, what would it prove
to do something like that now?
Nothing. But it will be amusing.
You're right.
A raccoon without a playful spirit...
is not a raccoon.
Will you help us too, Kincho?
Of course, if you don't mind
a little southern flair.
Ponkichi!
I'm here!
Let's gather everyone who's left.
Can we count on you too?
Naturally!
Hey, wait for me!
Oh, that looks like Mother.
It's Yotchan. Yotchan!
That's us when we were little!
Look, raccoons!
Gosh, they're so cute!
Look Mom, raccoons!
They're still around.
Even in a place like this.
Wait, raccoons!
Aw, they left.
I wanted to feed them.
Can raccoons really change
into something else?
So we lost our battle.
And development just goes on,
as if we'd never existed.
Humans quickly forget
how things used to be.
At least for them,
life is comfortable.
Trendy new condominiums
stand on Manpukuji Hill.
And as it turned out...
showing ourselves to the humans
had one good effect.
They take better care of nature.
They set aside
the last bits of forest...
and built a few parks.
“In harmony with the raccoons,”
as it said in the papers.
But for us it was too late.
We'd lost our home.
Some of us went over the mountain
to live in a town called Machida.
But there were
raccoons there already...
and development
was hurting them too.
Many were killed on the road.
Life got harder and harder.
So we decided
to bear the unbearable.
That's right. Those of us
who can transform...
are living as humans,
just like the foxes.
I have a desk job.
My wife, Kiyo, works at a bar.
Some of us got greedy
and made big money...
by working with the developers.
But most of us are tired and
want to go back to the forest.
It's amazing that humans
can actually live like this.
Some of us dropped out
and survive on scraps...
from the bars
and clubs of Shinjuku.
But what about Ponkichi
and the other raccoons?
No matter how tough
things get, raccoons are survivors.
They bear things without complaint
and live happily and freely.
They have children with a
carefree spirit, and then they die.
Ponkichi!
Shokichi!
- Welcome back!
- You haven't changed a bit!
On TV, they're saying
that foxes and raccoons...
have disappeared
because of urban sprawl.
Could you stop saying that?
Of course, some raccoons
and foxes can transform.
But what about the
rabbits and the other animals?
Some of us can't just disappear.
VOICES
Narration by Shincho Kokontei
Makoto Nonomura Yuriko lshida
Norihei Miki Nijiko Kiyokawa
Shigeru lzumiya Gannosuke Ashiya
Takehiro Murata Kobuhei Hayashiya
Akira Fukuzawa
Beicho Katsura Bunshi Katsura
Kosan Yanagiya
Executive Producers
Yasuyoshi Tokuma
Seiichiro Ujiie and Ritsuo lsobe
Planning by Hayao Miyazaki
Original story and Screenplay by
lsao Takahata
Music by Shang Shang Typhoon
English translation by
Rieko lzutsu-Vajirasarn
Nao Amisaki, Steve Alpert & Jim Hubbert
English subtitles by AURA
A Studio Ghibli Film
Produced by Toshio Suzuki
Directed by lsao Takahata
© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous